<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cakes on Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cakes on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Banana Bread</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/banana_bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/banana_bread/</guid>
      <description>The one thing one should do with old bananas. Easy and delicious.&#xA;Ingredients: 113 grams salted butter&#xA;150 grams sugar&#xA;3 ripe bananas&#xA;2 eggs&#xA;1 small teaspoon vanilla extract&#xA;1 tablespoon milk&#xA;walnuts (optional)&#xA;cooking chocolate1&#xA;240 grams flour&#xA;1 teaspoon baking powder&#xA;1 teaspoon baking soda&#xA;one big pinch of cayenne pepper (optional)&#xA;Preparation: lightly soften the butter in a microwave2&#xA;mix the sugar in&#xA;mix and mash the bananas in3</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>French Apple Cake</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/apple_cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/apple_cake/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is simple, surprisingly delicious, lets the apple shine through, and yet can be done with flavorless leftover apples.&#xA;Ingredients (one square cake pan): 3 large apples 2 teaspoons apple cider vinegar1 115 grams of salted butter 100 grams of white sugar 2 teaspoons of brown sugar (about 30 grams) 2 large eggs 1 large teaspoon vanilla extract2 120 grams flour 1 teaspoon baking powder Preparation: finely dice the apples3</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basic Mug Cake</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/mug_cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/mug_cake/</guid>
      <description>This is a recipe for a basic yellow mug cake. It might be a bit dry but it is perfect when you want cake in under five minutes. Feel free to add fruits, lemon juice/zests, chocolate chunks, or anything else really, to make it fancy!&#xA;Ingredients (one bowl of cake): 1 egg1 2 tablespoons of sugar 4 tablespoons of flour 1 teaspoon of baking powder2 3 tablespoons of milk 1 tablespoon of salted butter3 Preparation: mix the egg with the sugar add the flour and baking powder, mix add the milk, mix melt the butter in the microwave, add it and mix add any additional (flavoring) ingredient Cooking: microwave about 1min204 Credits: This is my take on this recipe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avocado Bread</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/avocado_bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/avocado_bread/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is simple, tastes good, has an interesting texture and, more importantly, looks extremely weird making it a fantastic party dessert.&#xA;Ingredients (one rectangular cake pan): 2 (very ripe) avocados 100 grams of sugar 3 eggs 240 grams of flour 6 grams (one and a half) teaspoon of baking powder Preparation: dice the inside of the avocados and put them in a large bowl cream1 the avocados and sugar together beat the eggs into the mix add the flour and baking powder fold together Cooking: cook for 30 to 35 minutes in a 350F (180C) oven Credits: The recipe comes from Dylan Hollis&amp;rsquo;s excellent Youtube channel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate decadence flourless cake</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/flourless-chocolate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/flourless-chocolate/</guid>
      <description>This cake feels light yet very buttery, delicious and fully decadent.&#xA;Ingredients: 3 eggs 90 grams of white sugar 30 grams of plain yogurt 5 grams (about 2 teaspoons) of cornstarch 1 teaspoon of vanilla extract 1 teaspoon of grounded instant coffee 120 grams of salted butter 170 grams of 64% cacao chocolate one large pear Preparation: Eggs separate the white and yolks1 of the eggs beat the egg whites in a large bowl Batter in a large bowl, mix the sugar, yogurt, vanilla, coffee powder, cornstarch melt the butter and chocolate in the microwave then add to the mixture dice the pear and add it to the mix fold in the egg whites2 pour in a pan lined with parchment paper Cooking: cook 50 to 60 minutes in a 275F (135C) oven (it will still be fudgy once done) let cool in the pan before storing in the fridge for one to two hours before serving Credits: This is my take on Brian Lagerstrom&amp;rsquo;s Super Easy Flourless Chocolate Cake.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kougelhopf</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/kougelhopf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/kougelhopf/</guid>
      <description>Kougelhopf is the quintessential Alsacian cake. This bundt cake is perfect for breakfast, sliced and covered with a thin layer of salted butter.&#xA;Ingredients (one large Kougelhopf): 75 grams of dried grapes 20 centiliters (200 grams) of milk 25 grams of fresh yeast1 500 grams of flour 75 grams of sugar 2 eggs 150 grams of salted butter a dozen almonds Preparation: Grapes Puts the dried grapes in room temperature water to let them soak during the rest of the process Yeast mix the yeast with a few tablespoons of flour and 10 centiliters of lukewarm2 milk let rest until the yeast bubbles up Dough mix the flour, sugar and eggs add the leftover milk dice the butter and add it mix until the butter is properly incorporated add the yeast and milk to the dough, mix for a few minutes let rest one hour in a warm place (near a heater for example) Pan generously butter a Kougelhopf pan3 put almonds in the bottom indentations of the pan add the grapes to the dough put the dough in the pan let rest for about one hour (or until the dough fully fills the pan) Cooking: cook 45 minutes at 180C (350F)4 once it has had some time to cool down, unmold it onto a flat plate once cold, you can sprinkle some powdered sugar on the result for better looks Credits: This is my take on Marmiton&amp;rsquo;s Kougelhopf sucré (Alsace) recipe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beeny&#39;s Brownies</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/brownies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/brownies/</guid>
      <description>This is a very straightforward chocolate brownies recipe. You can pimp it up with some coffee powder1, a few salt flakes on top, any kind of nuts, chocolate chunks, etc. The world is your chocolate-flavored oyster!&#xA;Ingredients (8 slices): 100 grams of flour 37 grams of cocoa powder 125 grams of sugar 2 eggs 1 teaspoon of vanilla extract (optional) 100 grams of salted butter Preparation: mix the flour and cocoa in a bowl add the sugar and mix beat the eggs and add add the vanilla extract melt the butter, add it and mix pour in a pan lined with parchment paper Cooking: cook 25 to 30 minutes in a 340F (170C) oven let cool in the pan cut into slices before serving (they might be best served the next day for peak flavor and texture) Credits: This is my take on Sarah Beeny&amp;rsquo;s chocolate brownies recipe (with which she beat Gordon Ramsay on British television).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clafoutis</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/clafoutis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/clafoutis/</guid>
      <description>Clafoutis was my favorite kind of cake when I was a kid. My mother used to make plum ones while fruits were in season and I famously ate a full cake that just got out of the oven while she was away from the kitchen. They are also a great way to turn fruits into a cake that looks very pretty while being extremely easy to make.&#xA;Ingredients: about 500grams (you want to cover your pan with a nice layer) of a mix of cherries and apricots (stones fruits such as cherries, plums apricots, and peaches feel like a better match but it works with pretty much anything including bananas and rhubarb, I like a mix of cherries and apricots to vary colors and flavors) 4 eggs 100 grams of flour 60 grams of salted butter (you could use 45 grams of olive oil and some salt, the taste and texture would slightly differ but that still makes for a good cake) 60 grams of sugar (you could go up to 100 grams according to taste) 25cl of milk some vanilla extract (optional) Preparation: The pan put a generous amount of butter on the sides of your cake pan (you want a wider rather than tall pan) cut your fruits (stones fruits can be cut into two or four, don&amp;rsquo;t forget to remove the stone, you can leave the skin on) and spread them in the cake pan The batter mix the eggs with the sugar until smooth add the (optional) vanilla extract add the flour while mixing add the milk while mixing melt the butter in a microwave (or oven but 30 seconds in a microwave is perfect) then add (if the butter is warm, mix it fast enough to not cook your egg) pour the batter into your cake pan (the batter will be more golden and liquid than usual cake batter, it is perfectly normal) Cooking: cook 30 to 45 minutes at 350F (180C), you can stop once the top is golden and the batter firm serve at room temperature (it is also great cold after a few hours in the fridge) you can (optionally) dust the top with powdered white sugar just before serving if you are serving cold (this is purely esthetic) Credits: This clafoutis batter is pretty classic and can be found all over the web.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crumble</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/crumble/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/crumble/</guid>
      <description>Crumbles are pretty much impossible to miss and a great way to turn fruits (most fruits are suitable; apples, pears, and peaches are classic) and butter into a good cake. This one is pimped with chocolate chips, cinnamon, vanilla extract, and lemon juice. They are all worth it but, you can cut all of them if you want to keep things simple (or do not have them on hand).&#xA;Ingredients (for 4 portions): 100g of flour (you can easily turn the grams into cups and half cups: it is the respective proportions that matter) 100g of salted butter (you can also use unsalted butter and had some salt, the result is identical, but do not omit the salt) 50g of sugar 2 large pears some good cooking chocolate (no need for a sweet one, 70% cacao does a good job, also I like to get a chocolate bar and cut it into smallish chips, you get better quality chocolate and bigger chips) some cinnamon some vanilla extract some lemon juice Preparation: bottom layer peel the pears, dice them, and put them on the bottom of your baking dish (I use a Pyrex square one), you want enough pears to garnish the bottom of the dish with about one centimeter of pears add some lemon juice on top, not much just a spoonful so that the pears are finely coated cut your chocolate into chips and sprinkle them on top of the layer of pears (no need for much, it is not a chocolate cake!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
