<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Viellir: an ode to old age on Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/ode_to_old_age/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Viellir: an ode to old age on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/ode_to_old_age/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Grace Hopper</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/ode_to_old_age/grace-hopper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/ode_to_old_age/grace-hopper/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The most important thing I&amp;rsquo;ve accomplished, other than building the compiler, is training young people. They come to me, you know, and say, &amp;lsquo;Do you think we can do this?&amp;rsquo; I say, &amp;lsquo;Try it.&amp;rsquo; And I back &amp;rsquo;em up. They need that. I keep track of them as they get older and I stir &amp;rsquo;em up at intervals so they don&amp;rsquo;t forget to take chances.&amp;rdquo; — Grace Hopper
 Grace Hopper was both an admiral of the US navy and a pioneer of computer science, introducing some concepts that are now fundamental to programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hokusai</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/ode_to_old_age/hokusai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/ode_to_old_age/hokusai/</guid>
      <description>Hokusai is considered one of the greatest masters in the history of art. Even if you do not know his name, you have seen a reproduction or a take on his Great Wave off Kanagawa.
In his seventies, shortly after making the Great Wave off Kanagawa, he wrote:
 &amp;ldquo;From the age of six, I had a passion for copying the form of things and since the age of fifty I have published many drawings, yet of all I drew by my seventieth year there is nothing worth taking into account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yitang Zhang</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/ode_to_old_age/yitang-zhang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/ode_to_old_age/yitang-zhang/</guid>
      <description>Yitang Zhang was born in 1955. He obtained his Ph.D. at 36 but, having no publications nor the support of his advisor, he had to quit academia and work as an accountant and a delivery worker, sometimes sleeping in his car, while trying to make ends meet.
At 58 years old, he published an extremely influential paper on bounded gaps in prime numbers](https://annals.math.princeton.edu/2014/179-3/p07) which suddenly gained him a large number of prizes, a prestigious university position and wide recognition in the world of mathematics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
