<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Astrology SOS on Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Astrology SOS on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 18:00:16 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Capricorn (December 22 - January 19)</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/10-capricorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/10-capricorn/</guid>
      <description>December Romance Whether your love life has been warm or cold lately, the coming month will see things heating up for you. You&amp;rsquo;ve made some personal progress lately, and it will pay off for you and a very lucky guy or girl! You know when you&amp;rsquo;ve got it good, so enjoy yourself with that special friend.&#xA;Money You&amp;rsquo;re feeling pretty flush this month &amp;ndash; enough so that you&amp;rsquo;re able to spread the good cheer around a little bit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sagittarius (November 22 - December 21)</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/9-sagittarius/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/9-sagittarius/</guid>
      <description>December Romance Has your romance cup just not been running over lately? If not, don&amp;rsquo;t dwell on the negative. Instead, take this opportunity to think about what you really want out of your love life, and consider what you can do to make it happen &amp;ndash; and bring this unlucky streak to an end!&#xA;Money Make sure the kitchen knives are sharpened, because you&amp;rsquo;re eating steak this month! Things are going your way, and you&amp;rsquo;ll likely find your wallet a little thicker and heavier than usual.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scorpio (October 23 - November 21)</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/8-scorpio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/8-scorpio/</guid>
      <description>December Love Some frustrations are in the picture for you in the romance department this month. You&amp;rsquo;ll probably find yourself feeling like you&amp;rsquo;re having trouble connecting with someone. While this is bound to be dissatisfying, remember that not everything is in your control, and this too is temporary.&#xA;Money Your financial dealings will really click into place this month, and with a little effort you should come out ahead of the game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Libra (September 23 - October 22)</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/7-libra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/7-libra/</guid>
      <description>December Love Lucky for you, it seems like there&amp;rsquo;s romance everywhere you turn this month. Someone is going out of their way to make you feel special, beautiful, and all-around fabulous &amp;ndash; and they&amp;rsquo;re doing a darn good job of it! Let them know you appreciate it; a little positive reinforcement can go a long way!&#xA;Money Good news: beneficial things await your pocketbook. If you&amp;rsquo;ve been working toward some sort of payoff, you can expect to start reaping the rewards this month.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virgo (August 23 - September 22)</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/6-virgo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/6-virgo/</guid>
      <description>December Love Unfortunately, you can expect some pot holes on the road to love this month. While keeping your eyes peeled will naturally help you dodge a few of them, you&amp;rsquo;re bound to hit some of them head on. While this is sure to be frustrating, remember it&amp;rsquo;s up to you to change your circumstances if things aren&amp;rsquo;t going the way you know you deserve.&#xA;Money You&amp;rsquo;ll find yourself on a bit of a roll financially this month.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leo (July 23 - August 22)</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/5-leo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/5-leo/</guid>
      <description>December Love If you detect a whiff of something sweet in the air, it&amp;rsquo;s because romance is in full bloom for you this month. Your charms have been working, and someone special is really taking notice of you. You feel like you deserve a little sweetness in your life, and you know what? You&amp;rsquo;re right! So enjoy it for all it&amp;rsquo;s worth.&#xA;Money Although you&amp;rsquo;re certainly not greedy, there&amp;rsquo;s a certain comfort that comes with financial security.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cancer (June 21 - July 22)</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/4-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/4-cancer/</guid>
      <description>December Love Even if your love life has led to some frustrations lately, these next few weeks will see your situation getting much, much warmer. The positive steps you make will naturally take you (and a very lucky guy or girl!) to whole new places. You know when you&amp;rsquo;ve got it good, so go out and enjoy yourself and that special friend.&#xA;Finance It looks like things are finally starting to go your way financially this month.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gemini (May 21 - June 20)</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/3-gemini/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/3-gemini/</guid>
      <description>December Love You&amp;rsquo;ve been musing about you and a particularly outstanding guy or girl, and lucky you, they&amp;rsquo;re musing right back. So don&amp;rsquo;t be shy! Whenever you take charge of the situation and grab the reins, you&amp;rsquo;re sure to see some of those dreams transform into magnificent real life events. By month&amp;rsquo;s end you&amp;rsquo;ll thank yourself for it (and you won&amp;rsquo;t be the only one).&#xA;Finance Even if things have been a little tight in the financial department lately, this month you can expect some good news.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taurus (April 20 - May 20)</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/2-taurus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/2-taurus/</guid>
      <description>December Love Unfortunately, this is a month looks to be a challenging one for your love life. You&amp;rsquo;ve been feeling more than a little far away (in many ways), but don&amp;rsquo;t worry, this won&amp;rsquo;t last much longer. Keep your chin up, and hold out for when your situation gets better by the end of next month.&#xA;Finance This is one of those months when all your financial dealings just seem to click into place, and you come out ahead with hardly any effort.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aries (March 21 - April 19)</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/1-aries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/1-aries/</guid>
      <description>December Love As the month gets going, get ready for some tremendous sparks to fly. You may even surprise yourself with the excitement you cause. This is genuinely one of those times when things just seem to click into place, and your good feelings rub off on everyone around you &amp;ndash; most of all, the lucky guy or girl who gets to reap the benefits!&#xA;Finance Some months, everything in your financial life just seems to go right.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pisces (February 19 - March 20)</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/12-pisces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/12-pisces/</guid>
      <description>December Romance Unfortunately, the stars indicate a lull in your love life this month. Despite your best efforts, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably find it frustratingly difficult to make the kind of romantic connection you&amp;rsquo;d like. Remember this too shall pass, and don&amp;rsquo;t let yourself settle for something that you&amp;rsquo;ll end up regretting later on.&#xA;Money Your finances are treating you pretty well this month. Projects that you&amp;rsquo;ve had in the works will finally start to show results, and you&amp;rsquo;ll find yourself solidly in the black (maybe even with a little left over to spare).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aquarius (January 20 - February 18)</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/11-aquarius/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/11-aquarius/</guid>
      <description>December Romance Your charms have been working overtime lately, and lucky for you, it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been for nothing; someone special is taking extra notice of you. How you take advantage of that is up to you, but be sure to make the most of it. You feel like you deserve a little loving care in your life, and you know what? You&amp;rsquo;re right! So enjoy it for all it&amp;rsquo;s worth.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
