<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pies on Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/pies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pies on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/pies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pâte sablée (short crust pie)</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/pies/pate_sablee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/pies/pate_sablee/</guid>
      <description>This is a great pie dough for most open-style pies. It is rich in butter and tastes great by itself, even raw!&#xA;Ingredients (for one pie): 75 grams of sugar 1 egg 250 grams of flour 100 grams of salted butter1 Preparation: mix the sugar and egg in a large bowl add the flour dice the butter and add it to the mix mix until homogeneous2 Cooking: use a rolling pin to flatten the dough before putting it in the pie pan3 add the sweet pie fillings4 of your choice you might want to prebake the pie crust for about 10 minutes at 180C (350F) Credits: This is my take on Marmiton&amp;rsquo;s Pâte sablée recipe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US-style pie crust</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/pies/us_pie_crust/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/pies/us_pie_crust/</guid>
      <description>This pie dough is easy to make and tastes pretty much perfect for a US-style pie (with crust below and above the pie). Plus, the leftover dough can be stored in the fridge for later use.&#xA;Ingredients (for one pie): 300 grams of flour 20 grams of sugar (optional) 227 grams of salted butter (get it out of the fridge as soon as you start to raise its temperature and make your job easier) 53 grams of water 8 grams of apple cider vinegar (needs testing to see how impactful it is) Preparation: put the flour in a large bowl add the sugar add the butter diced or sliced into thin slices (to simplify the mixing) with one hand mix the dough until you get a crumbly/flaky consistency add half of the water plus the vinegar and mix add the leftover water and mix into a ball cut the ball in two and refrigerate for 30 minutes while you prepare the fillings Cooking: You might want to prebake the bottom of our pie (for a European-style pie) or let your pie cook for a long time.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
