<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nestor&#39;s Guides on Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nestor&#39;s Guides on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nestor&#39;s guide to being creative</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/creativity/</guid>
      <description>For me making a habit of thinking about problems, writing my ideas and organizing them has been extremely valuable in all fields where I applied it (I am a PhD student in computeur science and act as a consultant for some magicians). I do not think that you can make a habit of producing good ideas but if you produce enough ideas you will end up producing at least a few good ones, it is only a matter of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nestor&#39;s guide to dating apps</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/dating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/dating/</guid>
      <description>General principles A lot of the following might seem obvious to you but, as what is obvious to some isn’t to others, I am putting a maximum of information here in the hope that you might find things that you do not already know.
There are a lot of men per woman on those apps so women there are used to doing very little work and having a lot of choices to select from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nestor&#39;s guide to doing hard things</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/doing-hard-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/doing-hard-things/</guid>
      <description>cut them into smaller things
do a small thing to lower the barrier of entry
be okay when it starts to be late and you have done nothing
make it look good fast</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nestor&#39;s guide to writing</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/writing/</guid>
      <description>disclaimer: I have written non-fiction profesionaly in various fields by never published any fiction so take the following with the appropriate amoint of salt
do a bad version first
identify lazyness things you could improve to make the result better but do not improve because you think it is good enough even if you know it would make it better
story circle
snowflake method
make it look good fast
(see also my guide on doing hard things)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some heuristics I use</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/heuristics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/heuristics/</guid>
      <description>play to your strengths, being balanced sounds nice but end up being really unproductive / un-pleasant be nice / kind / non-jugemental to people spend time on the things you like, as time and practice pile up you will end up skilled in those domain go for the things that are of interest to you, not for the trendy ones time spend automating tasks is usually time well spent taking a break to gather knowledge on something vaguely connected to the thing you are doing is never time lost when you have been procrastinating something for most of the day, declare that you will not do it today and that it is okay, it will free your mind to do other things instead of leaving you stuck try and do one, single and quantifiable, thing a day.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
