<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Savoury on Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Savoury on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The mighty KrautBurger</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/kraut-burger/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 21:16:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/kraut-burger/</guid>
      <description>The Krautburger is my favourite homemade burger of the moment. It is vegetarian (but not vegan due to the presence of mayonaise and, harder to replace, cheese) and light while hitting all the flavours I want due to the melted cheese and toasted bun combined with the surprise freshness of the thick tomato slice hidden inside the burger.
Ingredients (one burger):  a burger bun (bread rather than brioche if possible) some mayonaise one tomato enough sauerkraut to make a small patty out of it (pick one that is not too flavorfull and whose flavor you like, otherwise you might be disapointed by this burger&amp;hellip;) 2 slices of cheese (you want a cheese that does not melt instantly, so no american cheese, I like pepper jack because of the added flavor from the chili flakes, I would probably spinkle some chilly flakes on my sauerkraut if all I had was Gruyere)  Preparation:  toast the lower bun (this step is optional but will reduce soginess) spread a layer of mayonnaise on each half bun (the goal here is not to act on the taste but to stop water from going through and into the bun) put thick tomato slices on the bottom bun until it is fully covered (I like my slices about one centimeter thick) add one slice of cheese put some sauerkraut on top and shape it like a small pattie add the second slice of cheese add the final bun  Cooking:  toast in oven until the cheese is nicely melted and the top bun lightly toasted  Credits: This burger was born from some experimentation with leftovers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The secret of the Tarte au Maroille</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/tarte-au-maroille/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 21:16:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/tarte-au-maroille/</guid>
      <description>This cheese pie recipe is a family secret. It was past down from my grandmother to my mother to me (my sister did not care for cooking at the time). I am writting it so that it can be saved for future generation to enjoy (if you want to keep a secret, put it in writting).
Ingredients (two pies): Dought  1kg of white flour 5 egg yolks 1 cube of fresh yeast (if you cannot find it, it is hard to find in the US, a paquet of dry yeast will be fine but result in a more homogeneous result) a few spoonful of suger (white is fine, brown is better, cassonade/vergeoise is traditional) 125 grams of salted butter (butter is good, salted is better)  Toping:  one egg one egg&amp;rsquo;s worth of milk some gratted nutmeg (optional) one big, full, Maroille (this is a washed rind cheese with a strong smell, slightly sticky texture and a pinkish color, typical from north France and very hard to replace in this recipe as most similar cheeses stay too strong once baked while Maroille&amp;rsquo;s taste mellow enough for even non cheese lovers to love this pie)  Preparation: Dough  put the sugar and the yeast in a sall bowl of warmish water (my rule of thumb is that it should feel warm, so above body temperature, but no more than that, if you can burn your finger then it will kill your yeast&amp;hellip; I should maybe invest in a thermometer), mix once and let rest until it gets foamy put most of the flour in a large mixing bowl (set a little aside to shape the dough later) add the egg yolks and the yeast with its water mix until combined, do not overmix (the resulting dough will be very sticky) cover with a towel and let rise for one hour (warmish places such as a window in the sun are best)  Assembling the pie  spread the dough on top of your pizza pans (you want flat pans rather than pie pans), you can use the leftover flour to help shape the dough (do not use a rollin pin, this is a finger streching affair) add slices of Maroile on your pan (you want to cover it, the more the merryier) brush with a mix done with one egg and a little bit of milk (you can brush with your fingers) add a little bit of grounded nutmeg  Cooking:  cook at 180C (350F) for 30 to 45 minutes (the crust should be hardened and the cheese pretty melted).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
