<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Savoury on Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Savoury on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rice Zucchini à la Alfredo</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/rice_zucchini/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/rice_zucchini/</guid>
      <description>This dish is all about the pleasure of eating rice with Parmesan and butter, with some zucchini tossed in for good measure. It is quick to do and delicious, try it on a weekday.
Ingredients (one person):   Half a zucchini, 60 grams of rice, a lot of salted butter1, as much Parmesan as butter, optionally, some smoked chilly flakes for added flavor complexity.  Preparation:   Peel the Zucchini and dice it, bring water to a boil, add the rice and zucchini to the water and cook for ten minutes2, put the butter in the plate, add the (optional) chilly flakes, once the rice and zucchini are cooked, strain and pour on the butter add the Parmesan and mix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The regular pasta bellpepper</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/pasta_bellpepper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/pasta_bellpepper/</guid>
      <description>This dish is very fast to cook, brings you the carbs you need, some greens (technically reds) and has a distinct enough flavor to fight monotony in your eating habits.
Ingredients (for two portions):   160 grams of pasta (80 grams per person, you could go up to 100 grams), I like fusilli for this dish but most pasta types would be fine 1 bell pepper (all colors are fine, but I have a slight preference for red as it imparts some color to the pasta) some salted soy sauce (the salt will be useful) some olive oil (we will cook it so no need for high quality stuff) some herbes de Provence (you could use another dry herbs mix but do use dry herbs, they make the flavor of the dish) some cayenne pepper (optional)  Preparation:  Pasta   fill a pan with water and bring it to a boil (big bubbles, small bubbles do not count as boiling, you will be delighted to discover that I met people for which this is not obvious) add the pasta when the water starts boiling and keep cooking for about 10 minutes (until your pasta are cooked)  Sauce   once the pasta are in the water, put the diced bell pepper in a wok (or similar large pan) on low heat add a generous splash of olive oil add a generous splash of soy sauce (this will bring you the salt in the dish plus a lot of the flavor) add a very generous sprinkle of herbs (you can hardly overdo it here) optionally, add a sprinkle of cayenne pepper (you want enough for people to realize the dish has some hotness but no more, it is not a hot dish) cook on low heat  Assembly   once the pasta are cooked, add a splash of pasta water in the wok, this will help with the sauce consistency (you can be approximate with the quantity, too little and your sauce will miss a bit of thickness, too much and you will have to reduce longer: either way the result will be fine and you can do better next time) you can do it directly from the pasta pan, no need for an intermediate container (that would give you additional opportunities to burn yourself) strain the pasta and add them to the wok (it is okay if there is some pasta water left with the pasta, we have pasta water in the wok anyway) raise to medium it and keep mixing until you get the sauce consistency you want (the mixing time will depend on the amount of water you put, you should be done in two minutes) serve in a plate, feel free to add butter and shredded Parmesan to pimp the result slightly  Credits:  Using the pasta water comes from French guy cooking&amp;rsquo;s Alex and is a game changer for pasta sauces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The everlasting pasta ratatouille</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/pasta_ratatouille/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/pasta_ratatouille/</guid>
      <description>This dish is a worker: it is fast and easy to cook while being delicious and rich in vegetables and flavors.
I have been cooking variations of this dish for as long as I have been cooking for myself, starting when I had my first apartment. It has evolved a lot since its inception but it is still one of my favorite way to eat pasta.
Ingredients (for two portions):   160 grams of pasta (80 grams per person, you could go up to 100 grams), I like fusilli for this dish but most pasta types would be fine half a jar of organic1 ratatouille (this is where I lose my US readers, you simply cannot find this stuff in the US: you might replace it with a jar of tomato sauce that contains a generous amount of eggplants and assorted vegetables) some salted soy sauce (the salt will be useful) some olive oil (we will cook it so no need for high quality stuff) some salt (optional) some cayenne pepper (optional)  Preparation:  Pasta   fill a pan with water and bring it to a boil (big bubbles, small bubbles do not count as boiling, you will be delighted to discover that I met people for which this is not obvious) you can optionally add a generous amount of salt to your pasta water, the pasta will taste better but do not need it here add the pasta when the water starts boiling and keep cooking for about 10 minutes (until your pasta are cooked)  Sauce   once the pasta are in the water, put the ratatouille in a wok (or similar large pan) on low heat add a generous splash of olive oil add a generous splash of soy sauce (this will bring you the salt in the dish plus a lot of the flavor) optionally, add a sprinkle of cayenne pepper (you want enough for people to realize the dish has some hotness but no more, it is not a hot dish) cook on low heat  Assembly   once the pasta are cooked, add a splash of pasta water in the wok, this will help with the sauce consistency (you can be approximate with the quantity, too little and your sauce will miss a bit of thickness, too much and you will have to reduce longer: either way the result will be fine and you can do better next time) you can do it directly from the pasta pan, no need for an intermediate container (that would give you additional opportunities to burn yourself) strain the pasta and add them to the wok (it is okay if there is some pasta water left with the pasta, we have pasta water in the wok anyway) raise to medium it and keep mixing until you get the sauce consistency you want (the mixing time will depend on the amount of water you put, you should be done in two minutes) serve in a plate, feel free to add butter and shredded Parmesan to pimp the result slightly  Credits:  I used soy sauce and a jar of ratatouille because my father put them in my very first grocery bag as an independent student.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The secret of the Tarte au Maroille</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/tarte_maroille/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/tarte_maroille/</guid>
      <description>This cheese pie recipe is a family secret. It was past down from my grandmother to my mother to me (my sister did not care for cooking at the time). I am writing it so that it can be saved for future generation to enjoy (if you want to keep a secret, put it in writing).
Ingredients (two pies):  Dought   1 kg of white flour 5 egg yolks 1 cube of fresh yeast (if you cannot find it, it is hard to find in the US, a sachet of dry yeast will be fine but result in a more homogeneous result) a few spoonfuls of sugar (white is fine, brown is better, cassonade/vergeoise is traditional) 125 grams of salted butter (butter is good, salted is better)  Toping   one egg, one egg&amp;rsquo;s worth of milk, some grated nutmeg (optional) one big, full, Maroille (this is a washed rind cheese with a strong smell, slightly sticky texture and a pinkish color, typical from north France and very hard to replace in this recipe as most similar cheeses stay too strong once baked while Maroille&amp;rsquo;s taste mellow enough for even non cheese lovers to love this pie)  Preparation:  Dough   Put the sugar and the yeast in a small bowl of warmish water (my rule of thumb is that it should feel warm, so above body temperature, but no more than that, if you can burn your finger then it will kill your yeast&amp;hellip; I should maybe invest in a thermometer), mix once and let rest until it gets foamy put most of the flour in a large mixing bowl (set a little aside to shape the dough later) add the egg yolks and the yeast with its water mix until combined, do not over mix (the resulting dough will be very sticky) cover with a towel and let rise for one hour (warmish places such as a window in the sun are best)  Assembling the pie   spread the dough on top of your pizza pans (you want flat pans rather than pie pans), you can use the leftover flour to help shape the dough (do not use a rolling pin, this is a finger stretching affair) add slices of Maroile on your pan (you want to cover it, the more the merrier) brush with a mix done with one egg and a little bit of milk (you can brush with your fingers) add a little bit of grounded nutmeg  Cooking:   Cook at 180C (350F) for 30 to 45 minutes (the crust should be hardened and the cheese pretty melted).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The mighty KrautBurger</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/krautburger/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/krautburger/</guid>
      <description>The Krautburger is my favorite homemade burger of the moment. It is vegetarian (but not vegan due to the presence of mayonnaise and, harder to replace, cheese) and light while hitting all the flavors I want due to the melted cheese and toasted bun combined with the surprise freshness of the thick tomato slice hidden inside the burger.
Ingredients (one burger):   a burger bun (bread rather than brioche if possible) some mayonnaise one tomato enough sauerkraut to make a small patty out of it (pick one that is not too flavorful and whose flavor you like, otherwise you might be disappointed by this burger&amp;hellip;) 2 slices of cheese (you want a cheese that does not melt instantly, so no American cheese, I like pepper jack because of the added flavor from the chili flakes, I would probably sprinkle some chilly flakes on my sauerkraut if all I had was Gruyère)  Preparation:   toast the lower bun (this step is optional but will reduce sogginess) spread a layer of mayonnaise on each half bun (the goal here is not to act on the taste but to stop water from going through and into the bun) put thick tomato slices on the bottom bun until it is fully covered (I like my slices about one centimeter thick) add one slice of cheese put some sauerkraut on top and shape it like a small pattie add the second slice of cheese add the final bun  Cooking:   toast in oven until the cheese is nicely melted and the top bun lightly toasted  Credits:  This burger was born from some experimentation with leftovers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
