<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Objects I like on Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/objects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Objects I like on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/objects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Victorinox Paring Knife Set</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/objects/knife_set/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/objects/knife_set/</guid>
      <description>I am usually against knife sets; they tend to contain useless knives and suboptimal versions of useful knives, but I absolutely love this set of paring knives1.
For $22, it includes a small (paring) knife (useful whenever you want a small sharp knife, i.e., perfect for onion), a serrated slightly longer (tomato) knife (great for smooth vegetables, like tomatoes, as well as a surprising array of small bread, sandwich, and pastries), and a small serrated knife (the least useful of the set, usually used when one of the other two is in washing).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japanese Can Opener</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/objects/can_opener/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/objects/can_opener/</guid>
      <description>The cheapest kind of can opener you can buy in France is a single piece of metal with a sharp edge. It is also the most practical kind of can opener. In the US, it is called a Japanese can opener, and it is apparently very fancy.
Those things are a marvel of design. They have no moving parts (it is literally a single piece of metal), making them dead easy to use and clean, very durable (they will outlive you by a long shot), space-efficient (nice if, for whatever reason, you want to travel with your can opener), and dirt cheap (about $9 on Amazon for a fancier model).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Shopping trolley bag</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/objects/cabas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/objects/cabas/</guid>
      <description>If you do your groceries on foot, a shopping trolley bag (with wheels) is a game-changer.
The main hurdle when going grocery shopping on foot is dealing with the weight of the produces on the way back. However, I observed a large number of old people doing their groceries on foot as if it were nothing (while the way back was clearly strenuous to my weak arms).
Their superpower? The power of the wheel!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philips Sonicare toothbrush</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/objects/toothbrush/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/objects/toothbrush/</guid>
      <description>The Philips Sonicare toothbrush is the best electronic toothbrush I ever used. By a significant margin. It is not only good at cleaning your teeth but also one of those rare objects that are well designed.
Regarding the quality of the cleaning (arguably the most important criteria), I could feel a sensible reduction in plaque when I went from a traditional toothbrush to an electric toothbrush, but this was one more step.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
