<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sandwiches on Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/sandwich/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sandwiches on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/sandwich/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Avocado toast</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/sandwich/avocado_toast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/sandwich/avocado_toast/</guid>
      <description>Avocado toast is the most shamefully Californian dish. This version has a nice spicy punch to it.
Ingredients (one toast):   one slice of bread (I recommend multigrain bread, it has more depth of flavor once toasted) some mayonnaise one avocado coarse salt pepper Sriracha sauce (as this is a big part of the final flavor, do not accept substitutes to the original sauce)  Preparation:   toast the bread put a thin layer of mayonnaise on the bread put a layer of avocado on the bread (you can spread it or slice it for a better-looking result) add a zigzag of Sriracha sauce add a generous amount of salt and pepper  Credits:  This recipe is taken straight from You suck at cooking&amp;rsquo;s great Youtube Channel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacon Tomato Melt</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/sandwich/bacon_tomato_melt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/sandwich/bacon_tomato_melt/</guid>
      <description>This is the pinnacle of self-indulging food. It is fast to prepare and very calorie-rich but the bacon, melted cheese, and toasted bread mesh perfectly and hit all the right spots.
Ingredients (one toast):   one or two slices of bacon1 one slice of bread (I recommend multigrain bread, it has more depth of flavor once toasted) some mayonnaise half a tomato coarse salt (optional) shredded cheese  Preparation:   cook the bacon in an oven or pan until crisp (note that it will give out a lot of fat, you could collect it for other recipes) toast the bread spread a thin layer of mayonnaise on the bread (it is there for some flavor notes but also to avoid having the tomato juice make the bread soggy) covers the bread with a one-slice thick layer of tomato sprinkle some salt add a layer of crispy bacon add a pile of shredded cheese at the very least as thick as the rest of the sandwich on top toast until the cheese is melted to your preference serve warm  Credits:  This recipe is taken straight from You suck at cooking&amp;rsquo;s great Youtube Channel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The mighty KrautBurger</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/sandwich/krautburger/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/sandwich/krautburger/</guid>
      <description>The Krautburger is my favorite homemade burger of the moment. It is vegetarian (but not vegan due to the presence of mayonnaise and, harder to replace, cheese) and light while hitting all the flavors I want due to the melted cheese and toasted bun combined with the surprising freshness of the thick tomato slice hidden inside the burger.
Ingredients (one burger):   a burger bun (bread rather than brioche if possible) some mayonnaise one tomato enough sauerkraut to make a small patty out of it (pick one that is not too flavorful and whose flavor you like, otherwise you might be disappointed by this burger&amp;hellip;) 2 slices of cheese (you want a cheese that does not melt instantly, so no American cheese, I like pepper jack because of the added flavor from the chili flakes, I would probably sprinkle some chilly flakes on my sauerkraut if all I had was Gruyère)  Preparation:   toast the lower bun (this step is optional but will reduce sogginess) spread a layer of mayonnaise on each half-bun (the goal here is not to act on the taste but to stop water from going through and into the bun) put thick tomato slices on the bottom bun until it is fully covered (I like my slices about one centimeter thick) add one slice of cheese put some sauerkraut on top and shape it like a small pattie add the second slice of cheese add the final bun  Cooking:   toast in the oven until the cheese is nicely melted and the top bun lightly toasted.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
