<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Techniques on Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/technique/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Techniques on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/technique/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Melting butter</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/technique/melting_butter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/technique/melting_butter/</guid>
      <description>This should be obvious but&amp;hellip;&#xA;Ingredients: the butter you want to melt Technique: put the butter in a small bowl microwave until you hear some bubbling sound (30 seconds is usually enough) Credits: The technique seems obvious, I am not aware of any particular credits.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Melting chocolate</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/technique/melting_chocolate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/technique/melting_chocolate/</guid>
      <description>The classical technique to melt chocolate is to use a double broiler (also called bain Marie). However, I am deeply convinced that using a microwave is significantly easier and faster.&#xA;Ingredients: chocolate to melt a tablespoon of water (you need some water to prevent dry burning but too much will deteriorate the result) if the recipe calls for melted butter, adding cream or milk, you can replace the water with one of those in the quantities required by the recipe Technique: put the chocolate in a small bowl add the liquid or milk produce microwave until the chocolate is softened (around one minute depending on the strength of your microwave) mix the result to finish melting the chocolate Credits: I am not aware of any particular credit for this technique, I saw it used by a variety of sources.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
