<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Other sweet dishes on Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Other sweet dishes on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Shrikhand</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/shrikhand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/shrikhand/</guid>
      <description>Shrikhand is an Indian, Gujarati and Marathi, dessert made primarily with yogurt and cardamom. It is quick to make, looks quite fancy, and has a nice richness of flavor: basically a fancy Indian yogurt.
Ingredients (1 small bowl):    1 small bowl of dry1 Greek2 yogurt Nuts3 to taste Dried grapes to taste (optional) A hazelnut-sized4 amount of butter 1/2 teaspoon of cardamom powder 1/4 teaspoon of saffron threads Powdered sugar to taste  Preparation:   Saffron    Grind or chop the saffron finely (reserve some threads for garnish) Mix it and let it bloom in a teaspoon5 of hot water  Nuts    Chop the nuts finely (reserve some for garnishing) Bloom the nuts with the dried grapes and butter in a small pan  Yogurt    Pass the yogurt through a fine sieve6 Add the nuts, spices, and sugar Mix until smoothly combined Garnish with the reserved chopped nuts and saffron threads  Credits:   I learned about the dish, as well as the idea of blooming nuts in butter, in Bon Appétit&amp;rsquo;s Pro Chefs Give 26 Cooking Tips for Every Letter A-Z video.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giant Almond Croissant</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/giant_croissant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/giant_croissant/</guid>
      <description>Like most puff pastry recipes, this recipe feels like cheating. It is super easy to do yet looks fantastic. Plus, if for some weird reason you do not want a giant almond croissant, you can easily adapt it to oddly shaped leftover puff pastry bits and stale croissants.
Ingredients (12 servings):    one sheet of puff pastry1, 56 grams of salted butter, 100 grams of white sugar, 108 grams of almond flour2, 1 large egg, 1 tablespoon vanilla extract, 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Red Bean Paste Cookie</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/red_bean_paste_cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/red_bean_paste_cookies/</guid>
      <description>Those cookies are very worth doing. They focus the flavor on the red bean paste while looking fancier than they are difficult to cook (which is always a good thing).
Ingredients (2 person):    1 egg 50 grams of salted butter 100 grams of flour 25 grams of icing sugar1 1 teaspoon vanilla extract 100 grams of red bean paste2 optional: 1 additional egg for brushing3 optional: sesame seeds  Preparation:   Cookie dough    whisk the egg in a bowl add the softened4 butter and mix until homogeneous add the flour, icing sugar and vanilla extract mix until smooth5 cover and refrigerate for one hour  Assembly    get the dough on a floured6 surface using a rolling pin, shape the dough into a long rectangle shape the red bean paste into a thick bar and place it in the middle of the rectangle carefully fold the two sides of the rectangle over the bar and flip it to put the seam down cut the resulting bar of dough into squarish cookies  Decoration    whisk the additional egg and brush the cookies with it7 sprinkle some sesame seeds on the cookies  Baking    bake 20 to 25 minutes at 360F (180C) let cool down a little before eating  Credits:   This recipe is mostly my notes on China Sichian Food&amp;rsquo;s Red Bean Paste Cookie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dalgona Coffee</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/dalgona_coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/dalgona_coffee/</guid>
      <description>This drink is quick and easy to make, tastes like an éclair au café, and looks very pretty. It is perfect to share with a guest who likes coffee.
Ingredients (1 glass):    two teaspoons of instant coffee1 two teaspoons of sugar two teaspoons of boiling water one glass of very cold whole2 milk3  Preparation:    mix the instant coffee, sugar, and boiling water in a bowl whip until the color lightens and the texture becomes fluffier4 pour the coffee foam5 on top of a glass of very cold milk to serve add a straw, let guests mix, and start drinking  Credits:   This recipe was inspired by seeing James Hoffman discuss the drink on his youtube channel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegan fruity breakfast</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/breakfast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/breakfast/</guid>
      <description>This breakfast manages to both be delicious and give you the feeling that you are eating healthy. And it feels good. I get the needed ingredients about once a month to eat it for a few days (I feel that eating it every day would reduce my enjoyment).
Ingredients (1 bowl):    two tablespoons of granola1 two tablespoons of unsweetened coconut milk yogurt2 two tablespoons of blueberries a few strawberries3  Preparation:    put the granola in a bowl add the yogurt wash and add the blueberries wash, dice and add the stawberries  Credits:   You can find similar recipes on Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two-ingredient chocolate mousse</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/chocolate_mousse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/chocolate_mousse/</guid>
      <description>This is the perfect recipe to do when you have leftover egg whites. It is delicious and uses barely any ingredients (I always keep the proper chocolate in my pantry to do this recipe when I have egg whites). Its only downside is that, once you have prepared everything, you need to wait.
Ingredients (1 portion):    1 egg whites1 35 grams of chocolate2  Preparation:    beat your egg whites into a nice firm foam melt the chocolate (it is okay to leave some chunks in the melted chocolate, they will add heterogeneity to the result) optionally, if you have egg yolks, add them to the melted chocolate and mix until homogeneous (be careful not to cook them in the hot chocolate) fold (or beat) the melted chocolate into the egg whites pour into one glass, mug, or bowl per portion store in the fridge for at least 5 hours (you can wait a full night if you want to be sure) eat cold (you can shave some chocolate on top if you want to make it look fancy)  Credits:   The proportions are inspired by this Mousse au chocolat facile recipe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crêpes</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/crepes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/crepes/</guid>
      <description>Crêpes are the perfect social dish. You can make them together, then everyone puts the toppings1 of their choice on top, sweet or savory2.
Ingredients (4 people):    250 grams flour 25 grams sugar 4 eggs 500 ml milk 50 grams salted butter (or 40 grams olive oil and a pinch of salt, the taste is slightly different but it works)  Preparation:    Put the flour in a mixing bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
