<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Beowulf on Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Beowulf on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Translator&#39;s Notes</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/notes/</guid>
      <description>The bulk of the translation work was done using Artificial Intelligence (and in particular Claude Opus1).
The process and prompt I used are detailed below. They were born out of a lot of trial and error and are likely still very imperfect (as demonstrated by the fact that I was not able to capture the style I wanted).
Chapters   First, I cut the story into chapters (as a way to both break down the work and introduce breathing points into the reading), starting from Carrigan&amp;rsquo;s model of Beowulf&amp;rsquo;s design then trying to produce units of text of similar size2 and each ending on a dramatic or suspenseful note:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IIX. Twilight</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/8-twilight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/8-twilight/</guid>
      <description>Then the prince went and sat on a seat by the wall, thoughtfully gazing on the work of giants, how the stone-arches held up the eternal earth-hall from within. His thane, glorious in his victory, washed the blood-stained hand of his lord abundantly with water, the great-hearted man, weary from his battle-wounds, and loosened his helmet.
Beowulf spoke in spite of his injuries, his mortal wound; he knew full well that he had spent his allotted days, his worldly joy; then all was gone for him, the count of his days, death very near: &amp;ldquo;Now I would give my war-gear to my son, if any heir had been granted to me, born of my body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VII. The Dragon</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/7-dragon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/7-dragon/</guid>
      <description>The dragon guarded a hoard in the high heath, a stone-barrow; a path ran beneath, unknown to men. Inside, a certain man had entered who seized a cup, a gold-plated treasure; he did not give it back, though he had tricked the sleeping guardian with thievish craft. The king found out that his rage was provoked.
It was not by his own desire that the man sought out the dragon&amp;rsquo;s hoard, bringing about woe and destruction; rather, out of dire necessity, a servant, one of some slaves, sought refuge there with a guilty conscience, fleeing heavy blows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VI. Trophies</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/6-trophies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/6-trophies/</guid>
      <description>Beowulf spoke, the son of Ecgtheow: &amp;ldquo;Lo, son of Healfdene, prince of the Scyldings, we have joyfully brought you this sea-booty, which you gaze on here, as a token of glory. I hardly survived it, hazarded an undersea battle, engaged in a risky task. The fight would soon have been finished if fate had not protected me. I could not accomplish anything with Hrunting in the conflict, though that weapon is strong; but the All-Father granted that I saw a beautiful, powerful sword hanging on the wall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>V. Grendel&#39;s Mother</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/5-mother/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/5-mother/</guid>
      <description>She came then to Heorot, where the Ring-Danes slept throughout the hall. Misfortune befell the nobles when Grendel&amp;rsquo;s mother burst in upon them. The terror was less only by so much as the strength of women, the war-terror of a wife, is less than an armed man&amp;rsquo;s, when the bound sword, hammer-forged and stained with blood, the keen blade with its edge, cuts the boar on the helmet of the opposed warrior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IV. The Morning After</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/4-celebrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/4-celebrations/</guid>
      <description>In the morning, as I have heard, many a warrior gathered around the gift-hall. Tribal chiefs came from far and wide over distant paths to behold the wonder, the tracks of the enemy. His parting from life did not seem grievous to any of the men who saw the splendor of the inglorious one&amp;rsquo;s footprints, how he, weary in spirit and overcome in the fight, doomed and driven out, bore his death-marks to the mere of the water-monsters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>III. Beowulf</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/3-beowulf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/3-beowulf/</guid>
      <description>In the beer-hall, a bench was cleared for the Geats to sit together, the stout-hearted ones proud in their strength. A thane did his duty, bearing in his hands the decorated ale-cup, pouring out the bright sweet drink. At times, a clear-voiced scop sang in Heorot, and there was joy among the heroes, a great host of Danes and Weders.
Unferth, son of Ecglaf, who sat at the feet of the Scyldings&amp;rsquo; lord, spoke, unbinding a battle-rune.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>II. Grendel</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/2-grendel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/2-grendel/</guid>
      <description>At dawn, as day broke, Grendel&amp;rsquo;s deeds were laid bare. After their feasting, wailing filled the morning air, a great cry of sorrow. The renowned ruler, long good and noble, sat joyless, the strong one suffering for his thanes as they beheld the loathsome foe&amp;rsquo;s track, the accursed spirit&amp;rsquo;s trail. That struggle was too strong, too long-lasting and loathsome.
After a single night, Grendel wrought more slaughter, not shrinking from his evil, firmly set in his ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I. Beginnings</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/1-beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/1-beginnings/</guid>
      <description>Listen well! Let me tell you of the glory of the Spear-Danes&amp;rsquo; kings in days long past, and the valorous deeds of those mighty princes.
Scyld Scefing, abandoned as a child, rose to seize the mead-benches from many tribes and troops of enemies. From this, he found solace. He grew under the heavens, thriving with honors, until each nation across the whale-road had to obey him and pay tribute. That was a good king!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prelude</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/0-prelude/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/0-prelude/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;If you wish to translate, not rewrite Beowulf, your language must be literary and traditional: not because it is now a long while since the poem was made, or because it speaks of things that have since become ancient; but because the diction of Beowulf was poetical, archaic, artificial (if you will), in the day that the poem was made.&amp;rdquo; — J. R. R. Tolkien, Beowulf: The Monsters and the Critics</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
