<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Special meals on Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Special meals on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The secret of the Tarte au Maroille</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/tarte_maroille/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/tarte_maroille/</guid>
      <description>This cheese pie recipe is a family secret. It was passed down from my grandmother to my mother to me (my sister did not care for cooking at the time). I am writing it so that it can be saved for future generations to enjoy (if you want to keep a secret, put it in writing).
Ingredients (two pies):  Dought   1 kg of white flour 5 egg yolks 1 cube of fresh yeast (if you cannot find it, it is hard to find in the US, a sachet of dry yeast will be fine but result in a more homogeneous result) a few spoonfuls of sugar (white is fine, brown is better, cassonade/vergeoise is traditional) 125 grams of salted butter (butter is good, salted is better)  Toping   one egg, one egg&amp;rsquo;s worth of milk, some grated nutmeg (optional) one big, full, Maroille (this is a washed rind cheese with a strong smell, slightly sticky texture, and a pinkish color, typical from North France and very hard to replace in this recipe as most similar cheeses stay too strong once baked while Maroille&amp;rsquo;s taste mellow enough for even non-cheese-lovers to love this pie)  Preparation:  Dough   Put the sugar and the yeast in a small bowl of warmish water (my rule of thumb is that it should feel warm, so above body temperature, but no more than that, if you can burn your finger then it will kill your yeast&amp;hellip; I should maybe invest in a thermometer), mix once and let rest until it gets foamy put most of the flour in a large mixing bowl (set a little aside to shape the dough later) add the egg yolks and the yeast with its water mix until combined, do not over-mix (the resulting dough will be very sticky) cover with a towel and let rise for one hour (warmish places such as a window in the sun are best)  Assembling the pie   spread the dough on top of your pizza pans (you want flat pans rather than pie pans), you can use the leftover flour to help shape the dough (do not use a rolling pin, this is a finger stretching affair) add slices of Maroile on your dough (you want to cover it, the more the merrier) brush with a mix done with one egg and a little bit of milk (you can brush with your fingers) add a little bit of grounded nutmeg  Cooking:   Cook at 180C (350F) for 30 to 45 minutes (the crust should be hardened and the cheese pretty melted).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
