<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Special Meals on Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Special Meals on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Okonomiyaki</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/okonomiaki/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/okonomiaki/</guid>
      <description>Okonomiyaki, which roughly translates to &amp;ldquo;anything grilled,&amp;rdquo; can be described as a Japanese cabbage and seafood-flavored pancake. But, that is very much off the mark as to what the dish is: think of a grilled disk of cabbage and batter, coated in a sweet sauce, and Japanese mayo. It is heaven and surprisingly easy to make.&#xA;Ingredients (1 Okonomiyaki): Batter:&#xA;76 grams flour 1/8 teaspoon1 of baking powder 1/4 teaspoon of salt 2 eggs 60 ml of warm water2 bonito flakes 1/2 teaspoon soy sauce 1/4 of a head of cabbage 1/4 of a red3 onion Sauce4:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Naans</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/naan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/naan/</guid>
      <description>Naans are very easy to make, go well with any curry or thick sauce, and make for a nice change of carbs.&#xA;Ingredients (3 big naans): 200 grams flour&#xA;1 teaspoon sugar&#xA;a big pinch of salt&#xA;1/2 teaspoon baking powder&#xA;3 tablespoons of olive oil&#xA;125 grams yogurt&#xA;7 centiliters1 of water&#xA;1 tablespoon butter (or ghee), 1 clove garlic and (optionally) cilantro for garlic naans&#xA;laughing cow for cheese naans</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nachos</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/nachos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/nachos/</guid>
      <description>Nachos are a great group meal to eat with friends. This particular version comes with a satisfying bean base to make it a proper meal that can be scooped with tortilla chips as you go.&#xA;Ingredients (two servings): half of an onion (I like a red onion for decorative purposes)&#xA;olive oil&#xA;soy sauce&#xA;one can of beans (I like chili beans)&#xA;ketchup1&#xA;cayenne pepper (you could use another source of spiciness such as chilly flakes)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pizza dough</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/pizza/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/pizza/</guid>
      <description>Pizza is a classic for a reason. A lot of recipes call for preparing the dough on a previous day or a special oven, this recipe steers away from those best practices to give you something delicious within two hours.&#xA;Ingredients (one pizza): 250 grams of flour 6 grams of salt 4 grams of dry yeast (about half a packet) 175 grams of warm water1 15 grams of olive oil (enough to coat the pan) Preparation: Dough mix the flour, salt and yeast in a big bowl</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tarte au Maroille</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/tarte_maroille/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/tarte_maroille/</guid>
      <description>This cheese pie recipe is a family secret. It was passed down from my grandmother to my mother to me (my sister did not care for cooking at the time). I am writing it so that it can be saved for future generations to enjoy (if you want to keep a secret, put it in writing).&#xA;Ingredients (two pies): Dought 1 kg of white flour 5 egg yolks 1 cube of fresh yeast1 a few spoonfuls of sugar (white is fine, brown is better, cassonade/vergeoise is traditional) 125 grams of salted butter (butter is good, salted is better) Toping one egg, one egg&amp;rsquo;s worth of milk, some grated nutmeg (optional) one big, full, Maroille2 Preparation: Dough Put the sugar and the yeast in a small bowl of warmish water3, mix once and let rest until it gets foamy put most of the flour in a large mixing bowl (set a little aside to shape the dough later) add the egg yolks and the yeast with its water mix until combined, do not over-mix (the resulting dough will be very sticky) cover with a towel and let rise for one hour (warmish places such as a window in the sun are best) Assembling the pie spread the dough on top of your pizza pans (you want flat pizza type of pans rather than pie pans), you can use the leftover flour to help shape the dough (do not use a rolling pin, this is a finger-stretching affair) add slices of Maroile on your dough (you want to cover it, the more the merrier) brush with a mix done with one egg and a little bit of milk (you can brush with your fingers) add a little bit of grounded nutmeg Cooking: Cook at 180C (350F) for 30 to 45 minutes (the crust should be hardened and the cheese pretty melted).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
