<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Concepts on Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/concepts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Concepts on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/concepts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Consumers and producers</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/concepts/consumers_producers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/concepts/consumers_producers/</guid>
      <description>Most activities can be categorized as either consumer or producer.
A consumer activity is an activity during which you consume existing content such as watching a video, reading a book, or browsing the Internet. Depending on the content you consumed, it can be nourishing or leave you with a feeling of emptiness.
A producer activity is an activity during which you produce new content for others to consume such as drawing, writing, cooking, or programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The easy path</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/concepts/easy_path/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/concepts/easy_path/</guid>
      <description>The opposite of wanting something to be perfect is following the easy path: knowing that some things could be done to make your project objectively better but keeping the current version because it is &amp;ldquo;good enough&amp;rdquo;.
This, as long as the modification would be within the scope and allotted time1, is a form of laziness. However, it is insidious. All parts of a project have to be considered &amp;ldquo;good enough&amp;rdquo; before you let go of them to tackle the next step, it is very easy to not realize that your motivation shifted from an objective look at the quality of your work toward avoiding additional work to the detriment of the result.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
