<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Movie reviews on Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Movie reviews on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Name of the Rose</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/name-of-the-rose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/name-of-the-rose/</guid>
      <description>Note: There will be spoilers.
I just re(re-re)-watched the Name of the Rose and I still absolutely love it.
The main character, William of Baskerville, is basically a Sherlock Holmes clone (he even says &amp;ldquo;Elementary!&amp;rdquo; to his apprentice a couple of times) except that he is a Franciscan monk living during the middle-ages and investigating a murder in an abbey that is busy with a debate on whether the church should be poor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Batman</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/the-batman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/the-batman/</guid>
      <description>I saw the Batman and&amp;hellip; meh.
I love the acting of the Riddler in his unmasked sections (he looks like an accountant and that is great).
Some solid action scenes, but none of the set pieces really strikes me.
The gadgets are really nice (lenses, parachute, etc.) but the scenario leaves me cold. The Riddler and the plot are clearly inspired by Seven while Batman&amp;rsquo;s moral (and notebook) are clearly taken from Watchmen&amp;rsquo;s Rorschach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nightmare alley</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/nightmare-alley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/nightmare-alley/</guid>
      <description>I watched Guillermo Del Toro&amp;rsquo;s Nightmare Alley yesterday and&amp;hellip; It was ok.
I might have been let down a little because I love both Guillermo Del Toro and the source material (by the way, you can find both the original black&amp;amp;white movie and the book for free, legally, on the internet archive) so I had a lot of expectations.
The actors are solid, the movie has a very nice forties ambiance (I love the psychologist&amp;rsquo;s office design) and some scenes are wonderful (the one scene dealing with the consequence of his actions&amp;hellip; and the final scene which was already one of the strong points from the original story) but I felt that the scenario was lacking.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
