<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Movie reviews on Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Movie reviews on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Guillermo Del Toro&#39;s Pinocchio</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/pinocchio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/pinocchio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1488589/&#34;&gt;Guillermo Del Toro&amp;rsquo;s Pinocchio&lt;/a&gt; is surprisingly both a very faithful rendition of the original story and a very Del Toro movie.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It has a lot of Del Toro&amp;rsquo;s elements (older spirits meddling with human life, a found family, a refusal to glorify war and fascism as a background) but, if you did not know that it was a Del Toro movie, you would accept all of those elements as coming from the original material.&#xA;It feels like he has found an existing story that meshes very well with his personality and interests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Name of the Rose</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/name-of-the-rose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/name-of-the-rose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note: There will be spoilers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I just re(re-re)-watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0091605/&#34;&gt;the Name of the Rose&lt;/a&gt; and I still absolutely love it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main character, William &lt;em&gt;of Baskerville&lt;/em&gt;, is basically a Sherlock Holmes clone (he even says &amp;ldquo;Elementary!&amp;rdquo; to his apprentice a couple of times) except that he is a Franciscan monk living during the middle-ages and investigating a murder in an abbey that is busy with a debate on whether the church should be poor.&#xA;As far as I am concerned, this is the perfect set-up for a movie.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Batman</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/the-batman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/the-batman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I saw &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Batman_%28film%29&#34;&gt;the Batman&lt;/a&gt; and&amp;hellip; meh.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I love the acting of the Riddler in his unmasked sections (he looks like an accountant and that is great).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some solid action scenes, but none of the set pieces really strikes me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The gadgets are really nice (lenses, parachute, etc.) but the scenario leaves me cold.&#xA;The Riddler and the plot are clearly inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seven_%281995_film%29&#34;&gt;Seven&lt;/a&gt; while Batman&amp;rsquo;s moral (and notebook) are clearly taken from &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rorschach_%28character%29&#34;&gt;Watchmen&amp;rsquo;s Rorschach&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nightmare alley</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/nightmare-alley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/nightmare-alley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/Q81Yf46Oj3s&#34;&gt;Guillermo Del Toro&amp;rsquo;s Nightmare Alley&lt;/a&gt; yesterday and&amp;hellip; It was ok.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I might have been let down a little because I love both Guillermo Del Toro and the source material (by the way, you can find both the original &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/nightmarealley1947&#34;&gt;black&amp;amp;white movie&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/nightmarealley00will/mode/2up&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; for free, legally, on the internet archive) so I had a lot of expectations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The actors are solid, the movie has a very nice forties ambiance (I love the psychologist&amp;rsquo;s office design) and some scenes are wonderful (the one scene dealing with the consequence of his actions&amp;hellip; and the final scene which was already one of the strong points from the original story) but I felt that the scenario was lacking. In particular, it gets very &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; linear and unsurprising once they get out of the carnival (also, I believe all the parts on the main character&amp;rsquo;s father could have been omitted, I suspect it hinders more than it adds to the story).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
