<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Speeches and texts on Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Speeches and texts on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Moloch</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/moloch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/moloch/</guid>
      <description>What sphinx of cement and aluminum bashed open their skulls and ate up their brains and imagination?
Moloch! Solitude! Filth! Ugliness! Ashcans and unobtainable dollars! Children screaming under the stairways! Boys sobbing in armies! Old men weeping in the parks!
Moloch! Moloch! Nightmare of Moloch! Moloch the loveless! Mental Moloch! Moloch the heavy judger of men!
Moloch the incomprehensible prison! Moloch the crossbone soulless jailhouse and Congress of sorrows! Moloch whose buildings are judgment!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rediscovering ideas</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/rediscovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/rediscovery/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Back in my religious days if you independently rediscovered an idea already uncovered by some rabbi 400 years ago it was a big deal and great honor, the whole class would celebrate you. The bigger the rabbi the greater the honor.&amp;rdquo; — @hormeze
 I think that this is a very healthy approach toward the rediscovery of ideas. Honoring both the lineage of knowledge and the ability to reach a particular conclusion instead of lamenting the fact that we do not get to reap the benefits of being the first to climb a particular hill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ozymandias</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/ozymandias/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/ozymandias/</guid>
      <description>I met a traveller from an antique land,
Who said—“Two vast and trunkless legs of stone
Stand in the desert. . . . Near them, on the sand,
Half sunk a shattered visage lies, whose frown,
And wrinkled lip, and sneer of cold command,
Tell that its sculptor well those passions read
Which yet survive, stamped on these lifeless things,
The hand that mocked them, and the heart that fed;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This too shall pass</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/this-too-shall-pass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/this-too-shall-pass/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;King Solomon once searched for a cure against depression. He assembled his wise men together. They meditated for a long time and gave him the following advice: Make yourself a ring and have thereon engraved the words &amp;lsquo;This too will pass.&amp;rsquo;
The King carried out the advice. He had the ring made and wore it constantly. Every time he felt sad and depressed, he looked at the ring, whereon his mood would change and he would feel cheerful&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Zen story</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/zen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/zen/</guid>
      <description>One day a famous government officer met a highly respected elderly master. Being conceited, he wanted to prove that he was the superior person.
As their conversation drew on, he asked the master, &amp;ldquo;Old monk, do you know what I think of you and the things you said?&amp;rdquo;
The master replied, &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t care what you think of me. You are entitled to have your own opinion.&amp;rdquo;
The officer snorted, &amp;ldquo;Well, I will tell you what I think anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Figures of speech</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/figures_of_speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/figures_of_speech/</guid>
      <description>Figures of speech (which you can find here) is a project done illuminations media for the Almeida Theater in which great actors read great speeches and it is absolutely fantastic.
It includes, amongst others, Ian McKellen reading Harvey Milk&amp;rsquo;s Hope Speech, Derek Jacobi reading Socrates&amp;rsquo; I Go To Die, and Noma Dumezweni reading Margaret Sanger&amp;rsquo;s The Morality of Birth Control.
The actors are great, the speeches have stood the test of time and it is a great vessel to get familiar with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First they came ...</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/first_they_came/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/first_they_came/</guid>
      <description>First they came for the Communists
And I did not speak out
Because I was not a Communist
Then they came for the Socialists
And I did not speak out
Because I was not a Socialist
Then they came for the trade unionists
And I did not speak out
Because I was not a trade unionist
Then they came for the Jews
And I did not speak out
Because I was not a Jew</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter from a Birmingham Jail</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/birmingham_jail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/birmingham_jail/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I have almost reached the regrettable conclusion that the Negro&amp;rsquo;s great stumbling block in his stride toward freedom is not the White Citizen&amp;rsquo;s Counciler or the Ku Klux Klanner, but the white moderate, who is more devoted to &amp;ldquo;order&amp;rdquo; than to justice; who prefers a negative peace which is the absence of tension to a positive peace which is the presence of justice.&amp;rdquo; — Martin Luther King Jr., Letter from a Birmingham Jail</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
