<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sweet on Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sweet on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The vegan fruity breakfast</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/breakfast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/breakfast/</guid>
      <description>This breakfast manages to both be delicious and give you the feeling that you are eating healthy. And it feels good. I get the needed ingredients about once a month to eat it for a few days (I feel that eating it every day would reduce my enjoyment).
Ingredients (1 bowl):   two tablespoons of granola1 two tablespoons of unsweetened coconut milk yogurt2 two tablespoons of blueberries a few strawberries3  Preparation:   put the granola in a bowl add the yogurt wash and add the blueberries wash, dice and add the stawberries  Credits:  You can find similar recipes on Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The two-ingredient chocolate mousse</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/chocolate_mousse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/chocolate_mousse/</guid>
      <description>This is the perfect recipe to do when you have leftover egg whites. It is delicious and uses barely any ingredients (I always keep the proper chocolate in my pantry to do this recipe when I have egg whites). Its only downside is that, once you have prepared everything, you need to wait.
Ingredients (1 portion):   1 egg whites1 35 grams of chocolate2  Preparation:   beat your egg whites into a nice firm foam melt the chocolate (it is okay to leave some chunks in the melted chocolate, they will add heterogeneity to the result) optionally, if you have egg yolks, add them to the melted chocolate and mix until homogeneous (be careful not to cook them in the hot chocolate) fold the melted chocolate into the egg whites pour into one glass, mug, or bowl per portion store in the fridge for at least 5 hours (you can wait a full night if you want to be sure) eat cold (you can shave some chocolate on top if you want to make it look fancy)  Credits:  The proportions are inspired by this Mousse au chocolat facile recipe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Crêpes</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/crepes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/crepes/</guid>
      <description>Crêpes are the perfect social dish. You can make them together then everyone put the topping of their choice on top, sweet or savory1.
Ingredients (4 people):   250 grams flour 25 grams of sugar 4 eggs 500 ml milk 50 grams of salted butter (or 40 grams of olive oil and a pinch of salt, the taste is slightly different but it works)  Preparation:   put the flour in a mixing bowl add the sugar add the eggs and mix add the milk progressively while mixing add the melted butter (making sure it is not hot enough to cook the eggs prematurely) and mix  Cooking:   slightly oil (or butter) the pan put a ladle worth of crêpe batter and spread it to make it round once the bottom is cooked (the sides should start to get browned), use a spatula and flip it (it should cook for about a minute) repeat as many times as needed  Credits:  This recipe is my version of Crêpes : la meilleure recette rapide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chef John&#39;s US pie crust</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/us_pie_crust/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/us_pie_crust/</guid>
      <description>This pie dough is easy to make and tastes pretty much perfect for a US-style pie (with crust below and above the pie). Plus, the leftover dough can be stored in the fridge for later use.
Ingredients (for one pie):   300 grams of flour 20 grams of sugar (optional) 227 grams of salted butter (get it out of the fridge as soon as you start to raise its temperature and make your job easier) 53 grams of water 8 grams of apple cider vinegar (needs testing to see how impactful it is)  Preparation:   put the flour in a large bowl add the sugar add the butter diced or sliced into thin slices (to simplify the mixing) with one hand mix the dough until you get a crumbly/flaky consistency add half of the water plus the vinegar and mix add the leftover water and mix into a ball cut the ball in two and refrigerate for 30 minutes while you prepare the fillings  Cooking:   You might want to prebake the bottom of our pie (for a European-style pie) or let your pie cook for a long time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The surprisingly-good-looking Clafoutis</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/clafoutis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/clafoutis/</guid>
      <description>Clafoutis was my favorite kind of cake when I was a kid. My mother used to make plum ones while fruits were in season and I famously ate a full cake that just got out of the oven while she was away from the kitchen. They are also a great way to turn fruits into a cake that looks very pretty while being extremely easy to make.
Ingredients:   about 500grams (you want to cover your pan with a nice layer) of a mix of cherries and apricots (stones fruits such as cherries, plums apricots, and peaches feel like a better match but it works with pretty much anything including bananas and rhubarb, I like a mix of cherries and apricots to vary colors and flavors) 4 eggs 100 grams of flour 60 grams of salted butter (you could use 45 grams of olive oil and some salt, the taste and texture would slightly differ but that still makes for a good cake) 60 grams of sugar (you could go up to 100 grams according to taste) 25cl of milk some vanilla extract (optional)  Preparation:  The pan   put a generous amount of butter on the sides of your cake pan (you want a wider rather than tall pan) cut your fruits (stones fruits can be cut into two or four, don&amp;rsquo;t forget to remove the stone, you can leave the skin on) and spread them in the cake pan  The batter   mix the eggs with the sugar until smooth add the (optional) vanilla extract add the flour while mixing add the milk while mixing melt the butter in a microwave (or oven but 30 seconds in a microwave is perfect) then add (if the butter is warm, mix it fast enough to not cook your egg) pour the batter into your cake pan (the batter will be more golden and liquid than usual cake batter, it is perfectly normal)  Cooking:   cook 30 to 45 minutes at 350F (180C), you can stop once the top is golden and the batter firm serve at room temperature (it is also great cold after a few hours in the fridge) you can (optionally) dust the top with powdered white sugar just before serving if you are serving cold (this is purely esthetic)  Credits:  This clafoutis batter is pretty classic and can be found all over the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The not-so-secret Crumble recipe</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/crumble/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/crumble/</guid>
      <description>Crumbles are pretty much impossible to miss and a great way to turn fruits (most fruits are suitable; apples, pears, and peaches are classic) and butter into a good cake. This one is pimped with chocolate chips, cinnamon, vanilla extract, and lemon juice. They are all worth it but, you can cut all of them if you want to keep things simple (or do not have them on hand).
Ingredients (for 4 portions):   100g of flour (you can easily turn the grams into cups and half cups: it is the respective proportions that matter) 100g of salted butter (you can also use unsalted butter and had some salt, the result is identical, but do not omit the salt) 50g of sugar 2 large pears some good cooking chocolate (no need for a sweet one, 70% cacao does a good job, also I like to get a chocolate bar and cut it into smallish chips, you get better quality chocolate and bigger chips) some cinnamon some vanilla extract some lemon juice  Preparation:  bottom layer   peel the pears, dice them, and put them on the bottom of your baking dish (I use a Pyrex square one), you want enough pears to garnish the bottom of the dish with about one centimeter of pears add some lemon juice on top, not much just a spoonful so that the pears are finely coated cut your chocolate into chips and sprinkle them on top of the layer of pears (no need for much, it is not a chocolate cake!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
