<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cartoons I like on Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cartoons I like on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Harley Quinn</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/harley-quinn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/harley-quinn/</guid>
      <description>What is it about?   We follow the adventure of Harley Quinn, Joker&amp;rsquo;s previous sidekick and girlfriend (in the Batman universe) as she becomes an independent villain with her own crew and a healthy love life.
The target public is teenagers to adults.
Why do I like it?   This show is both very funny and very good at character development1.
With time, the Batman universe has accumulated a lot of unhealthy behaviors2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amphibia</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/amphibia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/amphibia/</guid>
      <description>What is it about?   Amphibia is about a young girl being trapped in a world of talking frogs, adapting to her new environment and trying to get back home.
The target public is mostly younger children (no older than middle school).
Why do I like it?   The show is made of bite-sized, mostly self-contained adventures. It is very light-hearted1, you can pick up any episode and go along with the comedy and adventure of the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Batman Beyond</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/batman-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/batman-beyond/</guid>
      <description>What is it about?   The events of the cartoon happen years in the future, Bruce Wayne is now a grumpy old man mentoring a young new Batman.
The target public is middle school to high school children.
Why do I like it?   Batman Beyond is a Peter Parker (Spiderman) like teenager dressed as Batman and evolving in Blade Runner&amp;rsquo;s dystopian company-owned universe and it works so well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bob&#39;s Burger</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/bobs-burger/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/bobs-burger/</guid>
      <description>What is it about?   We follow Bob and his family trying to make ends meet with their small burger restaurant.
This cartoon is suitable for all ages and tries to give something to everyone.
Why do I like it?   Most family comedy shows display people that are very mean to each other1. Bob&amp;rsquo;s Burger, on the other side, is wholesome: showing us a loving family that stands united despite day-to-day struggles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craig of the Creek</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/craig-of-the-creek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/craig-of-the-creek/</guid>
      <description>What is it about?   We follow Craig and his friends as they play in the nearby woods (the eponymous creek) after school.
The target public is mostly younger children (no older than middle school).
Why do I like it?   This show is an ode to the power of imagination. We follow a group of children playing games and see the world through their eyes, never quite sure where reality stops and imagination begins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DuckTales</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/ducktales/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/ducktales/</guid>
      <description>What is it about?   Ducktales (the 2017 reboot) follows the adventure of Uncle Scrooge and his family as they scour the world for treasure.
The target public is mostly younger children (no older than middle school).
Why do I like it?   Ducktales is very funny.
While I am a fan of the original characters, this is a great take on them and it introduces some things that should become standard in this universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravity Falls</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/gravity-falls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/gravity-falls/</guid>
      <description>What is it about?   We follow twins during their summer vacation with their weird old uncle.
The target public is mostly younger children (no older than middle school).
Why do I like it?   This is twin peaks for kids.
This show strikes a great balance between being funny, mysterious, adventurous, quaint, somewhat a coming-of-age story and still funny1. All of the plots work well together and it juggles between tones seamlessly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Owl House</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/owl-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/owl-house/</guid>
      <description>What is it about?   The Owl House is about a young girl living her dream of moving to a world of witches.
The target public is mostly younger children (up to high school).
Why do I like it?   This is basically a cartoon version of Harry Potter with great representation (strong women, people of color / diverse ethnicities and wholesome LGBTQ+ relationships) and a strong &amp;ldquo;be your own quircky self&amp;rdquo; message.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
