<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Breviarium Politicorum on Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Breviarium Politicorum on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IV. Summary</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/5-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/5-summary/</guid>
      <description>Keep these five things in mind:
 Simulate. Dissimulate. Trust No One. Praise All. Mind Your Words  Simulate, Dissimulate   Show yourself as a friend to all and converse even with those you dislike, so that you may learn from their behavior and be cautious in your dealings with them.
Control your anger in all situations, as it can damage your reputation more than many virtues will enhance it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>III. Axioms</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/4-axioms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/4-axioms/</guid>
      <description>Treat any friend as if he may one day become your enemy. It is dangerous when a single individual becomes too powerful within any group or organization. When you desire something, let no one notice your intentions until you have obtained it. Stay vigilant and anticipate potential pitfalls to prevent them from occurring. Resolve matters through peaceful means whenever possible, avoiding war or disputes. Accept small losses instead of risking everything for potentially significant but uncertain gains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Word from the Publisher</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/1-word-publisher/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/1-word-publisher/</guid>
      <description>I had been delaying the publication1 of this Political treatise, sent to me by an Italian Prince, due to being overwhelmed with the most pressing matters. Now, under the orders of that same Excellent Prince, I am making it public. The importance of the subject, and the name of Cardinal Mazarin, whose life serves as the model and standard for the ideas presented here, will add significant weight to the commonly proposed political rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Signs of Power</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/assets/signs_of_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/assets/signs_of_power/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s be frank. Everything we know about Cardinal Mazarin (apart from his name in history textbooks glimpsed towards the end of the Thirty Years&amp;rsquo; War) comes from Dumas&amp;rsquo; Twenty Years After. A particularly odious cardinal, a sinister individual, a scoundrel and simulator compared to his eminent predecessor, the great Richelieu who knew how to defeat his enemies and grant a musketeer&amp;rsquo;s commission to those who deserved it, Mazarin lies, breaks his word, is reluctant to pay his debts, has the Duke of Beaufort&amp;rsquo;s dog, trained to bark at him, poisoned.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
