<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About on Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Consulting mentalist</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/mentalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/mentalism/</guid>
      <description>I am a consulting mentalist. Among other things, I have a book published for that public, give talks at specialized conventions, and I designed stage shows that are now playing in various1 countries.
What is Mentalism?   Mentalism is an ensemble of techniques (including mnemonics, hypnosis, magic tricks, a trained intuition, and knowledge of statistically likely phenomena) used to produce incredible phenomena (usually psychic phenomena or a mastery of the human mind) in an entertainment setting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research I did</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/research/</guid>
      <description>I am a researcher with specialties in numerical accuracy, artificial intelligence, data analysis, and high-performance computing.
Papers   You can find most of my publications on Researchgate:
High-level GPU code: a case study examining JAX and OpenMP. (high-performance computing)   This paper (published as part of the proceedings of Supercomputing 2023) contrasts and compares the use of both JAX and OpenMP target offload to port a large cosmology code to GPU.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software I wrote</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/software/</guid>
      <description>I am an engineer with a specialty in applied mathematics and computer science.
You can find most of the software I developed on Github and Gitlab. Here is a list of some noticeable libraries (focusing on projects where I am the lead developer):
Divinatory GPTs (Prompt)   This is a collection of scripts and prompts I used to make custom GPTs around the theme of divination (and, in particular, tools to help people become better tarot readers).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
