<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About on Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Consulting mentalist</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/mentalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/mentalism/</guid>
      <description>I am a consulting mentalist. Amongst other things, I have a book published for that public and, I designed stage shows that are now playing in various1 countries.
What is mentalism?   Mentalism is an ensemble of techniques (including mnemotechnic, hypnosis, magic tricks, knowledge of statistically likely phenomenons, and a trained intuition) used to produce incredible phenomenons (usually psychic phenomenons or an impressive mastery of the human mind) in an entertainment setting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research I did</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/research/</guid>
      <description>I am a researcher with specialties in numerical accuracy, artificial intelligence, data analysis, and high-performance computing.
Papers   You can find most of my publications on Researchgate:
High-level GPU code: a case study examining JAX and OpenMP. (high-performance computing)   This paper (published as part of the proceedings of Supercomputing 2023) contrasts and compare the use of both JAX and OpenMP target offload to port a large cosmology code to GPU.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software I wrote</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/software/</guid>
      <description>I am an engineer with a specialty in applied mathematics and computer science.
You can find most of the software I developed on Github and Gitlab. Here is a list of some noticeable libraries (focussing on projects where I am the lead developer):
Xmap (Python)   An alternative xmap implementation for Jax.
This implementation solves my gripes with the official implementation: providing a slightly improved interface, focuses on vectorizing a function along one or more axes (it implements none of the other functionalities supported by the official implementation), jits down to several calls to vmap (making it resilient to update on Jax&amp;rsquo;s side), and provides jit-time checks to try and catch common error (such as forgetting an argument or passing something of the wrong shape / type) with nice error messages.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
