<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 21:16:50 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cutting a bellpepper</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/technique/bellpepper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 21:16:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/technique/bellpepper/</guid>
      <description>credit adam ragusea</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cutting oignons</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/technique/oignon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 21:16:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/technique/oignon/</guid>
      <description>credit french guy cooking?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Melting butter</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/technique/melting_butter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 21:16:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/technique/melting_butter/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Melting chocolate</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/technique/melting_chocolate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 21:16:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/technique/melting_chocolate/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The everlasting pasta ratatouille</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/pasta_ratatouille/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 21:16:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/pasta_ratatouille/</guid>
      <description>I have been cooking variations of this dish for as long as I have been cooking for myself, starting when I had my first apartment. It has evolved a lot since its inception but it is still one of my favorite way to eat pasta.
Ingredients (for two portions):  160 grams of pasta (80 grams per person, you could go up to 100 grams), I like fusilli for this dish but most pasta types would be fine half a jar of organic1 ratatouille (this is where I lose my US readers, you simply cannot find this stuff in the US: you might replace it with a jar of tomato sauce that contains quite a bit of eggplants and assorted vegetables) some salted soy sauce (the salt will be useful) some olive oil (we will cook it so no need for high quality stuff) some salt (optional) some cayenne pepper (optional)  Preparation: Pasta  fill a pan with water and bring it to a boil (big bubbles, small bubbles do not count as boiling, you will be delighted to discover that I met people for which this is not obvious) you can optionally add a generous amount of salt to your pasta water, the pasta will taste better but do not need it here add the pasta when the water starts boiling and keep cooking for about 10 minutes (until your pasta are cooked)  Sauce  once the pasta are in the water, put the ratatouille in a wok (or similar large pan) on low heat add a generous splash of olive oil add a generous splash of soy sauce (this will bring you the salt in the dish plus a lot of the flavor) optionally, add a sprinkle of cayenne pepper (you want enough for people to realize the dish has some hotness but no more, it is not a hot dish) cook on low heat  Assembly  once the pasta are cooked, add a splash of pasta water in the wok, this will help with the sauce consistency (you can be approximate with the quantity, too little and your sauce will miss a bit of thickness, too much and you will have to reduce longer: either way the result will be fine and you can do better next time) you can do it directly from the pasta pan, no need for an intermediate container (that would give you additional opportunities to burn yourself) strain the pasta and add them to the wok (it is okay if there is some pasta water left with the pasta, we have pasta water in the wok anyway) raise to medium it and keep mixing until you get the sauce consistency you want (the mixing time will depend on the amount of water you put, you should be done in two minutes) serve in a plate, feel free to add butter and shredded Parmesan to pimp the result slightly  Credits: I used soy sauce and a jar of ratatouille because my father put them in my very first grocery bag as an independent student.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The mighty KrautBurger</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/krautburger/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 21:16:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/krautburger/</guid>
      <description>The Krautburger is my favorite homemade burger of the moment. It is vegetarian (but not vegan due to the presence of mayonnaise and, harder to replace, cheese) and light while hitting all the flavors I want due to the melted cheese and toasted bun combined with the surprise freshness of the thick tomato slice hidden inside the burger.
Ingredients (one burger):  a burger bun (bread rather than brioche if possible) some mayonnaise one tomato enough sauerkraut to make a small patty out of it (pick one that is not too flavorful and whose flavor you like, otherwise you might be disappointed by this burger&amp;hellip;) 2 slices of cheese (you want a cheese that does not melt instantly, so no American cheese, I like pepper jack because of the added flavor from the chili flakes, I would probably sprinkle some chilly flakes on my sauerkraut if all I had was Gruyère)  Preparation:  toast the lower bun (this step is optional but will reduce sogginess) spread a layer of mayonnaise on each half bun (the goal here is not to act on the taste but to stop water from going through and into the bun) put thick tomato slices on the bottom bun until it is fully covered (I like my slices about one centimeter thick) add one slice of cheese put some sauerkraut on top and shape it like a small pattie add the second slice of cheese add the final bun  Cooking:  toast in oven until the cheese is nicely melted and the top bun lightly toasted  Credits: This burger was born from some experimentation with leftovers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The not-so-secret Crumble recipe</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/crumble/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 21:16:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/crumble/</guid>
      <description>Crumbles are basically impossible to miss and a great way to turn fruits (most fruits are suitable; apples, pears and peaches are classic) and butter into a good cake. This one is pimped with chocolate chips, cinnamon, vanilla extract and lemon juice. They are all worth it but, you can cut all of them if you want to keep things simple (or do not have them on hand).
Ingredients (for 4 portions):  100g of flour (you can easily turn the grams in cups and half cups: it is the respective proportions that matter) 100g of salted butter (you can also use unsalted butter and had some salt, the end result is identical, but do not omit the salt) 50g of sugar 2 large pears some good cooking chocolate (no need for a sweet one, 70% cacao does a good job, also I like to get a chocolate bar and cut it into smallish chips, you get better quality chocolate and bigger chips) some cinnamon some vanilla extract some lemon juice  Preparation: bottom layer  peel the pears, dice them and put them on the bottom of your baking dish (I use a Pyrex square one), you want enough pears to garnish the bottom of the dish with about one centimeter of pears add some lemon juice on top, not much just a spoonful so that the pear are finely coated cut your chocolate into chips and sprinkle them on top of the layer of pears (no need for much, it is not a chocolate cake!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The secret of the Tarte au Maroille</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/tarte_maroille/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 21:16:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/tarte_maroille/</guid>
      <description>This cheese pie recipe is a family secret. It was past down from my grandmother to my mother to me (my sister did not care for cooking at the time). I am writing it so that it can be saved for future generation to enjoy (if you want to keep a secret, put it in writing).
Ingredients (two pies): Dought  1 kg of white flour 5 egg yolks 1 cube of fresh yeast (if you cannot find it, it is hard to find in the US, a sachet of dry yeast will be fine but result in a more homogeneous result) a few spoonfuls of sugar (white is fine, brown is better, cassonade/vergeoise is traditional) 125 grams of salted butter (butter is good, salted is better)  Toping:  one egg, one egg&amp;rsquo;s worth of milk, some grated nutmeg (optional) one big, full, Maroille (this is a washed rind cheese with a strong smell, slightly sticky texture and a pinkish color, typical from north France and very hard to replace in this recipe as most similar cheeses stay too strong once baked while Maroille&amp;rsquo;s taste mellow enough for even non cheese lovers to love this pie)  Preparation: Dough  Put the sugar and the yeast in a small bowl of warmish water (my rule of thumb is that it should feel warm, so above body temperature, but no more than that, if you can burn your finger then it will kill your yeast&amp;hellip; I should maybe invest in a thermometer), mix once and let rest until it gets foamy put most of the flour in a large mixing bowl (set a little aside to shape the dough later) add the egg yolks and the yeast with its water mix until combined, do not over mix (the resulting dough will be very sticky) cover with a towel and let rise for one hour (warmish places such as a window in the sun are best)  Assembling the pie  spread the dough on top of your pizza pans (you want flat pans rather than pie pans), you can use the leftover flour to help shape the dough (do not use a rolling pin, this is a finger stretching affair) add slices of Maroile on your pan (you want to cover it, the more the merrier) brush with a mix done with one egg and a little bit of milk (you can brush with your fingers) add a little bit of grounded nutmeg  Cooking:  Cook at 180C (350F) for 30 to 45 minutes (the crust should be hardened and the cheese pretty melted).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The surprisingly-good-looking Clafoutis</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/clafoutis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 21:16:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/clafoutis/</guid>
      <description>Clafoutis were my favorite kind of cake when I was a kid. My mother used to make plum ones while fruits were in season and I famously ate a full cake who just got out of the oven while she was away of the kitchen. They are also a great way to turn fruits into a cake that looks very pretty while being extremely easy to make.
Ingredients:  about 500grams (you want to cover your pan with a nice layer) of a mix of cherries and apricots (stones fruits such as cherries, plums apricots and peaches feel like a better match but it works with pretty much anything including bananas and rhubarb, I like a mix of cherries and apricots to vary colors and flavors) 4 eggs 100 grams of flour 60 grams of salted butter (you could use olive oil and some salt, the taste would differ but that still makes for a good cake) 100 grams of sugar (could be reduced according to taste) 25cl of milk some vanilla extract (optional)  Preparation: The pan  put a generous amount of butter on the sides of your cake pan (you want a wider rather than tall pan) cut your fruits (stones fruits can be cut into two or four, don&amp;rsquo;t forget to remove the stone, you can leave the skin on) and spread them in the cake pan  The batter  mix the eggs with the sugar until smooth add the (optional) vanilla extract add the flour while mixing add the milk while mixing melt the butter in a microwave (or oven but 30 seconds in a microwave is perfect) then add (if the butter is warm, mix it fast enough to not cook your egg) pour the batter in your cake pan (the batter will be more golden and liquid than usual cake batter, it is perfectly normal)  Cooking:  cook 30 to 45 minutes at 350F (180C), you can stop once the top is golden and the batter firm serve at room temperature (it is also great cold after a few hours in the fridge) you can (optionally) dust the top with powdered white sugar just before serving if you are serving cold (this is purely esthetic)  Credits This clafoutis batter is pretty classic and can be found all over the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A magician is a...</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/magician_is_actor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/magician_is_actor/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;A magician is an actor playing the part of a magician.&amp;rdquo; — Jean Eugène Robert-Houdin.
 The quote This essay is dedicated to magicians. Others might find it intriguing, but it will probably be irrelevant to them.
If you ask a magician to give you one famous quote about their object of study, the vast majority of them will tell you that Jean Eugène Robert-Houdin once said &amp;ldquo;A magician is an actor playing the part of a magician.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A script about a scriptwriter</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/script_about_scriptwriter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/script_about_scriptwriter/</guid>
      <description>STATUS: DRAFT
I believe there is an inherent lazyness to people writing about their own profession book, scriptwriter, mangaka, moviemaker
i understand the attraction, thus they can speak from experience and introduce some additoinal realism and maybe the illusion that it is a true story (link fargo)
obviously there are exeption, scott mccloud made a comic about making comics but it is not a comic about a comic writer, it is a comic about the theory and thinking that goes into making a comic a treaty on the subject</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Articles I like</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/articles/</guid>
      <description>the great ptolemaic smackdown</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogs I like</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/blogs/</guid>
      <description> gwern xkcd qntm slate star codex the jerx news from marmalade fall speeches collection on youtube  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consulting mentalist</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/mentalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/mentalism/</guid>
      <description>I am a consulting mentalist (I have a book published for that public and I designed a stage show amongst other things).
What is mentalism? Mentalism is an ensemble of techniques (including mnemotechnic, hypnosis, magic tricks, a knowledge of statistically likely phenomenons and a trained intuition) used to produce incredible phenomenons (usually psychic phenomenons or an impressive mastery of the human mind) in an entertainment setting.
One point that is worth stressing is that it is neither all real (magic tricks are great to make things look better / add some punch and anyone telling you they don&amp;rsquo;t use them is either lying or very ignorant) nor all fake (anyone telling you otherwise is, similarly, likely ignorant or a magician who did some telepathy-themed tricks and think that it is all there is to it, the human mind is an amazing toy).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consummers and producers</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/concepts/consumers_producers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/concepts/consumers_producers/</guid>
      <description>STATUS: DRAFT
but there is a risk of feeling bad about consuming too much and then you consume to feel better</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critical path</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/concepts/critical_path/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/concepts/critical_path/</guid>
      <description>STATUS: DRAFT</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eldritch Academia</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/fiction/eldritch_academia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/fiction/eldritch_academia/</guid>
      <description>Object: Some News Hey Sonia,
How are you doing?
To answer your question (sorry for the late email, moving did not leave me much time to write), the math department is paying me to study KTu-L spaces.
You might have seen some reference to them popping up in the past year, they have gained a lot of visibility as some mathematicians (mostly Providence’s research team which I will be joining this week) claim that they can be used to solve a number of interesting conjectures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>False dichotomy</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/concepts/false_dichotomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/concepts/false_dichotomy/</guid>
      <description>STATUS: DRAFT
definition example its a rethoric device it also, and more importantly, applies to one one&amp;rsquo;s thinking</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grocerie bag</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/objects/cabas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/objects/cabas/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nestor&#39;s guide to creating a blog</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/blogging/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: this guide is mostly about me keeping a trace of the process I followed to create this blog. I really wanted to use GitHub for the hosting and that leads to a lot of additional complexity that you should avoid if you are not used to writing code.
Hosting I used GitHub pages to host my blog, they are free but only support static websites and, by default, force you to use their domain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nestor&#39;s guide to dating apps</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/dating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/dating/</guid>
      <description>General principles A lot of the following might seem obvious to you but, as what is obvious to some isn’t to others, I am putting a maximum of information here in the hope that you might find things that you do not already know.
There are a lot of men per woman on those apps so women there are used to doing very little work and having a lot of choices to select from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nestor&#39;s guide to doing hard things</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/hard_things/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/hard_things/</guid>
      <description>STATUS: DRAFT
cut them into smaller things
do a small thing to lower the barrier of entry
be okay when it starts to be late and you have done nothing
make it look good fast
The easy path be conscious of the temtation to be lazy and do something &amp;ldquo;good enough&amp;rdquo; you will recognise it when you will think that it is too much effort for too little recompense
the easy path</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nestor&#39;s guide to having ideas</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/ideas/</guid>
      <description>STATUS: DRAFT
Making a habit of thinking about problems, writing my ideas and organizing them has been extremely valuable in all fields where I applied it I do not think that you can make a habit of producing good ideas but if you produce enough ideas you will end up producing at least a few good ones, it is only a matter of time.
Also, having a good storage system lets me revisit ideas that were imperfect at a later point in time when I might have the correct frame of mind or knowledge to improve on them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nestor&#39;s guide to writing</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/writing/</guid>
      <description>STATUS: DRAFT
disclaimer: I have written non-fiction profesionaly in various fields by never published any fiction so take the following with the appropriate amoint of salt
do a bad version first
identify lazyness things you could improve to make the result better but do not improve because you think it is good enough even if you know it would make it better
story circle
snowflake method
make it look good fast</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nightmare alley</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/nightmare-alley/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/nightmare-alley/</guid>
      <description>I watched Guillermo Del Toro&amp;rsquo;s Nightmare Alley yesterday and&amp;hellip; It was ok.
I might have been let down a little because I love both Guillermo Del Toro and the source material (by the way, you can find both the original black&amp;amp;white movie and the book for free, legally, on the internet archive) so I had a lot of expectations.
The actors are solid, the movie has a very nice forties ambiance (I love the psychologist&amp;rsquo;s office design) and some scene are wonderful (the one scene dealing with the consequence of his actions&amp;hellip; and the final scene which was already one of the strong points from the original story) but I felt that the scenario was lacking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philips toothbrush</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/objects/toothbrush/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/objects/toothbrush/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Production value</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/concepts/production_value/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/concepts/production_value/</guid>
      <description>STATUS: DRAFT</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research I did</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/research/</guid>
      <description>STATUS: DRAFT
I am a researcher with a specialty in numerical accuracy, artificial inteligence and high performance computing.
list of my notable publications with some description my researchgate</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rubber duck debugging</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/concepts/rubber_duck_debugging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/concepts/rubber_duck_debugging/</guid>
      <description>STATUS: DRAFT
One good tip I got to rubber duck debug without another human was to write your questions / explanations in an email or a chat. I found that indeed, writing an email explaining a problem to a colleague was helpful to solve it despite me never sending the email.
It also applies to debugging the human mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software I wrote</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/software/</guid>
      <description>STATUS: DRAFT
I am an engineer with a speciality in applied mathematics and computeur science.
List of some noticeable codes i published my github and gitlab</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some heuristics I use</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/heuristics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/heuristics/</guid>
      <description>STATUS: DRAFT
 play to your strengths, being balanced sounds nice but end up being really unproductive / un-pleasant be nice / kind / non-jugemental to people spend time on the things you like, as time and practice pile up you will end up skilled in those domain go for the things that are of interest to you, not for the trendy ones time spend automating tasks is usually time well spent taking a break to gather knowledge on something vaguely connected to the thing you are doing is never time lost when you have been procrastinating something for most of the day, declare that you will not do it today and that it is okay, it will free your mind to do other things instead of leaving you stuck try and do one, single and quantifiable, thing a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Batman</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/the-batman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/the-batman/</guid>
      <description>Note: this review is adapted from some text messages so it is written in a flow of consciousness type of way.
I saw the Batman and&amp;hellip; meh.
I love the acting of the Riddler in his unmasked sections (he looks like and accountant and that is great).
Some solid action scenes but none of the set pieces really strikes me.
The gadgets are really nice (lenses, parachte, etc) but the scenario leaves me cold.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
