<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reading Speculative Books</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/55-reading-speculative/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/55-reading-speculative/</guid>
      <description>When reading an assertion, consider the following: the main message, the number of points made, the specific words used and their order, what can be inferred, and how the assertion is proven.
To internalize the assertion, break down the arguments into a logical structure and anticipate potential responses.
Are the premises sufficiently strong or well-supported? How can the supporting arguments be confirmed and what examples can be provided? With what main idea or argument does it agree or seem to conflict?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visiting Provinces</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/54-visiting-provinces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/54-visiting-provinces/</guid>
      <description>First, when arriving in a new region, avoid keeping records that are easily readable by the locals. Instead, write any noteworthy observations, whether positive or negative, in a foreign language. This prevents locals from taking offense if they happen to come across your notes.&amp;quot;
Second, observe all sacred objects in both public and private spaces, such as the interiors of temples, epitaphs, offerings, tombs of notable figures, and religious symbols and architecture such as organs, columns, and pulpits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being Accused</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/53-being-accused/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/53-being-accused/</guid>
      <description>If you notice that someone has accused you, conceal your knowledge of the accusation and do not immediately change your behavior. This way, the informer cannot boast that their accusation was well-received by the Prince or superior they reported to.
Instead, when the opportunity arises, insinuate to the Prince that your accuser is an enemy and an informer. Suggest that informers, like traitors, are useful when needed but should never be truly trusted or loved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accusing</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/52-accusing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/52-accusing/</guid>
      <description>Avoid being the first to accuse, and refrain from bringing a lawsuit against someone you know the judge favors more than you. Only proceed if you have noticed the judge&amp;rsquo;s opinion shifting in your favor.
If you have brought a lawsuit, or one has been brought against you, even if your cause is most just, act as if it were extremely bad.
Approach and influence the judges with gifts, and your adversary through mediators who may meet with him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arriving at the Truth</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/51-arriving-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/51-arriving-truth/</guid>
      <description>To get an honest opinion about your actions, pretend that someone else is describing them, or read about your own deeds as if they were performed by another person. Then ask for opinions.
Remember that people have different views, and keep in mind that friends may be more forgiving in their evaluation.
If you receive measured praise, you can be more confident in the opinion&amp;rsquo;s sincerity. Giving some praise is considerate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Lending Money</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/50-avoiding-lending/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/50-avoiding-lending/</guid>
      <description>When lending items, instruct the servant who is delivering them to provide a detailed receipt. Have the servant sign the receipt as if they were acting on their own behalf, without your knowledge.
If you cannot avoid lending money, consider the following options: claim that you are also in debt or do not have the full amount requested, and ask to borrow something of equal value in return; or explain that you can provide the money without interest if your friend offers collateral.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Emotions</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/49-managing-emotions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/49-managing-emotions/</guid>
      <description>If you openly display strong emotions or personal feelings for too long, people will eventually oppose your actions. Therefore, it is better to refrain from publicly displaying these emotions or behaviors. Encourage others who genuinely feel the same way to do the same.
In the meantime, it is best to focus on serious matters to distract yourself from the emotions you wish to eliminate.
By doing so, you will conceal your true feelings of anger or happiness from even the most attentive observers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arguing and Correcting</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/48-arguing-correcting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/48-arguing-correcting/</guid>
      <description>Avoid criticizing someone when they expect praise or are expressing gratitude.
Praise even the smallest deeds, as this encourages diligence.
It is best to admonish someone through a mutual friend, in a confidential manner.
If someone is involved in illicit loves and you wish to help them break free, keep them occupied with challenging tasks and responsibilities.
Discreetly arrange for others to criticize the person&amp;rsquo;s words or deeds. Have them report their findings to you, provide false testimony, and disapprove of all the person&amp;rsquo;s actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Vain Pursuits</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/47-avoiding-vain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/47-avoiding-vain/</guid>
      <description>When dealing with a serious matter, let others focus on trivial aspects like applause and glory.
If an enemy wishes to surrender a city, offer them the most honorable conditions. Make them believe they are doing you a favor rather than being conquered. Let him depart with his banners unfurled and provide him with all the symbolic trappings of victory. In exchange, ensure that he yields the lands, hands over the captives, and leaves behind the gold and fortifications before sunset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traveling</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/46-traveling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/46-traveling/</guid>
      <description>Never reveal how much money you have to anyone. If strangers ask about your wealth, always claim to have very little.
Deceive potential thieves as much as you can, and tell no one which direction you are heading. To further conceal your route, ask different people for directions and get varying answers.
Beware of joining quarrelers, as they often start fights to distract and rob those who get involved. If someone taunts you, hide your true feelings and remain calm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deposing the Wicked</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/45-deposing-wicked/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/45-deposing-wicked/</guid>
      <description>If you want to remove someone from their position, start by withholding the funds necessary for them to perform their key responsibilities. This will cause the person to incur debts. These debts can then be used as a pretext to justify their removal from office and subsequent punishment. Ensure that the debts are portrayed as illegitimate, so that the creditors themselves may demand repayment from the person, further pressuring them. Thus you have punished the person financially without trouble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Averting Suspicion</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/44-averting-suspicion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/44-averting-suspicion/</guid>
      <description>Read the section titled Gaining Favor, Avoiding Offense, and Acting Cautiously.
If you are suspected of having slandered or discredited some accusers before the Prince, write letters praising them to the Prince, and ensure these letters reach those who suspect you.
Alternatively, if you wish to vex them, allow genuinely blank letters to be intercepted, making them suspect various secret writing techniques, such as the use of invisible ink that can be revealed by water or heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acquiring Dexterity in Acting</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/43-acquiring-dexterity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/43-acquiring-dexterity/</guid>
      <description>When sympathizing with someone&amp;rsquo;s suffering, console them using common expressions of support, without touching on anything that may offend them.
If someone is disparaged in your presence, be most cautious - neither praise nor condemn them. Both are odious.
Always speak well of your superiors, even if they have offended you. When someone else speaks ill of your superiors, do not agree or pretend to agree with them, even if it pleases you to do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disregarding Criticism</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/42-disregarding-criticism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/42-disregarding-criticism/</guid>
      <description>People are most deceitful when it comes to giving praise or mockery, flattery or taunts.
Collect written satires or mocking texts about you and read them yourself. Also, have others read them and laugh at them, as this will cause the author to despair.
Do not reveal a satirical piece written against you. If it must be revealed, invent a reason for doing so. However, if the satirical piece must be displayed, take the following steps: read it often at home, learn to laugh at it, and assume appropriate emotions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintaining Inner Peace</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/41-maintaining-inner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/41-maintaining-inner/</guid>
      <description>Avoid setting strict deadlines for accomplishing tasks, as unforeseen circumstances may arise, causing you to either neglect other matters or become distressed if you are unable to meet your goal.
Understand that your subordinates are likely to make mistakes; therefore, avoid over-planning.
Disregard the complaints of your subjects about you.
If entrusted with a secret, either decline to accept it or keep it strictly confidential.
Avoid accepting responsibility for others&amp;rsquo; money or belongings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling Self-Praise</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/40-handling-selfpraise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/40-handling-selfpraise/</guid>
      <description>Be cautious not to let praise lead to comparisons or claims of being unique, even if true, as such statements are rarely believed.
If someone openly praises you in the presence of the Prince, doubt whether they have secretly accused you. When you receive excessive praise, be cautious. If all your actions are praised, you are thanked for everything, and you are favored above others, be highly suspicious of these flatteries, as it may be a trap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quelling a Sedition</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/39-quelling-sedition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/39-quelling-sedition/</guid>
      <description>When dealing with a group, never allow more than one person to address you at a time. Instead, let the group choose a single representative from among themselves.
Inquire into the causes of an uprising. If it is due to usury, lend without interest yourself.
Offer great rewards to whoever quells the sedition, suggests a way to resolve it, eliminates the ringleaders, or betrays them.
If the people are rebellious or unruly, they must above all be guided towards virtue by good men.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Punishing and Correcting</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/38-punishing-correcting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/38-punishing-correcting/</guid>
      <description>Do not strike with your own hand, lest you acquire cruelty.
If you need to severely punish someone but lack strong justification, consider this approach: First, punish them for a mild offense that you would typically forgive. The offender will resent it and begin to complain and grumble. When punished again, he will complain again, until as if obstinate, he will give greater cause for a greater punishment, having been found guilty of a serious offense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleeing</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/37-fleeing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/37-fleeing/</guid>
      <description>Carry acid, such as burnt wine, and use it to drench clothes stuffed with straw. Suspend these clothes to create a diversion. The guard will believe you acted out of desperation and, neglecting his watch, will spread word to the others. Seize this opportunity to escape.
Feign illness by eating red ochre to simulate bloody stools, pressing near your elbow to alter your pulse, or inducing pallor. Then request that a doctor be summoned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Controlling Anger</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/36-controlling-anger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/36-controlling-anger/</guid>
      <description>Do not be quick to anger at anyone. Often, you will find that the matter was reported maliciously, or that you misunderstood it. If you act out of anger, the harm will remain with you.
If someone wrongs you, it is best to conceal your true feelings. Quarreling only leads to more conflicts and disrupts peace. Even if you emerge victorious, the consequences will be more severe than if you had been defeated, and you will attract more opposition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preventing Someone from Declining a Duty</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/35-preventing-someone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/35-preventing-someone/</guid>
      <description>If the person objects or makes an excuse, assure them that you will respect their wishes if it becomes evident that assigning them this duty was not in their best interest.
After you have departed, leave behind letters announcing the person&amp;rsquo;s new office. Instruct that these letters be read on a specific date. If the person writes letters back to you, do not respond to them.
If he complains, reassure him by saying that he will hold the office for only a short time and will be relieved of his duties soon if it seems appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Praising Others</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/34-praising-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/34-praising-others/</guid>
      <description>Pretend to be frank, acting as if you speak and act based solely on your own judgment and for the public good, and as if you hate nothing more than flattery.
Excuse someone&amp;rsquo;s gentleness and mercy as a duty of piety, so that their strictness and severity may weaken.
Avoid praising someone in a way that openly criticizes others, except perhaps in a crowd with many confused voices.
Leave people&amp;rsquo;s virtues unpraised and overlook their vices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissolving Friendships</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/33-dissolving-friendships/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/33-dissolving-friendships/</guid>
      <description>When ending a friendship, never abruptly break it off, as if you suddenly hate the person due to a perceived slight or offense. Instead, having reconciled and showing fervent love, gradually withdraw. To allow the friendship to gently dissolve, gradually reduce the frequency of your meetings. If you must meet, keep the conversations brief and invite them to dinner, acting as if you are burdened by business. This way, it won&amp;rsquo;t seem like you were only pretending to be their friend until you decided to cast them out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stirring Hatred Against the Wicked</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/32-stirring-hatred/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/32-stirring-hatred/</guid>
      <description>When in the presence of someone whose favor your target seeks or enjoys, praise your target in a way that may turn into an offense to their benefactor. Mention that what you said is commonly rumored, emphasizing that you are not expressing your own opinion. Imply to the benefactor that he should be concerned about his own reputation and that the reputation of those close to them is also at risk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covering Mistakes</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/31-covering-mistakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/31-covering-mistakes/</guid>
      <description>If you stumble in speech or act thoughtlessly, pretend it was deliberate, to test the judgment of others, or that you misspoke while trying to express something else. Smile as if you achieved your intended goal, or grieve as if you did not.
If you have made a mistake due to ignorance, do not ask others about it in a way that reveals your lack of knowledge or error. Plan ahead on how you would seek the truth or ask for others&amp;rsquo; opinions on what they would do in a similar situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Negotiating Shrewdly</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/30-negotiating-shrewdly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/30-negotiating-shrewdly/</guid>
      <description>When betting on an outcome, place an equal bet with another person on the opposite result. This way, regardless of the actual outcome, you will not incur any net loss.
When drafting onerous contracts, incorporate ambiguous terms that allow for broad or narrow interpretation. For example, upon a city&amp;rsquo;s surrender, promise to preserve everything if no uprising occurs, without specifying publicly or privately whether this applies to your own soldiers or the city&amp;rsquo;s inhabitants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acting in a Novel Way</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/29-acting-novel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/29-acting-novel/</guid>
      <description>Consider four things before acting in a novel way:
 First, consider whether it will be more beneficial or harmful to you? Second, ask yourself if you possess the necessary abilities or talents? Third, consider whether it aligns with your current status? Fourth, consider whether you are respected in your current role? And in the role you aspire to?  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Losses</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/28-avoiding-losses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/28-avoiding-losses/</guid>
      <description>Pay attention to even the smallest issues. Have your agents immediately report to you any potential sources of harm, so that you can take action before it occurs. Furthermore, ask them to suggest preventive measures.
The rates for buying and selling things should be observed, and experts should be consulted about unknown matters.
Each week, have the steward report on what has been accomplished.
After everyone has gone to bed, assign one person to check that the house is locked and note who is absent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feasting</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/27-feasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/27-feasting/</guid>
      <description>When hosting a feast, focus on items that can be preserved, such as candied fruits, decorative wax figurines, ornate fountains, artificial mountains, and self-playing musical instruments.
Include artistic elements that are fitting for the occasion, such as wax candelabra covers bearing the coats of arms of your guests, colorful drinks, scented beverages that seem imported from afar, and artificial wines like those described by Arnaldus de Villa Nova.
Present flowers, colored lettuces, giant eggs made from several smaller eggs and seasoned with spices, candles burning from ice, fragrant fires, vomiting mountains, fountains sprinkling snow, and fake fragrant fruits or apples brought to the table on the very branch - all things which can grow in your garden at little expense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Emotions</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/26-managing-emotions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/26-managing-emotions/</guid>
      <description>Compile examples of emotions and expressions from poetry, such as those found in the Palatium Eloquentiae1, and practice the ones you need until you have mastered them.
Trust no one, not even your closest friend. When interacting with others, you may pretend to trust them, but always maintain control over your facial expressions and words when showing affection. Remember that your face can reveal as much as your words.
Overcome your own timidity, so that even in moments of self-doubt, you can still act as boldly as you have in similar circumstances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responding to Requests</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/25-responding-requests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/25-responding-requests/</guid>
      <description>When presented with a request, do not refuse immediately. Instead, engage in some discussion before refusing. Once you have refused, stand firm in your decision. Only concede for serious reasons.
When you are about to refuse a request, take a moment to consider it, then pretend to be sorrowful. Alternatively, arrange for letters to be brought to you or have someone announce sad news. To achieve this, instruct a trusted servant to give you a predetermined signal, indicating through gestures and words that you are unable to fulfill the requester&amp;rsquo;s desire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaining and Conferring Honors</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/24-gaining-conferring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/24-gaining-conferring/</guid>
      <description>First, persuade others that it is necessary to bestow honor in a manner that you yourself define through the circumstances. Then, excuse yourself from receiving this honor, as if you had already possessed it to the same degree as you do now.
Strive for good and clear counsel and do many things that are pleasing to the public, such as the construction of public buildings, providing aid to the poor, and implementing measures that can be done without suddenly increasing taxes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Wealth</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/23-managing-wealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/23-managing-wealth/</guid>
      <description>Do not despise small gifts and be attentive to losses.
Avoid being wasteful with resources, such as allowing bread, food, or horse feed to go to waste.
Confer with skilled financial advisors and learn their methods.
Consider what can be sold, planted, or produced from your lands. Employ craftsmen to help you achieve these goals.
Know your entire income and always have an eye on your affairs.
Before incurring expenses, consider how you can recover an equal amount, so that you don&amp;rsquo;t lose money overall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Ambushes</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/22-avoiding-ambushes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/22-avoiding-ambushes/</guid>
      <description>Stage a quarrel with a friend to trick your enemy into believing you are genuinely at odds with each other. This may prompt your enemy to reveal their true feelings as they attempt to exploit the situation. Then, suddenly resist and oppose the enemy with your friend&amp;rsquo;s combined strength.
This tactic can also be used against robbers planning an ambush on the road or in similar situations. Intentionally make yourself appear vulnerable and approach the ambush site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joking</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/21-joking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/21-joking/</guid>
      <description>Avoid obscene words or actions, as these are the habits of foolish people. Similarly, refrain from mimicking the sounds of birds or other animals.
Never make jokes about things that would embarrass the other person, such as their physical or personality flaws, as these will leave a negative lasting impression. Furthermore, avoid speaking about the misfortunes of others, whether they are present or not. It is better to listen to such stories than to tell them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversing with Others</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/20-conversing-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/20-conversing-others/</guid>
      <description>Know yourself and from what background you come.
Some people may seem unpleasant to talk to at first, but as you spend more time with them, their wisdom becomes apparent, making the conversation more agreeable. Others may appear prudent and learned at first, but over time, they may prove to be flawed in their judgment or the consequences of their actions. Adapt your interactions based on the type of person you&amp;rsquo;re dealing with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Rid of an Unwelcome Guest</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/19-unwelcome-guest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/19-unwelcome-guest/</guid>
      <description>Arrange a signal with your servant beforehand. When they receive the signal, have them call you away as if for urgent business. They can whisper in your ear, send a messenger with letters, or announce that harm has been done or that there are disturbances among your subjects.
Have a doctor forbid you from speaking or drinking, etc.
Have a saddled horse brought, as if you are about to depart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acting Cautiously</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/18-acting-cautiously/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/18-acting-cautiously/</guid>
      <description>Being cautious involves two aspects: cautious trust and a certain generosity. Cautious trust means being on guard even with friends, as some friendships exist to deceive, and trusting no one without reason to suspect them. Generosity, in this context, means refraining from indiscriminately telling the truth or correcting others&amp;rsquo; errors and habits, while maintaining a pretense of doing so, although this is not entirely harmless.
Entrust a secret to no one, because anyone can become an enemy at any moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acquiring Prudence</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/17-acquiring-prudence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/17-acquiring-prudence/</guid>
      <description>As much as possible, be silent and listen to the advice of others, and carefully weigh it in your mind.
Take care not to be carried away by the passion of love.
Do not value your own words and deeds too highly.
Do not occupy yourself with useless matters that will be of no future use.
Finally, do not entangle yourself in the affairs of others.
Freely give others credit for accomplishments, even if you have greatly contributed to the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encouraging Action</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/16-encouraging-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/16-encouraging-action/</guid>
      <description>To encourage someone to act, take responsibility for any potential losses, such as goods or property, and offer specific rewards in return.
For example, before a battle, a commander should announce compensation for specific injuries, that he will cover their losses in goods and baggage; meanwhile, he should place a strong garrison in the camp, lest concern for it distract the soldiers&amp;rsquo; minds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Offense</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/15-avoiding-offense/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/15-avoiding-offense/</guid>
      <description>If you have been reluctant or less generous in granting someone&amp;rsquo;s request, be careful not to be overly generous to others in a similar situation for some time afterward, even if it seems minor. Otherwise, you will either arouse distrust towards yourself or incite hatred between the parties involved.
Never increase severity toward those you govern unless you also increase rewards or benefits at the same time; otherwise, you will either incur hatred or contempt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discerning Intentions</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/14-discerning-intentions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/14-discerning-intentions/</guid>
      <description>First, examine a person&amp;rsquo;s motives and assess whether they are consistent with their claimed actions, typical behavior, or the actions they are suspected of committing. Additionally, note if the person is acting more passionately or more cautiously than they typically do.
If a person is not acting in their own interest, or if they abruptly change their stance with great zeal, it may indicate that they have been bribed.
If a person does not agree after their stated reasons have been thoroughly disproven, they are not genuinely motivated by those reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering Secrets</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/13-uncovering-secrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/13-uncovering-secrets/</guid>
      <description>Engage even people of low status in conversation. Overcome by kindness, especially if you grease their palms with gold, they will likely tell you everything you want to know. (You can also gather information by talking with children, but this comes with certain risks.)
Set servants against each other, so they will betray each other&amp;rsquo;s secrets.
However, it is crucial to always keep your promises to everyone. Failing to do so will cause them to lose trust in you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Envy</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/12-avoiding-envy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/12-avoiding-envy/</guid>
      <description>Avoid acting as a witness in disputes. Doing so will inevitably offend one side or the other.
Do not speak poorly of anyone, and do not show disdain through your gestures. If you make a scornful remark about someone, continue the conversation as if nothing happened.
In the presence of others, do not show special favor to anyone. If you do, those who are not favored will feel despised and begin to hate you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Additional References</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/references/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/references/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The more the poem is read, the less it is read except in translation&amp;rdquo; — John D. Niles, Rewriting Beowulf: The Task of Translation
 Beowulf has been translated and adapted many times (you will find a handy comparison of various translations here). I believe this stems from the impossibility of producing a perfect translation—a translation that would both preserve the form (alliterative verse) and produce a text whose meaning is clear to modern readers (is the text even designed to be read silently?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preserving Health</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/11-preserving-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/11-preserving-health/</guid>
      <description>Avoid eating too little or too much, and ensure that your food is of good quality.
Dress appropriately for the weather, avoiding excessive heat or cold.
Avoid sleeping, working, or living in uncomfortable or stressful environments.
Do not spend too much time in high altitudes.
Overeating and irregular bowel movements are the sources of diseases. Engage in moderate physical activity and rest, and keep your emotions under control.
Do not dwell near swamps or even rivers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Deception</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/10-avoiding-deception/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/10-avoiding-deception/</guid>
      <description>Be cautious when trusting prudent men. They may minimize issues related to their own duties and be too generous when judging the reputations of others. They will not reveal if anyone has spoken badly about you in their presence, nor whom you should be wary of, or what vices they themselves struggle with. The same is true of priests when they praise their penitents, because they can say nothing but good about them, no less than parents about their children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translator&#39;s Notes</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/notes/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Like any interpretive work, a translation is the result of a volatile hermeneutic process. Its readers should be wary of accepting it as a record of “what the text says,” for the text says many things, some of them enigmatically.&amp;rdquo; — John D. Niles, Rewriting Beowulf: The Task of Translation
 The bulk of the translation work was done using Artificial Intelligence (and in particular Claude Opus1).
The process and prompt I used are detailed below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Admonishing</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/9-admonishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/9-admonishing/</guid>
      <description>To reprimand someone without them realizing it, begin by discussing unrelated topics. Then, subtly exaggerate and criticize the actions you want to address. To obscure the fact that you are reprimanding them, add other details to the conversation. Additionally, frequently encourage them to be positive and cheerful, and include some jokes to lighten the mood. If they become sad, inquire about the reason. After discussing their emotional state, add all the other points you want to make at the end, even discussing potential solutions in a general sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IIX. Twilight</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/8-twilight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/8-twilight/</guid>
      <description>Then the prince went and sat on a seat by the wall, thoughtfully gazing on the work of giants, how the stone-arches held up the eternal earth-hall from within. His thane, glorious in his victory, washed the blood-stained hand of his lord abundantly with water, the great-hearted man, weary from his battle-wounds, and loosened his helmet.
Beowulf spoke in spite of his injuries, his mortal wound; he knew full well that he had spent his allotted days, his worldly joy; then all was gone for him, the count of his days, death very near: &amp;ldquo;Now I would give my war-gear to my son, if any heir had been granted to me, born of my body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asking for Things</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/8-asking-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/8-asking-things/</guid>
      <description>When asking a friend for a favor, make sure your request doesn&amp;rsquo;t require too much money or effort. Simply letting them know you need help should suffice. If your friend does not provide the favor voluntarily, he will not do so even if you ask directly. However, express gratitude for all help provided, as this will subtly convey your desire for further assistance.
If you are about to request something serious, first discuss other matters and subtly explain your desires as if doing something else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VII. The Dragon</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/7-dragon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/7-dragon/</guid>
      <description>The dragon guarded a hoard in the high heath, a stone-barrow; a path ran beneath, unknown to men. Inside, a certain man had entered who seized a cup, a gold-plated treasure; he did not give it back, though he had tricked the sleeping guardian with thievish craft. The king found out that his rage was provoked.
It was not by his own desire that the man sought out the dragon&amp;rsquo;s hoard, bringing about woe and destruction; rather, out of dire necessity, a servant, one of some slaves, sought refuge there with a guilty conscience, fleeing heavy blows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving Gifts and Favors</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/7-giving-gifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/7-giving-gifts/</guid>
      <description>Be generous in giving what you know others will not ask for, or what they will never use, such as privileges.
A teacher should not teach his student everything he knows, in order to maintain the student&amp;rsquo;s desire to learn more. Similarly, a parent should not give their child so much that the child no longer needs or hopes for anything more from the parent. The same principle applies to a master&amp;rsquo;s relationship with his servant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VI. Trophies</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/6-trophies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/6-trophies/</guid>
      <description>Beowulf spoke, the son of Ecgtheow: &amp;ldquo;Lo, son of Healfdene, prince of the Scyldings, we have joyfully brought you this sea-booty, which you gaze on here, as a token of glory. I hardly survived it, hazarded an undersea battle, engaged in a risky task. The fight would soon have been finished if fate had not protected me. I could not accomplish anything with Hrunting in the conflict, though that weapon is strong; but the All-Father granted that I saw a beautiful, powerful sword hanging on the wall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading and Writing</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/6-reading-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/6-reading-writing/</guid>
      <description>If you are writing in a public place, pretend to be copying from another document. Hold up a sheet of paper so others can see it, while keeping your actual writing hidden. Cover your work with a book or another sheet of paper, or position the raised paper so that only the line you appear to be copying is visible to anyone who approaches.
If someone approaches while you are reading, quickly turn to a different page to avoid drawing attention to your focus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>V. Grendel&#39;s Mother</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/5-mother/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/5-mother/</guid>
      <description>She came then to Heorot, where the Ring-Danes slept throughout the hall. Misfortune befell the nobles when Grendel&amp;rsquo;s mother burst in upon them. The terror was less only by so much as the strength of women, the war-terror of a wife, is less than an armed man&amp;rsquo;s, when the bound sword, hammer-forged and stained with blood, the keen blade with its edge, cuts the boar on the helmet of the opposed warrior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acquiring Gravity</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/5-acquiring-gravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/5-acquiring-gravity/</guid>
      <description>Undertake occupations suitable to your role: for example, a Prelate should not handle weapons, a Nobleman should not practice chiromancy, a Religious person should not practice medicine, and a Priest should not teach fencing.
Avoid making promises or concessions.
Laugh sparingly, and when you do, keep it brief.
Do not change what has been decided.
Avoid staring at others.
Do not turn up your nose or furrow your brow.
Do not be sullen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IV. Summary</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/5-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/5-summary/</guid>
      <description>Keep these five things in mind:
 Simulate. Dissimulate. Trust No One. Praise All. Mind Your Words  Simulate, Dissimulate   Show yourself as a friend to all and converse even with those you dislike, so that you may learn from their behavior and be cautious in your dealings with them.
Control your anger in all situations, as it can damage your reputation more than many virtues will enhance it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IV. The Morning After</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/4-celebrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/4-celebrations/</guid>
      <description>In the morning, as I have heard, many a warrior gathered around the gift-hall. Tribal chiefs came from far and wide over distant paths to behold the wonder, the tracks of the enemy. His parting from life did not seem grievous to any of the men who saw the splendor of the inglorious one&amp;rsquo;s footprints, how he, weary in spirit and overcome in the fight, doomed and driven out, bore his death-marks to the mere of the water-monsters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding More Time for Business</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/4-time-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/4-time-business/</guid>
      <description>Delegate minor tasks to others.
Establish a strict schedule for yourself and adhere to it without deviation. Allocate the smallest amount of time to the smallest tasks, and spend only the time needed to complete each task effectively.
When fatigued by work, avoid undertaking anything further. Instead, refresh yourself with honest play and physical activity. Afterward, you will accomplish more, with greater ease and in a shorter time. If you must work, take on a task that you can handle without effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>III. Axioms</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/4-axioms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/4-axioms/</guid>
      <description>Treat any friend as if he may one day become your enemy. It is dangerous when a single individual becomes too powerful within any group or organization. When you desire something, let no one notice your intentions until you have obtained it. Stay vigilant and anticipate potential pitfalls to prevent them from occurring. Resolve matters through peaceful means whenever possible, avoiding war or disputes. Accept small losses instead of risking everything for potentially significant but uncertain gains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>III. Beowulf</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/3-beowulf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/3-beowulf/</guid>
      <description>In the beer-hall, a bench was cleared for the Geats to sit together, the stout-hearted ones proud in their strength. A thane did his duty, bearing in his hands the decorated ale-cup, pouring out the bright sweet drink. At times, a clear-voiced scop sang in Heorot, and there was joy among the heroes, a great host of Danes and Weders.
Unferth, son of Ecglaf, who sat at the feet of the Scyldings&amp;rsquo; lord, spoke, unbinding a battle-rune.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>English Translation</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/6-translators-notes/2-translation/1-english/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/6-translators-notes/2-translation/1-english/</guid>
      <description>Breviarum Politicorum   A Word from the Publisher   I had been delaying the publication of this Political treatise, sent to me by an Italian Prince, due to being overwhelmed with the most pressing matters. Now, under the orders of that same Excellent Prince, I am making it public. The importance of the subject, and the name of Cardinal Mazarin, whose life serves as the model and standard for the ideas presented here, will add significant weight to the commonly proposed political rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaining Esteem and Reputation</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/3-esteem-reputation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/3-esteem-reputation/</guid>
      <description>Never assume that someone will keep a secret if you act or speak too freely or confidently in their presence, even if they are a child or servant. They will judge you by this action and describe you accordingly to others.
Never assume that someone will excuse your questionable behavior; in fact, they will likely interpret it in the worst possible way. To prevent this, avoid engaging in any actions that could be seen as questionable, even if there is only one witness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>II. Grendel</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/2-grendel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/2-grendel/</guid>
      <description>At dawn, as day broke, Grendel&amp;rsquo;s deeds were laid bare. After their feasting, wailing filled the morning air, a great cry of sorrow. The renowned ruler, long good and noble, sat joyless, the strong one suffering for his thanes as they beheld the loathsome foe&amp;rsquo;s track, the accursed spirit&amp;rsquo;s trail. That struggle was too strong, too long-lasting and loathsome.
After a single night, Grendel wrought more slaughter, not shrinking from his evil, firmly set in his ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I. Beginnings</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/1-beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/1-beginnings/</guid>
      <description>Listen well! Let me tell you of the glory of the Spear-Danes&amp;rsquo; kings in days long past, and the valorous deeds of those mighty princes.
Scyld Scefing, abandoned as a child, rose to seize the mead-benches from many tribes and troops of enemies. From this, he found solace. He grew under the heavens, thriving with honors, until each nation across the whale-road had to obey him and pay tribute. That was a good king!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identifying Who is Someone&#39;s Friend</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/2-identifying-someones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/2-identifying-someones/</guid>
      <description>If you praise someone and a listener remains silent in response, it indicates that the listener is not truly the praised person&amp;rsquo;s friend.
You can also tell that a person is not another&amp;rsquo;s friend if they respond to your praise in certain ways. These include diverting the conversation elsewhere, speaking halfheartedly or reluctantly, diminishing the praise, claiming the story is inconsistent, attributing part of the praise to others, or failing to enhance your praise despite knowing about a praiseworthy deed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latin Reference</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/6-translators-notes/1-latin-reference/2-latin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/6-translators-notes/1-latin-reference/2-latin/</guid>
      <description>Breviarum Politicorum, Secundum Rubricas Mazarinicas   Typographus Lectori   Quem ad me Princeps Italus tractatum hunc Politicum in lucem edendum miserat, gravissimis districtus negotiis, typis mandare distuleram, nunc ejusdem Excellentissimi Principis jussu publicum facio. Materia dignitas, et Eminentissimi Cardinalis Mazarini nomen, ad cujus vitae modulum et normam adornata sunt et composita quae hic proponuntur maxime, superpondium non leve politicis regulis, quae vulgo proponuntur, additurus est. Quam enim gravissimis procellis immersus, et tantum non submersus fuerit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn About Others</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/2-fundamentals/2-learn-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/2-fundamentals/2-learn-others/</guid>
      <description>Much can be learned about someone&amp;rsquo;s true character in situations like sickness, drunkenness, gain or loss of money, games, and travel. When the doors of the mind are relaxed, the wild beasts more readily emerge from their dens.
Pay attention to how people behave during times of affliction, especially when they are insulted or facing other challenges. Interact with those you wish to know better during these situations to gain insights into their character.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Word from the Publisher</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/1-word-publisher/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/1-word-publisher/</guid>
      <description>I had been delaying the publication1 of this Political treatise, sent to me by an Italian Prince, due to being overwhelmed with the most pressing matters. Now, under the orders of that same Excellent Prince, I am making it public. The importance of the subject, and the name of Cardinal Mazarin, whose life serves as the model and standard for the ideas presented here, will add significant weight to the commonly proposed political rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaining Favor</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/1-gaining-favor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/1-gaining-favor/</guid>
      <description>Identify your friend&amp;rsquo;s interests and choose gifts that align with them. Suitable items include mathematics books, optical instruments, microscopes, sundials, various mirrors, and other curiosities, as well as treatises on the secrets of nature, such as those written by Mizauld.
Speak with him often, consult him, and ask for his advice, then follow it. But never lay yourself so bare that if he becomes your enemy, he can use it against you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn About Yourself</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/2-fundamentals/1-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/2-fundamentals/1-learn/</guid>
      <description>Are you overcome by anger, fear, rashness, or some other strong emotion? What defects are evident in your conduct during various activities, such as dining, attending church, conversing, playing games, or engaging in other social interactions?
Examine all the parts of your body: are your eyes too insolent, foot or head bent too far, forehead wrinkled, lips unkempt, gait too slow or fast?
With whom do you associate? Are they praiseworthy, successful, prudent individuals?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Original Sources</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/6-translators-notes/1-latin-reference/1-sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/6-translators-notes/1-latin-reference/1-sources/</guid>
      <description>Scans of several prints of the text can be found online. From them emerge three main editions of the text: an original edition, an expanded edition, and a simplified edition.
Original Edition   These are print and reprints of the original edition, with only minor tweaks between each other.
 1684 Print (original) 1691 Print 1694 Print 1695 Print 1696 Print 1697 Print 1700 Print  Expanded Edition   This edition is greatly expanded, including a first Ubi Ingenium Excolendum section as well as a De Conciliatione Animorum final section; these are most likely other booklets touching on similar topics that have been added for padding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prelude</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/0-prelude/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/beowulf/0-prelude/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;If you wish to translate, not rewrite Beowulf, your language must be literary and traditional: not because it is now a long while since the poem was made, or because it speaks of things that have since become ancient; but because the diction of Beowulf was poetical, archaic, artificial (if you will), in the day that the poem was made.&amp;rdquo; — J. R. R. Tolkien, Beowulf: The Monsters and the Critics</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tower and the Critics</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/tower/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/tower/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;A man inherited a field in which was an accumulation of old stone, part of an older hall. Of the old stone some had already been used in building the house in which he actually lived, not far from the old house of his fathers. Of the rest he took some and built a tower. But his friends coming perceived at once (without troubling to climb the steps) that these stones had formerly belonged to a more ancient building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When his Salary depends on it</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/salary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/salary/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;It is difficult to get a man to understand something, when his salary depends on his not understanding it.&amp;rdquo; — Upton Sinclair, I, Candidate for Governor: And How I Got Licked
 When I affirm that something is safe, good, or necessary, how much of it comes from my salary depending on its success or continuation?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheesy Egg Toast</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/sandwich/egg_toast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/sandwich/egg_toast/</guid>
      <description>This is pretty much peak cheesy toast experience1: it is crispy, cheesy, very flavorful, yet filling like a generous slice of a savory cake. Plus, as a nice bonus, once you have the ingredients, you can just pile them up in the right order and be done with. There are no intermediate cooking steps or other elements that would make it a time-consuming process.
Ingredients (one toast):    two thick2 slice of bread, two slices of cheese3, two thin slices of pepperoni4, a tablespoon of butter5, one garlic clove, one room temperature egg, shredded cheese6, salt, pepper7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nestor&#39;s Guide to Giving a Presentation</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/presentation/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Only the prepared speaker deserves to be confident.&amp;rdquo; — Dale Carnegie
In my early engineering school days, I was lucky to intern with a team of biologists who were really good at presenting their ideas (be it for conferences or internal meetings). This taught me a lot of things and set what I believe are good practices.
Here are some of the key things I try to have in mind when I give a presentation1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nestor&#39;s Guide to Remembering Things Forever</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/spaced_repetition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/spaced_repetition/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;La répétition fixe la notion.&amp;rdquo; — Anonymous
I have been using mnemotechnic techniques for about a dozen years now (they are definitely the one thing I wish I would have known when I was a student with important exams coming up), but I recently became enamored with spaced repetition as an easy way to learn anything you want and remember it forever.
Imagine being able to trust the process and knowing that if you get started today, in six months you will know a complex piece of knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astrology SOS</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/astrology_sos/</guid>
      <description>Astrology SOS, by The Woke Mystix, is not about telling you what your zodiac sign (there is already a plethora of books about that out there) does but rather to give you a sense of rhythm.
Our rhythms1 as well as the rhythm of the weeks, seasons2, planets, etc. It is not about woo3, it is about keeping your ear to the flow of life and seasons. Being aware of the flow to be able to take actions4 instead of being a cork raised by the tide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forgotten Wolves.</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/fiction/forgotten_wolves/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/fiction/forgotten_wolves/</guid>
      <description>As a kid, I knew that there were wolves in the dark. Scrawny wolves walking naked on their hind legs. Wolves that talk to you before eating you, but wolves nonetheless. Wolves you forget as soon as they leave your field of vision.
At night, I would turn the lights on, progressively, carefully, as I went from my bedroom, through a corridor, down the stairs, by the underground cellar, to the toilets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leek Gratin</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/weekday_meal/leek-gratin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/weekday_meal/leek-gratin/</guid>
      <description>I absolutely love this recipe. It is dead easy, legitimately 2 ingredients &amp;ndash; the leek juice and melted cheese combining to make the sauce &amp;ndash;, delicious but unlikely to weight you down. Very much worth cooking when leeks are in season, and you want something warm and cheesy to pick up your soul.
Ingredients:    2 big leeks1 1 full2 Roblochon3  Cooking:    Cut the leeks into 1cm slices then cook them in salted water until they reach your favorite consistency4 drain the leeks carefully in a colander then transfer them to the bottom of you cooking pan put a layer of cheese slices on top of the leeks cook in an oven at 350F (180C) until the cheese is melted or crispy to your preference5 eat hot  Credits:   This particular take on the recipe came straight from a French book of recipe whose name sadly escapes me at the moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pasta (cherry) Tomatoes Basil</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/weekday_meal/pasta_tomatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/weekday_meal/pasta_tomatoes/</guid>
      <description>This is an easy pasta dish that has a surprising depth of flavor.
Ingredients (for two portions):    160 grams of pasta1 (80 grams per person) some salt some olive oil a generous amount of pepper the equivalent of one and a half large cloves of garlic a dozen leaves of basil2 100 grams (roughly) of cherry tomatoes3 optionally about 30 grams of butter  Preparation:   Mise en place    rince the basil leaves and dice them very finely crush the garlic cut the cherry tomatoes in fourth4  Pasta    fill a pan with water and bring it to a boil add a generous amount of salt to your pasta water5 add the pasta when the water starts boiling and keep cooking for about 10 minutes (until your pasta is cooked)  Sauce    put the olive oil in a wok add a very generous amount of pepper and cook on high heat until the pepper becomes fragrant6 add the crushed garlic and finely diced basil add the tomatoes let simmer until the pasta are ready  Assembly    once the pasta is cooked, add a splash of pasta water to the wok, this will help with the consistency of the sauce strain the pasta and add them to the wok (it is fine if there is some pasta water left with the pasta, we added pasta water to the wok anyway) optionally add the diced butter start mixing on high heat until you reach the desired consistency7  Credits:   This recipe is an array of classic techniques put together to produce a pasta dish with a (cherry) tomatoes and basil sauce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Failure of Imagination</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/concepts/failure-of-imagination/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/concepts/failure-of-imagination/</guid>
      <description>A failure of imagination usually refers to a bad outcome which, despite being predictable, is not imagined and thus not planned for. However, I use the expression in a more positive light, to speak of a good outcome that, despite being possible, is not imagined and thus not explored. I know of two failures of imagination:
The first failure of imagination is imagining that something is impossible without actual proof. Even given proof that something is impossible, one should be attentive to the hypotheses that went into the proof, as well as to what exactly has been proven impossible1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Responsibility of the Poet</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/responsibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/responsibility/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;We are now inclined to make much of this distinction between amateur and professional, but it is reassuring to know that these words first were used in opposition to each other less than two hundred years ago. Before the first decade of the nineteenth century, no one felt the need for such a distinction &amp;ndash; which established itself, I suppose, because of the industrial need to separate love from work, and so it was made at first to discriminate in favor of professionalism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banana Bread</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/banana_bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/banana_bread/</guid>
      <description>The one thing one should do with old bananas. Easy and delicious.
Ingredients:     113 grams salted butter
  150 grams sugar
  3 ripe bananas
  2 eggs
  1 small teaspoon vanilla extract
  1 tablespoon milk
  walnuts (optional)
  cooking chocolate1
  240 grams flour
  1 teaspoon baking powder
  1 teaspoon baking soda</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garlic toast</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/sandwich/garlic_toast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/sandwich/garlic_toast/</guid>
      <description>This recipe will produce something flavorful, buttery, garlicky and tomato-y within minutes.
Ingredients (one toast):    one slice of bread (I recommend multigrain bread, it has more depth of flavor once toasted) 2 tablespoon of butter 1 clove garlic a handful of cherry tomatoes a similar amount of feta cheese  Preparation:     melt the butter in a microwave
  press the garlic and mix it with the butter1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naans</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/naan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/naan/</guid>
      <description>Naans are very easy to make, go well with any curry or thick sauce, and make for a nice change of carbs.
Ingredients (3 big naans):     200 grams flour
  1 teaspoon sugar
  a big pinch of salt
  1/2 teaspoon baking powder
  3 tablespoons of olive oil
  125 grams yogurt
  7 centiliters1 of water
  1 tablespoon butter (or ghee), 1 clove garlic and (optionally) cilantro for garlic naans</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gochujang Buttered Noodles</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/weekday_meal/gochujang_noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/weekday_meal/gochujang_noodles/</guid>
      <description>While this is a quick way to pimp up cheap instant noodles, turning them into a pasta dish that feels fancy, this buttered gochujang sauce can also be used to elevate any kind of pasta.
Ingredients (single serving):    1 pack of instant noodles 2 cloves of garlic 2 big tablespoons of salted butter 1 big teaspoon gochujang paste1 1 tablespoon of sherry or rice vinegar 1 tablespoon honey scallions (optional)  Preparation:   Pasta    put the instant noodles in boiling water cook to your desired consistency  Sauce    press2 the garlic first melt the butter in a pan as soon as the butter starts sizzling, add the garlic and mix add the gochujang, vinegar, and honey bring to a boil while mixing then let rest while waiting for the pasta to be ready  Assembly    add the noodles and a splash of pasta water to the sauce add one teaspoon of butter mix on high heat until well coated transfer to a bowl optionally sprinkle diced scallions on top  Credits:   This is my take on Eric Kim&amp;rsquo;s Gochujang Buttered Noodles (see also here for a video of the recipe).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French Apple Cake</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/apple_cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/apple_cake/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is simple, surprisingly delicious, lets the apple shine through, and yet can be done with flavorless leftover apples.
Ingredients (one square cake pan):    3 large apples 2 teaspoons apple cider vinegar1 115 grams of salted butter 100 grams of white sugar 2 teaspoons of brown sugar (about 30 grams) 2 large eggs 1 large teaspoon vanilla extract2 120 grams flour 1 teaspoon baking powder  Preparation:     finely dice the apples3</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moloch</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/moloch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/moloch/</guid>
      <description>What sphinx of cement and aluminum bashed open their skulls and ate up their brains and imagination?
Moloch! Solitude! Filth! Ugliness! Ashcans and unobtainable dollars! Children screaming under the stairways! Boys sobbing in armies! Old men weeping in the parks!
Moloch! Moloch! Nightmare of Moloch! Moloch the loveless! Mental Moloch! Moloch the heavy judger of men!
Moloch the incomprehensible prison! Moloch the crossbone soulless jailhouse and Congress of sorrows! Moloch whose buildings are judgment!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On a Monday Darkly.</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/fiction/monday/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/fiction/monday/</guid>
      <description>Jim started digging at the crossroad. He felt heavy, he wasn’t quite sure if it was the pasta or the meat, but eating before coming was probably a bad idea… but it&amp;rsquo;s not as if he had experience with this stuff.
Once the hole was big enough, he wrapped a silver dollar in one original page of Krazy Kat and buried it in the dirt. Then, he waited.
A fly started to bother him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Signs of Power</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/bonus/signs_of_power/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/bonus/signs_of_power/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s be frank. Everything we know about Cardinal Mazarin (apart from his name in history textbooks glimpsed towards the end of the Thirty Years&amp;rsquo; War) comes from Dumas&amp;rsquo; Twenty Years After. A particularly odious cardinal, a sinister individual, a scoundrel and simulator compared to his eminent predecessor, the great Richelieu who knew how to defeat his enemies and grant a musketeer&amp;rsquo;s commission to those who deserved it, Mazarin lies, breaks his word, is reluctant to pay his debts, has the Duke of Beaufort&amp;rsquo;s dog, trained to bark at him, poisoned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Mug Cake</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/mug_cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/mug_cake/</guid>
      <description>This is a recipe for a basic yellow mug cake. It might be a bit dry but it is perfect when you want cake in under five minutes. Feel free to add fruits, lemon juice/zests, chocolate chunks, or anything else really, to make it fancy!
Ingredients (one bowl of cake):    1 egg1 2 tablespoons of sugar 4 tablespoons of flour 1 teaspoon of baking powder2 3 tablespoons of milk 1 tablespoon of salted butter3  Preparation:    mix the egg with the sugar add the flour and baking powder, mix add the milk, mix melt the butter in the microwave, add it and mix add any additional (flavoring) ingredient  Cooking:    microwave about 1min204  Credits:   This is my take on this recipe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alignment.</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/fiction/alignement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/fiction/alignement/</guid>
      <description>This text, written in collaboration with ChatGPT, is not about an AI taking over the world.
 Hana, the head of the software development team, reclined in her chair, seeking a brief respite from her work. She absentmindedly clicked on her Reddit bookmark, hoping for a few minutes of distraction. To her surprise, the site was unresponsive. As if on cue, Tom, one of her engineers, strode towards her desk, exuding an unmistakable air of urgency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avocado Bread</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/avocado_bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/avocado_bread/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is simple, tastes good, has an interesting texture and, more importantly, looks extremely weird making it a fantastic party dessert.
Ingredients (one rectangular cake pan):    2 (very ripe) avocados 100 grams of sugar 3 eggs 240 grams of flour 6 grams (one and a half) teaspoon of baking powder  Preparation:    dice the inside of the avocados and put them in a large bowl cream1 the avocados and sugar together beat the eggs into the mix add the flour and baking powder fold together  Cooking:    cook for 30 to 35 minutes in a 350F (180C) oven  Credits:   The recipe comes from Dylan Hollis&amp;rsquo;s excellent Youtube channel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tuesday Night Club: A Miss Marple Short Story</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/tuesday_night_club/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/tuesday_night_club/</guid>
      <description>“As an artist I have knocked about among all sorts and conditions of people. I know life as darling Miss Marple here cannot possibly know it.”
 I recently finished reading Agatha Christie&amp;rsquo;s The Tuesday Night Club and it is surprisingly sharp.
A group of friends (a writer, an artist, a clergyman, a lawyer and a police commissioner) is having a late-night discussion, hosted by the old aunt of one of the members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Red Bean Paste Cookie</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/red_bean_paste_cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/red_bean_paste_cookies/</guid>
      <description>Those cookies are very worth doing. They focus the flavor on the red bean paste while looking fancier than they are difficult to cook (which is always a good thing).
Ingredients (2 person):    1 egg 50 grams of salted butter 100 grams of flour 25 grams of icing sugar1 1 teaspoon vanilla extract 100 grams of red bean paste2 optional: 1 additional egg for brushing3 optional: sesame seeds  Preparation:   Cookie dough    whisk the egg in a bowl add the softened4 butter and mix until homogeneous add the flour, icing sugar and vanilla extract mix until smooth5 cover and refrigerate for one hour  Assembly    get the dough on a floured6 surface using a rolling pin, shape the dough into a long rectangle shape the red bean paste into a thick bar and place it in the middle of the rectangle carefully fold the two sides of the rectangle over the bar and flip it to put the seam down cut the resulting bar of dough into squarish cookies  Decoration    whisk the additional egg and brush the cookies with it7 sprinkle some sesame seeds on the cookies  Baking    bake 20 to 25 minutes at 360F (180C) let cool down a little before eating  Credits:   This recipe is mostly my notes on China Sichian Food&amp;rsquo;s Red Bean Paste Cookie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rediscovering ideas</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/rediscovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/rediscovery/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Back in my religious days if you independently rediscovered an idea already uncovered by some rabbi 400 years ago it was a big deal and great honor, the whole class would celebrate you. The bigger the rabbi the greater the honor.&amp;rdquo; — @hormeze
 I think that this is a very healthy approach toward the rediscovery of ideas. Honoring both the lineage of knowledge and the ability to reach a particular conclusion instead of lamenting the fact that we do not get to reap the benefits of being the first to climb a particular hill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate decadence flourless cake</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/flourless-chocolate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/flourless-chocolate/</guid>
      <description>This cake feels light yet very buttery, delicious and fully decadent.
Ingredients:    3 eggs 90 grams of white sugar 30 grams of plain yogurt 5 grams (about 2 teaspoons) of cornstarch 1 teaspoon of vanilla extract 1 teaspoon of grounded instant coffee 120 grams of salted butter 170 grams of 64% cacao chocolate one large pear  Preparation:   Eggs    separate the white and yolks1 of the eggs beat the egg whites in a large bowl  Batter    in a large bowl, mix the sugar, yogurt, vanilla, coffee powder, cornstarch melt the butter and chocolate in the microwave then add to the mixture dice the pear and add it to the mix fold in the egg whites2 pour in a pan lined with parchment paper  Cooking:    cook 50 to 60 minutes in a 275F (135C) oven (it will still be fudgy once done) let cool in the pan before storing in the fridge for one to two hours before serving  Credits:   This is my take on Brian Lagerstrom&amp;rsquo;s Super Easy Flourless Chocolate Cake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kougelhopf</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/kougelhopf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/kougelhopf/</guid>
      <description>Kougelhopf is the quintessential Alsacian cake. This bundt cake is perfect for breakfast, sliced and covered with a thin layer of salted butter.
Ingredients (one large Kougelhopf):    75 grams of dried grapes 20 centiliters (200 grams) of milk 25 grams of fresh yeast1 500 grams of flour 75 grams of sugar 2 eggs 150 grams of salted butter a dozen almonds  Preparation:   Grapes    Puts the dried grapes in room temperature water to let them soak during the rest of the process  Yeast    mix the yeast with a few tablespoons of flour and 10 centiliters of lukewarm2 milk let rest until the yeast bubbles up  Dough    mix the flour, sugar and eggs add the leftover milk dice the butter and add it mix until the butter is properly incorporated add the yeast and milk to the dough, mix for a few minutes let rest one hour in a warm place (near a heater for example)  Pan    generously butter a Kougelhopf pan3 put almonds in the bottom indentations of the pan add the grapes to the dough put the dough in the pan let rest for about one hour (or until the dough fully fills the pan)  Cooking:    cook 45 minutes at 180C (350F)4 once it has had some time to cool down, unmold it onto a flat plate once cold, you can sprinkle some powdered sugar on the result for better looks  Credits:   This is my take on Marmiton&amp;rsquo;s Kougelhopf sucré (Alsace) recipe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pâte sablée (short crust pie)</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/pies/pate_sablee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/pies/pate_sablee/</guid>
      <description>This is a great pie dough for most open-style pies. It is rich in butter and tastes great by itself, even raw!
Ingredients (for one pie):    75 grams of sugar 1 egg 250 grams of flour 100 grams of salted butter1  Preparation:    mix the sugar and egg in a large bowl add the flour dice the butter and add it to the mix mix until homogeneous2  Cooking:    use a rolling pin to flatten the dough before putting it in the pie pan3 add the sweet pie fillings4 of your choice you might want to prebake the pie crust for about 10 minutes at 180C (350F)  Credits:   This is my take on Marmiton&amp;rsquo;s Pâte sablée recipe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grace Hopper</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/old-people/grace-hopper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/old-people/grace-hopper/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The most important thing I&amp;rsquo;ve accomplished, other than building the compiler, is training young people. They come to me, you know, and say, &amp;lsquo;Do you think we can do this?&amp;rsquo; I say, &amp;lsquo;Try it.&amp;rsquo; And I back &amp;rsquo;em up. They need that. I keep track of them as they get older and I stir &amp;rsquo;em up at intervals so they don&amp;rsquo;t forget to take chances.&amp;rdquo; — Grace Hopper
 Grace Hopper was both an admiral of the US navy and a pioneer of computer science, introducing some concepts that are now fundamental to programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hokusai</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/old-people/hokusai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/old-people/hokusai/</guid>
      <description>Hokusai is considered one of the greatest masters in the history of art. Even if you do not know his name, you have seen a reproduction or a take on his Great Wave off Kanagawa.
In his seventies, shortly after making the Great Wave off Kanagawa, he wrote:
 &amp;ldquo;From the age of six, I had a passion for copying the form of things and since the age of fifty I have published many drawings, yet of all I drew by my seventieth year there is nothing worth taking into account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yitang Zhang</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/old-people/yitang-zhang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/old-people/yitang-zhang/</guid>
      <description>Yitang Zhang was born in 1955. He obtained his Ph.D. at 36 but, having no publications nor the support of his advisor, he had to quit academia and work as an accountant and a delivery worker, sometimes sleeping in his car, while trying to make ends meet.
At 58 years old, he published an extremely influential paper on bounded gaps in prime numbers which suddenly gained him a large number of prizes, a prestigious university position and wide recognition in the world of mathematics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ozymandias</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/ozymandias/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/ozymandias/</guid>
      <description>I met a traveller from an antique land,
Who said—“Two vast and trunkless legs of stone
Stand in the desert. . . . Near them, on the sand,
Half sunk a shattered visage lies, whose frown,
And wrinkled lip, and sneer of cold command,
Tell that its sculptor well those passions read
Which yet survive, stamped on these lifeless things,
The hand that mocked them, and the heart that fed;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This too shall pass</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/this-too-shall-pass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/this-too-shall-pass/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;King Solomon once searched for a cure against depression. He assembled his wise men together. They meditated for a long time and gave him the following advice: Make yourself a ring and have thereon engraved the words &amp;lsquo;This too will pass.&amp;rsquo;
The King carried out the advice. He had the ring made and wore it constantly. Every time he felt sad and depressed, he looked at the ring, whereon his mood would change and he would feel cheerful&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guillermo Del Toro&#39;s Pinocchio</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/pinocchio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/pinocchio/</guid>
      <description>Guillermo Del Toro&amp;rsquo;s Pinocchio is surprisingly both a very faithful rendition of the original story and a very Del Toro movie.
It has a lot of Del Toro&amp;rsquo;s elements (older spirits meddling with human life, a found family, a refusal to glorify war and fascism as a background) but, if you did not know that it was a Del Toro movie, you would accept all of those elements as coming from the original material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harley Quinn</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/harley-quinn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/harley-quinn/</guid>
      <description>What is it about?   We follow the adventure of Harley Quinn, Joker&amp;rsquo;s previous sidekick and girlfriend (in the Batman universe) as she becomes an independent villain with her own crew and a healthy love life.
The target public is teenagers to adults.
Why do I like it?   This show is both very funny and very good at character development1.
With time, the Batman universe has accumulated a lot of unhealthy behaviors2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amphibia</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/amphibia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/amphibia/</guid>
      <description>What is it about?   Amphibia is about a young girl being trapped in a world of talking frogs, adapting to her new environment and trying to get back home.
The target public is mostly younger children (no older than middle school).
Why do I like it?   The show is made of bite-sized, mostly self-contained adventures. It is very light-hearted1, you can pick up any episode and go along with the comedy and adventure of the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Batman Beyond</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/batman-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/batman-beyond/</guid>
      <description>What is it about?   The events of the cartoon happen years in the future, Bruce Wayne is now a grumpy old man mentoring a young new Batman.
The target public is middle school to high school children.
Why do I like it?   Batman Beyond is a Peter Parker (Spiderman) like teenager dressed as Batman and evolving in Blade Runner&amp;rsquo;s dystopian company-owned universe and it works so well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bob&#39;s Burger</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/bobs-burger/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/bobs-burger/</guid>
      <description>What is it about?   We follow Bob and his family trying to make ends meet with their small burger restaurant.
This cartoon is suitable for all ages and tries to give something to everyone.
Why do I like it?   Most family comedy shows display people that are very mean to each other1. Bob&amp;rsquo;s Burger, on the other side, is wholesome: showing us a loving family that stands united despite day-to-day struggles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craig of the Creek</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/craig-of-the-creek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/craig-of-the-creek/</guid>
      <description>What is it about?   We follow Craig and his friends as they play in the nearby woods (the eponymous creek) after school.
The target public is mostly younger children (no older than middle school).
Why do I like it?   This show is an ode to the power of imagination. We follow a group of children playing games and see the world through their eyes, never quite sure where reality stops and imagination begins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DuckTales</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/ducktales/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/ducktales/</guid>
      <description>What is it about?   Ducktales (the 2017 reboot) follows the adventure of Uncle Scrooge and his family as they scour the world for treasure.
The target public is mostly younger children (no older than middle school).
Why do I like it?   Ducktales is very funny.
While I am a fan of the original characters, this is a great take on them and it introduces some things that should become standard in this universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravity Falls</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/gravity-falls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/gravity-falls/</guid>
      <description>What is it about?   We follow twins during their summer vacation with their weird old uncle.
The target public is mostly younger children (no older than middle school).
Why do I like it?   This is twin peaks for kids.
This show strikes a great balance between being funny, mysterious, adventurous, quaint, somewhat a coming-of-age story and still funny1. All of the plots work well together and it juggles between tones seamlessly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Owl House</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/owl-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/owl-house/</guid>
      <description>What is it about?   The Owl House is about a young girl living her dream of moving to a world of witches.
The target public is mostly younger children (up to high school).
Why do I like it?   This is basically a cartoon version of Harry Potter with great representation (strong women, people of color / diverse ethnicities and wholesome LGBTQ+ relationships) and a strong &amp;ldquo;be your own quircky self&amp;rdquo; message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nachos</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/nachos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/nachos/</guid>
      <description>Nachos are a great group meal to eat with friends. This particular version comes with a satisfying bean base to make it a proper meal that can be scooped with tortilla chips as you go.
Ingredients (two servings):     half of an onion (I like a red onion for decorative purposes)
  olive oil
  soy sauce
  one can of beans (I like chili beans)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pizza dough</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/pizza/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/pizza/</guid>
      <description>Pizza is a classic for a reason. A lot of recipes call for preparing the dough on a previous day or a special oven, this recipe steers away from those best practices to give you something delicious within two hours.
Ingredients (one pizza):    250 grams of flour 6 grams of salt 4 grams of dry yeast (about half a packet) 175 grams of warm water1 15 grams of olive oil (enough to coat the pan)  Preparation:   Dough     mix the flour, salt and yeast in a big bowl</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dalgona Coffee</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/dalgona_coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/dalgona_coffee/</guid>
      <description>This drink is quick and easy to make, tastes like an éclair au café, and looks very pretty. It is perfect to share with a guest who likes coffee.
Ingredients (1 glass):    two teaspoons of instant coffee1 two teaspoons of sugar two teaspoons of boiling water one glass of very cold whole2 milk3  Preparation:    mix the instant coffee, sugar, and boiling water in a bowl whip until the color lightens and the texture becomes fluffier4 pour the coffee foam5 on top of a glass of very cold milk to serve add a straw, let guests mix, and start drinking  Credits:   This recipe was inspired by seeing James Hoffman discuss the drink on his youtube channel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaghetti Epinardo E Olio</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/weekday_meal/pasta_spinash/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/weekday_meal/pasta_spinash/</guid>
      <description>This dish is relatively easy to cook while bringing some very strong flavors and colors to the table. I highly recommend it if you want a weeknight meal that feels slightly fancier than it should be.
Ingredients (for two portions):    160 grams of spaghetti1 (80 grams per person) some olive oil a generous amount of pepper some salt a large bowl packed full of fresh baby spinach the equivalent of one and a half large cloves of garlic2 about 30 grams of butter some grated parmesan3  Preparation:   Mise en place    rince the spinach and dice them very finely crush the garlic dice the butter  Pasta    fill a pan with water and bring it to a boil add a generous amount of salt to your pasta water4 add the pasta when the water starts boiling and keep cooking for about 10 minutes (until your pasta is cooked)  Spinach    put the olive oil in a wok add a very generous amount of pepper and cook on high heat until the pepper becomes fragrant5 add the finely diced spinach (roughly when you add the pasta to its water) and a big pinch of salt6 let simmer on medium to low heat until the pasta is ready  Assembly    once the pasta is cooked, add a splash of pasta water to the wok, this will help with the consistency of the sauce strain the pasta and add them to the wok (it is fine if there is some pasta water left with the pasta, we added pasta water to the wok anyway) add the crushed garlic and diced butter start mixing on high heat once it is fairly well mixed, sprinkle grated parmesan as you would cover a similar amount of pasta in a plate7 mix constantly on high heat until you reach the desired consistency (I recommend aiming for slightly more liquid than your sweet spot, the sauce will thicken further once served) and all the cheese has dissolved into the sauce salt to taste  Credits:   While this dish&amp;rsquo;s name is the combination of Spaghetti Aglio E Olio and the Italian word for spinach, it is inspired by wanting to do a pasta dish with spinach and having seen this Cacio E Pepe recipe recently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beeny&#39;s Brownies</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/brownies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/brownies/</guid>
      <description>This is a very straightforward chocolate brownies recipe. You can pimp it up with some coffee powder1, a few salt flakes on top, any kind of nuts, chocolate chunks, etc. The world is your chocolate-flavored oyster!
Ingredients (8 slices):    100 grams of flour 37 grams of cocoa powder 125 grams of sugar 2 eggs 1 teaspoon of vanilla extract (optional) 100 grams of salted butter  Preparation:    mix the flour and cocoa in a bowl add the sugar and mix beat the eggs and add add the vanilla extract melt the butter, add it and mix pour in a pan lined with parchment paper  Cooking:    cook 25 to 30 minutes in a 340F (170C) oven let cool in the pan cut into slices before serving (they might be best served the next day for peak flavor and texture)  Credits:   This is my take on Sarah Beeny&amp;rsquo;s chocolate brownies recipe (with which she beat Gordon Ramsay on British television).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eldritch Academia (annotated)</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/fiction/eldritch_academia_anotated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/fiction/eldritch_academia_anotated/</guid>
      <description>This is the annotated edition of Eldritch Academia1. I expect it to be of very limited interest to others (the short story is probably not worth an annotated edition) but, it is a fun way to record some of the thoughts and references I put in the text and an exercise in overloading a page with sidenotes.
My overall feeling about the story is that it lacks conflict, probably because the narrator is not resisting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegan fruity breakfast</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/breakfast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/breakfast/</guid>
      <description>This breakfast manages to both be delicious and give you the feeling that you are eating healthy. And it feels good. I get the needed ingredients about once a month to eat it for a few days (I feel that eating it every day would reduce my enjoyment).
Ingredients (1 bowl):    two tablespoons of granola1 two tablespoons of unsweetened coconut milk yogurt2 two tablespoons of blueberries a few strawberries3  Preparation:    put the granola in a bowl add the yogurt wash and add the blueberries wash, dice and add the stawberries  Credits:   You can find similar recipes on Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nestor&#39;s guide to writing</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/writing/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Writing is easy. Just put a sheet of paper in the typewriter and start bleeding.&amp;rdquo; — Walter Wellesley &amp;ldquo;Red&amp;rdquo; Smith
 I am the intended reader of this guide. If the tone seems harsh or the advice opinionated, it is because I can sometimes be harsh with myself and because I know that those techniques work for me. I have written non-fiction professionally in various fields but never published any fiction so take the following with the appropriate amount of salt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegetarian pasta carbonara</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/weekday_meal/pasta_carbonara/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/weekday_meal/pasta_carbonara/</guid>
      <description>This dish is slightly fancier than my usual weekday dish but it is good enough to have spoiled a lot of restaurant Carbonara pasta for me while being relatively fast and easy to cook. Plus, it is vegetarian!
Ingredients (for two portions):    160 grams of pasta (80 grams per person, you could go up to 100 grams), I like tagliatelle but, most pasta types would be fine1 half of a thick zucchini2 some olive oil some soy sauce two egg yolks3 some milk (about the same volume as the egg yolk) a lot of parmesan (at least the same volume as the egg yolk) a lot of black pepper (get a pepper grinder, you will get a much-improved taste) two big cloves of garlic4  Preparation:   Pasta    fill a pan with water and bring it to a boil you can optionally add a generous amount of salt to your pasta water, the pasta will taste better but, you do not need it here add the pasta when the water starts boiling and keep cooking for about 10 minutes (until your pasta is cooked)  Zucchini    peel your zucchini cut it into thin slices long as about a third of a bacon strip put in a wok with a splash of olive oil add a splash of soy sauce let cook until the pasta is ready  Sauce    put the egg yolks in a bowl add the milk add the parmesan add black pepper (you can, optionally, also add some chili flakes here) add the crushed garlic mix thoroughly and set aside  Assembly    once the pasta is cooked, add a splash of pasta water to the wok, this will help with the sauce consistency (you can be approximate with the quantity, too little and your sauce will miss a bit of thickness, too much and you will have to reduce longer: either way the result will be fine and you can do better next time) you can do it directly from the pasta pan, no need for an intermediate container (that would give you additional opportunities to burn yourself) strain the pasta and add them to the wok (it is okay if there is some pasta water left with the pasta, we have pasta water in the wok anyway) set the heat to low add the sauce and mix constantly (to avoid having the egg yolk curl) until you reach the desired consistency (I recommend aiming for slightly more liquid than your sweet spot, the sauce will thicken further once served) serve on a plate5  Credits:   This is my take on Adam Raguseas&amp;rsquo;s carbonara pasta with zucchini.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Zen story</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/zen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/zen/</guid>
      <description>One day a famous government officer met a highly respected elderly master. Being conceited, he wanted to prove that he was the superior person.
As their conversation drew on, he asked the master, &amp;ldquo;Old monk, do you know what I think of you and the things you said?&amp;rdquo;
The master replied, &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t care what you think of me. You are entitled to have your own opinion.&amp;rdquo;
The officer snorted, &amp;ldquo;Well, I will tell you what I think anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two-ingredient chocolate mousse</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/chocolate_mousse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/chocolate_mousse/</guid>
      <description>This is the perfect recipe to do when you have leftover egg whites. It is delicious and uses barely any ingredients (I always keep the proper chocolate in my pantry to do this recipe when I have egg whites). Its only downside is that, once you have prepared everything, you need to wait.
Ingredients (1 portion):    1 egg whites1 35 grams of chocolate2  Preparation:    beat your egg whites into a nice firm foam melt the chocolate (it is okay to leave some chunks in the melted chocolate, they will add heterogeneity to the result) optionally, if you have egg yolks, add them to the melted chocolate and mix until homogeneous (be careful not to cook them in the hot chocolate) fold (or beat) the melted chocolate into the egg whites pour into one glass, mug, or bowl per portion store in the fridge for at least 5 hours (you can wait a full night if you want to be sure) eat cold (you can shave some chocolate on top if you want to make it look fancy)  Credits:   The proportions are inspired by this Mousse au chocolat facile recipe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Figures of speech</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/figures_of_speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/figures_of_speech/</guid>
      <description>Figures of speech (which you can find here) is a project done illuminations media for the Almeida Theater in which great actors read great speeches and it is absolutely fantastic.
It includes, amongst others, Ian McKellen reading Harvey Milk&amp;rsquo;s Hope Speech, Derek Jacobi reading Socrates&amp;rsquo; I Go To Die, and Noma Dumezweni reading Margaret Sanger&amp;rsquo;s The Morality of Birth Control.
The actors are great, the speeches have stood the test of time and it is a great vessel to get familiar with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First they came ...</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/first_they_came/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/first_they_came/</guid>
      <description>First they came for the Communists
And I did not speak out
Because I was not a Communist
Then they came for the Socialists
And I did not speak out
Because I was not a Socialist
Then they came for the trade unionists
And I did not speak out
Because I was not a trade unionist
Then they came for the Jews
And I did not speak out
Because I was not a Jew</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter from a Birmingham Jail</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/birmingham_jail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/birmingham_jail/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I have almost reached the regrettable conclusion that the Negro&amp;rsquo;s great stumbling block in his stride toward freedom is not the White Citizen&amp;rsquo;s Counciler or the Ku Klux Klanner, but the white moderate, who is more devoted to &amp;ldquo;order&amp;rdquo; than to justice; who prefers a negative peace which is the absence of tension to a positive peace which is the presence of justice.&amp;rdquo; — Martin Luther King Jr., Letter from a Birmingham Jail</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consumers and producers</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/concepts/consumers_producers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/concepts/consumers_producers/</guid>
      <description>Most activities can be categorized as either consumer or producer.
A consumer activity is an activity during which you consume existing content such as watching a video, reading a book, or browsing the Internet. Depending on the content you consumed, it can be nourishing or leave you with a feeling of emptiness.
A producer activity is an activity during which you produce new content for others to consume such as drawing, writing, cooking, or programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rice Zucchini à la Alfredo</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/weekday_meal/rice_zucchini/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/weekday_meal/rice_zucchini/</guid>
      <description>This dish is all about the pleasure of eating rice with Parmesan and butter, with some zucchini tossed in for good measure. It is quick to do and delicious, try it on a weekday.
Ingredients (one person):    Half a zucchini, 60 grams of rice, a lot of salted butter1, as much Parmesan as butter, optionally, some smoked chilly flakes for added flavor complexity.  Preparation:    Peel the Zucchini and dice it, bring water to a boil, add the rice and zucchini to the water and cook for ten minutes2, put the butter on the plate, add the (optional) chilly flakes, once the rice and zucchini are cooked, strain and pour on the butter add the Parmesan and mix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japanese Can Opener</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/objects/can_opener/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/objects/can_opener/</guid>
      <description>The cheapest kind of can opener you can buy in France is a single piece of metal with a sharp edge, it is also the most practical kind of can opener. In the US it is called a Japanese can opener and it is apparently very fancy.
Those things are a marvel of design, they have no moving parts (it is literally a single piece of metal) making them dead easy to use and clean, very durable (they will outlive you, by a long shot), space-efficient (nice if, for whatever reason, you want to travel with your can opener) and dirt cheap (about $9 on Amazon for a fancier model).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Name of the Rose</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/name-of-the-rose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/name-of-the-rose/</guid>
      <description>Note: There will be spoilers.
I just re(re-re)-watched the Name of the Rose and I still absolutely love it.
The main character, William of Baskerville, is basically a Sherlock Holmes clone (he even says &amp;ldquo;Elementary!&amp;rdquo; to his apprentice a couple of times) except that he is a Franciscan monk living during the middle-ages and investigating a murder in an abbey that is busy with a debate on whether the church should be poor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Shopping trolley bag</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/objects/cabas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/objects/cabas/</guid>
      <description>If you do your groceries on foot, a shopping trolley bag (with wheels) is a game-changer.
The main hurdle when going grocery shopping on foot is dealing with the weight of the produces on the way back. However, I observed a large number of old people doing their groceries on foot as if it were nothing (while the way back was clearly strenuous to my weak arms).
Their superpower? The power of the wheel!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pasta bell pepper</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/weekday_meal/pasta_bellpepper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/weekday_meal/pasta_bellpepper/</guid>
      <description>This dish is very fast to cook, brings you the carbs you need, some greens (technically reds), and has a distinct enough flavor to fight monotony in your eating habits.
Ingredients (for two portions):    160 grams of pasta (80 grams per person, you could go up to 100 grams), I like fusilli for this dish but most pasta types would be fine 1 bell pepper (all colors are fine, but I have a slight preference for red as it imparts some color to the pasta) some salted soy sauce (the salt will be useful) some olive oil (we will cook it so no need for high-quality stuff) some herbes de Provence (you could use another dry herbs mix but do use dry herbs, they make the flavor of the dish) some cayenne pepper (optional)  Preparation:   Pasta    fill a pan with water and bring it to a boil (big bubbles, small bubbles do not count as boiling, you will be delighted to discover that I met people for which this is not obvious) add the pasta when the water starts boiling and keep cooking for about 10 minutes (until your pasta is cooked)  Sauce    once the pasta is in the water, put the diced bell pepper in a wok (or similar large pan) on low heat add a generous splash of olive oil add a generous splash of soy sauce (this will bring you the salt in the dish plus a lot of the flavor) add a very generous sprinkle of herbs (you can hardly overdo it here) optionally, add a sprinkle of cayenne pepper (you want enough for people to realize the dish has some hotness but no more, it is not a hot dish) cook on low heat  Assembly    once the pasta is cooked, add a splash of pasta water to the wok, this will help with the sauce consistency (you can be approximate with the quantity, too little and your sauce will miss a bit of thickness, too much and you will have to reduce longer: either way the result will be fine and you can do better next time) you can do it directly from the pasta pan, no need for an intermediate container (that would give you additional opportunities to burn yourself) strain the pasta and add them to the wok (it is okay if there is some pasta water left with the pasta, we have pasta water in the wok anyway) raise to medium heat and keep mixing until you get the sauce consistency you want (the mixing time will depend on the amount of water you put, you should be done in two minutes) serve on a plate, feel free to add butter and shredded Parmesan to pimp the result slightly  Credits:   Using the pasta water comes from French guy cooking&amp;rsquo;s Alex and is a game-changer for pasta sauces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philips Sonicare toothbrush</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/objects/toothbrush/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/objects/toothbrush/</guid>
      <description>The Philips Sonicare toothbrush is the best electronic toothbrush I ever used. By a significant margin. It is not only good at cleaning your teeth but also one of those rare objects that are well designed.
Regarding the quality of the cleaning (arguably the most important criteria), I could feel a sensible reduction in plaque when I went from a traditional toothbrush to an electric toothbrush, but this was one more step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Alchemaster&#39;s Apprentice</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/alchemasters_apprentice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/alchemasters_apprentice/</guid>
      <description>I just finished reading The Alchemaster&amp;rsquo;s Apprentice by Walter Moers.
Superficially, the book is about a young crat1 dying of hunger in the streets until he makes a Faustian bargain with an alchemaster: for a month he will be fed the best food, taught alchemy, and enjoy the best life a crat might want then, at the full moon, he will be killed and rendered for his fat. The book talks about friendship and love from a wide variety of angles, however, none of this is the point of the book, it is barely the seasoning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Birthday of the World and Other Stories</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/birthday_of_the_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/birthday_of_the_world/</guid>
      <description>I finished The Birthday of the World and Other Stories by Ursula K. Le Guin a few months ago. I know of Ursula Le Guin by reputation1, but it is the first of her book that I read, and&amp;hellip; it was a slap in the face.
The book is a collection of short stories in her Ekumen universe making them technically science fiction. However, while science-fiction usually deals with things and technologies, these stories are all about people and feelings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crêpes</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/crepes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/crepes/</guid>
      <description>Crêpes are the perfect social dish. You can make them together then everyone put the topping of their choice on top, sweet or savory1.
Ingredients (4 people):    250 grams flour 25 grams of sugar 4 eggs 500 ml milk 50 grams of salted butter (or 40 grams of olive oil and a pinch of salt, the taste is slightly different but it works)  Preparation:    put the flour in a mixing bowl add the sugar add the eggs and mix add the milk progressively while mixing add the melted butter (making sure it is not hot enough to cook the eggs prematurely) and mix  Cooking:    slightly oil (or butter) the pan put a ladle worth of crêpe batter and spread it to make it round once the bottom is cooked (the sides should start to get browned), use a spatula and flip it (it should cook for about a minute) repeat as many times as needed  Credits:   This recipe is my version of Crêpes : la meilleure recette rapide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The easy path</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/concepts/easy_path/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/concepts/easy_path/</guid>
      <description>The opposite of wanting something to be perfect is following the easy path: knowing that some things could be done to make your project objectively better but keeping the current version because it is &amp;ldquo;good enough&amp;rdquo;.
This, as long as the modification would be within the scope and allotted time1, is a form of laziness. However, it is insidious. All parts of a project have to be considered &amp;ldquo;good enough&amp;rdquo; before you let go of them to tackle the next step, it is very easy to not realize that your motivation shifted from an objective look at the quality of your work toward avoiding additional work to the detriment of the result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Melting butter</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/technique/melting_butter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/technique/melting_butter/</guid>
      <description>This should be obvious but&amp;hellip;
Ingredients:    the butter you want to melt  Technique:    put the butter in a small bowl microwave until you hear some bubbling sound (30 seconds is usually enough)  Credits:   The technique seems obvious, I am not aware of any particular credits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Melting chocolate</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/technique/melting_chocolate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/technique/melting_chocolate/</guid>
      <description>The classical technique to melt chocolate is to use a double broiler (also called bain Marie). However, I am deeply convinced that using a microwave is significantly easier and faster.
Ingredients:    chocolate to melt a tablespoon of water (you need some water to prevent dry burning but too much will deteriorate the result) if the recipe calls for melted butter, adding cream or milk, you can replace the water with one of those in the quantities required by the recipe  Technique:    put the chocolate in a small bowl add the liquid or milk produce microwave until the chocolate is softened (around one minute depending on the strength of your microwave) mix the result to finish melting the chocolate  Credits:   I am not aware of any particular credit for this technique, I saw it used by a variety of sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>US-style pie crust</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/pies/us_pie_crust/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/pies/us_pie_crust/</guid>
      <description>This pie dough is easy to make and tastes pretty much perfect for a US-style pie (with crust below and above the pie). Plus, the leftover dough can be stored in the fridge for later use.
Ingredients (for one pie):    300 grams of flour 20 grams of sugar (optional) 227 grams of salted butter (get it out of the fridge as soon as you start to raise its temperature and make your job easier) 53 grams of water 8 grams of apple cider vinegar (needs testing to see how impactful it is)  Preparation:    put the flour in a large bowl add the sugar add the butter diced or sliced into thin slices (to simplify the mixing) with one hand mix the dough until you get a crumbly/flaky consistency add half of the water plus the vinegar and mix add the leftover water and mix into a ball cut the ball in two and refrigerate for 30 minutes while you prepare the fillings  Cooking:    You might want to prebake the bottom of our pie (for a European-style pie) or let your pie cook for a long time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A magician is a...</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/magician_is_actor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/magician_is_actor/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;A magician is an actor playing the part of a magician.&amp;rdquo; — Jean Eugène Robert-Houdin.
 The quote   This essay is dedicated to magicians. Others might find it intriguing, but it will probably be irrelevant to them.
If you ask a magician to give you one famous quote about their object of study, the vast majority of them will tell you that Jean Eugène Robert-Houdin once said &amp;ldquo;A magician is an actor playing the part of a magician.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nestor&#39;s guide to creating a blog</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/blogging/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: This guide is mostly about me keeping a trace of the process I followed to create this blog. I really wanted to use GitHub for the hosting and that leads to a lot of additional complexity that you should avoid if you are not used to writing code.
Hosting   I used GitHub pages to host my blog, they are free but only support static websites and, by default, force you to use their domain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nestor&#39;s guide to doing a large project</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/hard_things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/hard_things/</guid>
      <description>Tackling a large project (this applies to anything including a book, a piece of software, or a movie for example) can be daunting. Suddenly it is not a sprint to the end of a task but, rather, an endurance race that requires regularly renewed dedication: something school and early life do not prepare you for.
These are my solutions to tackle large projects (you will find some overlap with my guide to doing the things you love well and my guide to writing).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pasta ratatouille</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/weekday_meal/pasta_ratatouille/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/weekday_meal/pasta_ratatouille/</guid>
      <description>This dish is a worker: it is fast and easy to cook while being delicious and rich in vegetables and flavors.
I have been cooking variations of this dish for as long as I have been cooking for myself, starting when I had my first apartment. It has evolved a lot since its inception but it is still one of my favorite way to eat pasta.
Ingredients (for two portions):    160 grams of pasta (80 grams per person, you could go up to 100 grams), I like fusilli for this dish but most pasta types would be fine half a jar of organic1 ratatouille (this is where I lose my US readers, you simply cannot find this stuff in the US: you might replace it with a jar of tomato sauce that contains a generous amount of eggplants and assorted vegetables) some salted soy sauce (the salt will be useful) some olive oil (we will cook it so no need for high-quality stuff) some salt (optional) some cayenne pepper (optional)  Preparation:   Pasta    fill a pan with water and bring it to a boil (big bubbles, small bubbles do not count as boiling, you will be delighted to discover that I met people for which this is not obvious) you can optionally add a generous amount of salt to your pasta water, the pasta will taste better but, you do not need it here add the pasta when the water starts boiling and keep cooking for about 10 minutes (until your pasta is cooked)  Sauce    once the pasta is in the water, put the ratatouille in a wok (or similar large pan) on low heat add a generous splash of olive oil add a generous splash of soy sauce (this will bring you the salt in the dish plus a lot of the flavor) optionally, add a sprinkle of cayenne pepper (you want enough for people to realize the dish has some hotness but no more, it is not a hot dish) cook on low heat  Assembly    once the pasta is cooked, add a splash of pasta water to the wok, this will help with the sauce consistency (you can be approximate with the quantity, too little and your sauce will miss a bit of thickness, too much and you will have to reduce longer: either way the result will be fine and you can do better next time) you can do it directly from the pasta pan, no need for an intermediate container (that would give you additional opportunities to burn yourself) strain the pasta and add them to the wok (it is okay if there is some pasta water left with the pasta, we have pasta water in the wok anyway) raise to medium heat and keep mixing until you get the sauce consistency you want (the mixing time will depend on the amount of water you put, you should be done in two minutes) serve on a plate, feel free to add butter and shredded Parmesan to pimp the result slightly  Credits:   I used soy sauce and a jar of ratatouille because my father put them in my very first grocery bag as an independent student.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avocado toast</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/sandwich/avocado_toast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/sandwich/avocado_toast/</guid>
      <description>Avocado toast is the most shamefully Californian dish. This version has a nice spicy punch to it.
Ingredients (one toast):    one slice of bread (I recommend multigrain bread, it has more depth of flavor once toasted) some mayonnaise one avocado coarse salt pepper Sriracha sauce (as this is a big part of the final flavor, do not accept substitutes to the original sauce)  Preparation:    toast the bread put a thin layer of mayonnaise on the bread put a layer of avocado on the bread (you can spread it or slice it for a better-looking result) add a zigzag of Sriracha sauce add a generous amount of salt and pepper  Credits:   This recipe is taken straight from You suck at cooking&amp;rsquo;s great Youtube Channel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacon Tomato Melt</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/sandwich/bacon_tomato_melt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/sandwich/bacon_tomato_melt/</guid>
      <description>This is the pinnacle of self-indulging food. It is fast to prepare and very calorie-rich but the bacon, melted cheese, and toasted bread mesh perfectly and hit all the right spots.
Ingredients (one toast):    one or two slices of bacon1 one slice of bread (I recommend multigrain bread, it has more depth of flavor once toasted) some mayonnaise half a tomato coarse salt (optional) shredded cheese  Preparation:    cook the bacon until crisp2 toast the bread spread a thin layer of mayonnaise on the bread (it is there for some flavor notes but also to avoid having the tomato juice make the bread soggy) covers the bread with a one-slice thick layer of tomato sprinkle some salt add a layer of crispy bacon add a pile of shredded cheese at the very least as thick as the rest of the sandwich on top toast until the cheese is melted to your preference serve warm  Credits:   This recipe is taken straight from You suck at cooking&amp;rsquo;s great Youtube Channel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clafoutis</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/clafoutis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/clafoutis/</guid>
      <description>Clafoutis was my favorite kind of cake when I was a kid. My mother used to make plum ones while fruits were in season and I famously ate a full cake that just got out of the oven while she was away from the kitchen. They are also a great way to turn fruits into a cake that looks very pretty while being extremely easy to make.
Ingredients:    about 500grams (you want to cover your pan with a nice layer) of a mix of cherries and apricots (stones fruits such as cherries, plums apricots, and peaches feel like a better match but it works with pretty much anything including bananas and rhubarb, I like a mix of cherries and apricots to vary colors and flavors) 4 eggs 100 grams of flour 60 grams of salted butter (you could use 45 grams of olive oil and some salt, the taste and texture would slightly differ but that still makes for a good cake) 60 grams of sugar (you could go up to 100 grams according to taste) 25cl of milk some vanilla extract (optional)  Preparation:   The pan    put a generous amount of butter on the sides of your cake pan (you want a wider rather than tall pan) cut your fruits (stones fruits can be cut into two or four, don&amp;rsquo;t forget to remove the stone, you can leave the skin on) and spread them in the cake pan  The batter    mix the eggs with the sugar until smooth add the (optional) vanilla extract add the flour while mixing add the milk while mixing melt the butter in a microwave (or oven but 30 seconds in a microwave is perfect) then add (if the butter is warm, mix it fast enough to not cook your egg) pour the batter into your cake pan (the batter will be more golden and liquid than usual cake batter, it is perfectly normal)  Cooking:    cook 30 to 45 minutes at 350F (180C), you can stop once the top is golden and the batter firm serve at room temperature (it is also great cold after a few hours in the fridge) you can (optionally) dust the top with powdered white sugar just before serving if you are serving cold (this is purely esthetic)  Credits:   This clafoutis batter is pretty classic and can be found all over the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tarte au Maroille</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/tarte_maroille/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/tarte_maroille/</guid>
      <description>This cheese pie recipe is a family secret. It was passed down from my grandmother to my mother to me (my sister did not care for cooking at the time). I am writing it so that it can be saved for future generations to enjoy (if you want to keep a secret, put it in writing).
Ingredients (two pies):   Dought    1 kg of white flour 5 egg yolks 1 cube of fresh yeast1 a few spoonfuls of sugar (white is fine, brown is better, cassonade/vergeoise is traditional) 125 grams of salted butter (butter is good, salted is better)  Toping    one egg, one egg&amp;rsquo;s worth of milk, some grated nutmeg (optional) one big, full, Maroille2  Preparation:   Dough    Put the sugar and the yeast in a small bowl of warmish water3, mix once and let rest until it gets foamy put most of the flour in a large mixing bowl (set a little aside to shape the dough later) add the egg yolks and the yeast with its water mix until combined, do not over-mix (the resulting dough will be very sticky) cover with a towel and let rise for one hour (warmish places such as a window in the sun are best)  Assembling the pie    spread the dough on top of your pizza pans (you want flat pizza type of pans rather than pie pans), you can use the leftover flour to help shape the dough (do not use a rolling pin, this is a finger-stretching affair) add slices of Maroile on your dough (you want to cover it, the more the merrier) brush with a mix done with one egg and a little bit of milk (you can brush with your fingers) add a little bit of grounded nutmeg  Cooking:    Cook at 180C (350F) for 30 to 45 minutes (the crust should be hardened and the cheese pretty melted).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crumble</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/crumble/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/crumble/</guid>
      <description>Crumbles are pretty much impossible to miss and a great way to turn fruits (most fruits are suitable; apples, pears, and peaches are classic) and butter into a good cake. This one is pimped with chocolate chips, cinnamon, vanilla extract, and lemon juice. They are all worth it but, you can cut all of them if you want to keep things simple (or do not have them on hand).
Ingredients (for 4 portions):    100g of flour (you can easily turn the grams into cups and half cups: it is the respective proportions that matter) 100g of salted butter (you can also use unsalted butter and had some salt, the result is identical, but do not omit the salt) 50g of sugar 2 large pears some good cooking chocolate (no need for a sweet one, 70% cacao does a good job, also I like to get a chocolate bar and cut it into smallish chips, you get better quality chocolate and bigger chips) some cinnamon some vanilla extract some lemon juice  Preparation:   bottom layer    peel the pears, dice them, and put them on the bottom of your baking dish (I use a Pyrex square one), you want enough pears to garnish the bottom of the dish with about one centimeter of pears add some lemon juice on top, not much just a spoonful so that the pears are finely coated cut your chocolate into chips and sprinkle them on top of the layer of pears (no need for much, it is not a chocolate cake!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KrautBurger</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/sandwich/krautburger/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/sandwich/krautburger/</guid>
      <description>The Krautburger is my favorite homemade burger of the moment. It is vegetarian (but not vegan due to the presence of mayonnaise and, harder to replace, cheese) and light while hitting all the flavors I want due to the melted cheese and toasted bun combined with the surprising freshness of the thick tomato slice hidden inside the burger.
Ingredients (one burger):    a burger bun (bread rather than brioche if possible) some mayonnaise one tomato enough sauerkraut to make a small patty out of it (pick one that is not too flavorful and whose flavor you like, otherwise you might be disappointed by this burger&amp;hellip;) 2 slices of cheese (you want a cheese that does not melt instantly, so no American cheese, I like pepper jack because of the added flavor from the chili flakes, I would probably sprinkle some chilly flakes on my sauerkraut if all I had was Gruyère)  Preparation:    toast the lower bun (this step is optional but will reduce sogginess) spread a layer of mayonnaise on each half-bun (the goal here is not to act on the taste but to stop water from going through and into the bun) put thick tomato slices on the bottom bun until it is fully covered (I like my slices about one centimeter thick) add one slice of cheese put some sauerkraut on top and shape it like a small pattie add the second slice of cheese add the final bun  Cooking:    toast in the oven until the cheese is nicely melted and the top bun lightly toasted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Batman</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/the-batman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/the-batman/</guid>
      <description>I saw the Batman and&amp;hellip; meh.
I love the acting of the Riddler in his unmasked sections (he looks like an accountant and that is great).
Some solid action scenes, but none of the set pieces really strikes me.
The gadgets are really nice (lenses, parachute, etc.) but the scenario leaves me cold. The Riddler and the plot are clearly inspired by Seven while Batman&amp;rsquo;s moral (and notebook) are clearly taken from Watchmen&amp;rsquo;s Rorschach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nightmare alley</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/nightmare-alley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/nightmare-alley/</guid>
      <description>I watched Guillermo Del Toro&amp;rsquo;s Nightmare Alley yesterday and&amp;hellip; It was ok.
I might have been let down a little because I love both Guillermo Del Toro and the source material (by the way, you can find both the original black&amp;amp;white movie and the book for free, legally, on the internet archive) so I had a lot of expectations.
The actors are solid, the movie has a very nice forties ambiance (I love the psychologist&amp;rsquo;s office design) and some scenes are wonderful (the one scene dealing with the consequence of his actions&amp;hellip; and the final scene which was already one of the strong points from the original story) but I felt that the scenario was lacking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nestor&#39;s guide to dating apps</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/dating/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/dating/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: This guide is targeted at heterosexual men (with a focus on people looking for a relationship) and was written at the end of 2021 for a friend, the content might not apply to you. Also, a lot of the following might seem obvious to you but, as what is obvious to some isn’t to others, I am putting a maximum of information here in the hope that you might find things that you do not already know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nestor&#39;s guide to doing the things you love well</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/heuristics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/heuristics/</guid>
      <description>Here are some heuristics I use in life and work:
 Play to your strengths; being balanced sounds nice but ends up being really unproductive/unpleasant. Spend time on the things you like, as time and practice pile up you will end up skilled in those domains. Go for the things that are of interest to you, not for the trendy ones. Time spent automating tasks is usually time well spent. Taking a break to gather knowledge on something vaguely connected to the thing you are doing is never time lost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eldritch Academia</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/fiction/eldritch_academia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/fiction/eldritch_academia/</guid>
      <description>Object: Some News   Hey Sonia,
How are you doing?
To answer your question (sorry for the late email, moving did not leave me much time to write), the math department is paying me to study KTu-L spaces.
You might have seen some references to them popping up in the past year, they have gained a lot of visibility as some mathematicians (mostly Providence’s research team which I will be joining this week) claim that they can be used to solve a number of interesting conjectures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nestor&#39;s guide to having ideas</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/ideas/</guid>
      <description>No One Is Born Uncreative   Some people have told me that they are not creative. It usually stems from them thinking that creativity is an innate gift: some people are born with a brain that overflows with ideas at regular intervals, while others stay dry for most of their life.
In practice, I have found creativity to be a muscle. The more you try to use it, the easier it gets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consulting mentalist</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/mentalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/mentalism/</guid>
      <description>I am a consulting mentalist. Among other things, I have a book published for that public, give talks at specialized conventions, and I designed stage shows that are now playing in various1 countries.
What is Mentalism?   Mentalism is an ensemble of techniques (including mnemonics, hypnosis, magic tricks, a trained intuition, and knowledge of statistically likely phenomena) used to produce incredible phenomena (usually psychic phenomena or a mastery of the human mind) in an entertainment setting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research I did</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/research/</guid>
      <description>I am a researcher with specialties in numerical accuracy, artificial intelligence, data analysis, and high-performance computing.
Papers   You can find most of my publications on Researchgate:
High-level GPU code: a case study examining JAX and OpenMP. (high-performance computing)   This paper (published as part of the proceedings of Supercomputing 2023) contrasts and compares the use of both JAX and OpenMP target offload to port a large cosmology code to GPU.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software I wrote</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/software/</guid>
      <description>I am an engineer with a specialty in applied mathematics and computer science.
You can find most of the software I developed on Github and Gitlab. Here is a list of some noticeable libraries (focusing on projects where I am the lead developer):
Divinatory GPTs (Prompt)   This is a collection of scripts and prompts I used to make custom GPTs around the theme of divination (and, in particular, tools to help people become better tarot readers).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
