<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Avocado Bread</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/avocado_bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/avocado_bread/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is simple, tastes good, has an interesting texture and, more importantly, looks extremely weird making it a fantastic party dessert.
Ingredients (8 slices):    2 (very ripe) avocados 150 grams of sugar 3 eggs 240 grams of flour 6 grams (one and a half) teaspoon of baking powder  Preparation:    dice the inside of the avocados and put it in a large bowl cream the avocados and sugar together beat the eggs into the mix add the flour and baking powder fold together  Cooking:    cook 45 to 50 minutes in a 350F (180C) oven  Credits:   The recipe comes from Dylan Hollis&amp;rsquo;s excelent Youtube channel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tuesday Night Club: A Miss Marple Short Story</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/tuesday_night_club/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/tuesday_night_club/</guid>
      <description>“As an artist I have knocked about among all sorts and conditions of people. I know life as darling Miss Marple here cannot possibly know it.”
 I recently finished reading Agatha Christie&amp;rsquo;s The Tuesday Night Club and it is surprisingly sharp.
A group of friends (a writer, an artist, a clergyman, a lawyer and a police commissioner) is having a late-night discussion, hosted by the old aunt of one of the members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Red Bean Paste Cookie</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/red_bean_paste_cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/red_bean_paste_cookies/</guid>
      <description>Those cookies are very worth doing. They focus the flavor on the red bean paste while looking fancier than they are difficult to cook (which is always a good thing).
Ingredients (2 person):    1 egg 50 grams of salted butter 100 grams of flour 25 grams of icing sugar1 1 teaspoon vanilla extract 100 grams of red bean paste2 optional: 1 additional egg for brushing3 optional: sesame seeds  Preparation:   Cookie dough    whisk the egg in a bowl add the softened4 butter and mix until homogeneous add the flour, icing sugar and vanilla extract mix until smooth5 cover and refrigerate for one hour  Assembly    get the dough on a floured6 surface using a rolling pin, shape the dough into a long rectangle shape the red bean paste into a thick bar and place it in the middle of the rectangle carefully fold the two sides of the rectangle over the bar and flip it to put the seam down cut the resulting bar of dough into squarish cookies  Decoration    whisk the additional egg and brush the cookies with it7 sprinkle some sesame seeds on the cookies  Baking    bake 20 to 25 minutes at 360F (180C) let cool down a little before eating  Credits:   This recipe is mostly my notes on China Sichian Food&amp;rsquo;s Red Bean Paste Cookie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rediscovering ideas</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/rediscovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/rediscovery/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Back in my religious days if you independently rediscovered an idea already uncovered by some rabbi 400 years ago it was a big deal and great honor, the whole class would celebrate you. The bigger the rabbi the greater the honor.&amp;rdquo; — @hormeze
 I think that this is a very healthy approach toward the rediscovery of ideas. Honoring both the lineage of knowledge and the ability to reach a particular conclusion instead of lamenting the fact that we do not get to reap the benefits of being the first to climb a particular hill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate decadence flourless cake</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/flourless-chocolate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/flourless-chocolate/</guid>
      <description>This cake feels light yet very buttery, delicious and fully decadent.
Ingredients:    3 eggs 90 grams of white sugar 30 grams of plain yogurt 5 grams (about 2 teaspoons) of cornstarch 1 teaspoon of vanilla extract 1 teaspoon of grounded instant coffee 120 grams of salted butter 170 grams of 64% cacao chocolate one large pear  Preparation:   Eggs    separate the white and yolks1 of the eggs beat the egg whites in a large bowl  Batter    in a large bowl, mix the sugar, yogurt, vanilla, coffee powder, cornstarch melt the butter and chocolate in the microwave then add to the mixture dice the pear and add it to the mix fold in the egg whites2 pour in a pan lined with parchment paper  Cooking:    cook 50 to 60 minutes in a 275F (135C) oven (it will still be fudgy once done) let cool in the pan before storing in the fridge for one to two hours before serving  Credits:   This is my take on Brian Lagerstrom&amp;rsquo;s Super Easy Flourless Chocolate Cake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kougelhopf</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/kougelhopf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/kougelhopf/</guid>
      <description>Kougelhopf is the quintessential Alsacian cake. This bundt cake is perfect for breakfast, sliced and covered with a thin layer of salted butter.
Ingredients (one large Kougelhopf):    75 grams of dried grapes 20 centiliters (200 grams) of milk 25 grams of fresh yeast1 500 grams of flour 75 grams of sugar 2 eggs 150 grams of salted butter a dozen almonds  Preparation:   Grapes    Puts the dried grapes in room temperature water to let them soak during the rest of the process  Yeast    mix the yeast with a few tablespoons of flour and 10 centiliters of lukewarm2 milk let rest until the yeast bubbles up  Dough    mix the flour, sugar and eggs add the leftover milk dice the butter and add it mix until the butter is properly incorporated add the yeast and milk to the dough, mix for a few minutes let rest one hour in a warm place (near a heater for example)  Pan    generously butter a Kougelhopf pan3 put almonds in the bottom indentations of the pan add the grapes to the dough put the dough in the pan let rest for about one hour (or until the dough fully fills the pan)  Cooking:    cook 45 minutes at 180C (350F)4 once it has had some time to cool down, unmold it onto a flat plate once cold, you can sprinkle some powdered sugar on the result for better looks  Credits:   This is my take on Marmiton&amp;rsquo;s Kougelhopf sucré (Alsace) recipe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pâte sablée (short crust pie)</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/pies/pate_sablee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/pies/pate_sablee/</guid>
      <description>This is a great pie dough for most open-style pies. It is rich in butter and tastes great by itself, even raw!
Ingredients (for one pie):    75 grams of sugar 1 egg 250 grams of flour 100 grams of salted butter1  Preparation:    mix the sugar and egg in a large bowl add the flour dice the butter and add it to the mix mix until homogeneous2  Cooking:    use a rolling pin to flatten the dough before putting it in the pie pan3 add the sweet pie fillings4 of your choice you might want to prebake the pie crust for about 10 minutes at 180C (350F)  Credits:   This is my take on Marmiton&amp;rsquo;s Pâte sablée recipe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grace Hopper</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/old-people/grace-hopper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/old-people/grace-hopper/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The most important thing I&amp;rsquo;ve accomplished, other than building the compiler, is training young people. They come to me, you know, and say, &amp;lsquo;Do you think we can do this?&amp;rsquo; I say, &amp;lsquo;Try it.&amp;rsquo; And I back &amp;rsquo;em up. They need that. I keep track of them as they get older and I stir &amp;rsquo;em up at intervals so they don&amp;rsquo;t forget to take chances.&amp;rdquo; — Grace Hopper
 Grace Hopper was both an admiral of the US navy and a pioneer of computer science, introducing some concepts that are now fundamental to programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hokusai</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/old-people/hokusai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/old-people/hokusai/</guid>
      <description>Hokusai is considered one of the greatest masters in the history of art. Even if you do not know his name, you have seen a reproduction or a take on his Great Wave off Kanagawa.
In his seventies, shortly after making the Great Wave off Kanagawa, he wrote:
 &amp;ldquo;From the age of six, I had a passion for copying the form of things and since the age of fifty I have published many drawings, yet of all I drew by my seventieth year there is nothing worth taking into account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yitang Zhang</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/old-people/yitang-zhang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/old-people/yitang-zhang/</guid>
      <description>Yitang Zhang was born in 1955. He obtained his Ph.D. at 36 but, having no publications nor the support of his advisor, he had to quit academia and work as an accountant and a delivery worker, sometimes sleeping in his car, while trying to make ends meet.
At 58 years old, he published an extremely influential paper on bounded gaps in prime numbers which suddenly gained him a large number of prizes, a prestigious university position and wide recognition in the world of mathematics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ozymandias</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/ozymandias/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/ozymandias/</guid>
      <description>I met a traveller from an antique land,
Who said—“Two vast and trunkless legs of stone
Stand in the desert. . . . Near them, on the sand,
Half sunk a shattered visage lies, whose frown,
And wrinkled lip, and sneer of cold command,
Tell that its sculptor well those passions read
Which yet survive, stamped on these lifeless things,
The hand that mocked them, and the heart that fed;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This too shall pass</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/this-too-shall-pass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/this-too-shall-pass/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;King Solomon once searched for a cure against depression. He assembled his wise men together. They meditated for a long time and gave him the following advice: Make yourself a ring and have thereon engraved the words &amp;lsquo;This too will pass.&amp;rsquo;
The King carried out the advice. He had the ring made and wore it constantly. Every time he felt sad and depressed, he looked at the ring, whereon his mood would change and he would feel cheerful&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guillermo Del Toro&#39;s Pinocchio</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/pinocchio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/pinocchio/</guid>
      <description>Guillermo Del Toro&amp;rsquo;s Pinocchio is surprisingly both a very faithful rendition of the original story and a very Del Toro movie.
It has a lot of Del Toro&amp;rsquo;s elements (older spirits meddling with human life, a found family, a refusal to glorify war and fascism as a background) but, if you did not know that it was a Del Toro movie, you would accept all of those elements as coming from the original material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harley Quinn</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/harley-quinn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/harley-quinn/</guid>
      <description>What is it about?   We follow the adventure of Harley Quinn, Joker&amp;rsquo;s previous sidekick and girlfriend (in the Batman universe) as she becomes an independent villain with her own crew and a healthy love life.
The target public is teenagers to adults.
Why do I like it?   This show is both very funny and very good at character development1.
With time, the Batman universe has accumulated a lot of unhealthy behaviors2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amphibia</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/amphibia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/amphibia/</guid>
      <description>What is it about?   Amphibia is about a young girl being trapped in a world of talking frogs, adapting to her new environment and trying to get back home.
The target public is mostly younger children (no older than middle school).
Why do I like it?   The show is made of bite-sized, mostly self-contained adventures. It is very light-hearted1, you can pick up any episode and go along with the comedy and adventure of the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Batman Beyond</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/batman-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/batman-beyond/</guid>
      <description>What is it about?   The events of the cartoon happen years in the future, Bruce Wayne is now a grumpy old man mentoring a young new Batman.
The target public is middle school to high school children.
Why do I like it?   Batman Beyond is a Peter Parker (Spiderman) like teenager dressed as Batman and evolving in Blade Runner&amp;rsquo;s dystopian company-owned universe and it works so well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bob&#39;s Burger</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/bobs-burger/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/bobs-burger/</guid>
      <description>What is it about?   We follow Bob and his family trying to make ends meet with their small burger restaurant.
This cartoon is suitable for all ages and tries to give something to everyone.
Why do I like it?   Most family comedy shows display people that are very mean to each other1. Bob&amp;rsquo;s Burger, on the other side, is wholesome: showing us a loving family that stands united despite day-to-day struggles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craig of the Creek</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/craig-of-the-creek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/craig-of-the-creek/</guid>
      <description>What is it about?   We follow Craig and his friends as they play in the nearby woods (the eponymous creek) after school.
The target public is mostly younger children (no older than middle school).
Why do I like it?   This show is an ode to the power of imagination. We follow a group of children playing games and see the world through their eyes, never quite sure where reality stops and imagination begins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DuckTales</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/ducktales/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/ducktales/</guid>
      <description>What is it about?   Ducktales (the 2017 reboot) follows the adventure of Uncle Scrooge and his family as they scour the world for treasure.
The target public is mostly younger children (no older than middle school).
Why do I like it?   Ducktales is very funny.
While I am a fan of the original characters, this is a great take on them and it introduces some things that should become standard in this universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravity Falls</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/gravity-falls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/gravity-falls/</guid>
      <description>What is it about?   We follow twins during their summer vacation with their weird old uncle.
The target public is mostly younger children (no older than middle school).
Why do I like it?   This is twin peaks for kids.
This show strikes a great balance between being funny, mysterious, adventurous, quaint, somewhat a coming-of-age story and still funny1. All of the plots work well together and it juggles between tones seamlessly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Owl House</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/owl-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/cartoons/owl-house/</guid>
      <description>What is it about?   The Owl House is about a young girl living her dream of moving to a world of witches.
The target public is mostly younger children (up to high school).
Why do I like it?   This is basically a cartoon version of Harry Potter with great representation (strong women, people of color / diverse ethnicities and wholesome LGBTQ+ relationships) and a strong &amp;ldquo;be your own quircky self&amp;rdquo; message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nachos</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/nachos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/nachos/</guid>
      <description>Nachos are a great group meal to eat with friends. This particular version comes with a satisfying bean base to make it a proper meal that can be scooped with tortilla chips as you go.
Ingredients (two servings):     half of an onion (I like a red onion for decorative purposes)
  olive oil
  soy sauce
  one can of beans (I like chili beans)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pizza dough</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/pizza/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/pizza/</guid>
      <description>Pizza is a classic for a reason. A lot of recipes call for preparing the dough on a previous day or a special oven, this recipe steers away from those best practices to give you something delicious within two hours.
Ingredients (one pizza):    250 grams of flour 6 grams of salt 4 grams of dry yeast (about half a packet) 175 grams of warm water1 15 grams of olive oil (enough to coat the pan)  Preparation:   Dough     mix the flour, salt and yeast in a big bowl</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dalgona Coffee</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/dalgona_coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/dalgona_coffee/</guid>
      <description>This drink is quick and easy to make, tastes like an éclair au café, and looks very pretty. It is perfect to share with a guest who likes coffee.
Ingredients (1 glass):    two teaspoons of instant coffee1 two teaspoons of sugar two teaspoons of boiling water one glass of very cold whole2 milk3  Preparation:    mix the instant coffee, sugar, and boiling water in a bowl whip until the color lightens and the texture becomes fluffier4 pour the coffee foam5 on top of a glass of very cold milk to serve add a straw, let guests mix, and start drinking  Credits:   This recipe was inspired by seeing James Hoffman discuss the drink on his youtube channel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spaghetti Epinardo E Olio</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/weekday_meal/pasta_spinash/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/weekday_meal/pasta_spinash/</guid>
      <description>This dish is relatively easy to cook while bringing some very strong flavors and colors to the table. I highly recommend it if you want a weeknight meal that feels slightly fancier than it should be.
Ingredients (for two portions):    160 grams of spaghetti1 (80 grams per person) some olive oil a generous amount of pepper some salt a large bowl packed full of fresh baby spinach the equivalent of one and a half large cloves of garlic2 about 30 grams of butter some grated parmesan3  Preparation:   Mise en place    rince the spinach and dice them very finely crush the garlic dice the butter  Pasta    fill a pan with water and bring it to a boil add a generous amount of salt to your pasta water4 add the pasta when the water starts boiling and keep cooking for about 10 minutes (until your pasta is cooked)  Spinach    put the olive oil in a wok add a very generous amount of pepper and cook on high heat until the pepper becomes fragrant5 add the finely diced spinach (roughly when you add the pasta to its water) and a big pinch of salt6 let simmer on medium to low heat until the pasta is ready  Assembly    once the pasta is cooked, add a splash of pasta water to the wok, this will help with the consistency of the sauce strain the pasta and add them to the wok (it is fine if there is some pasta water left with the pasta, we added pasta water to the wok anyway) add the crushed garlic and diced butter start mixing on high heat once it is fairly well mixed, sprinkle grated parmesan as you would cover a similar amount of pasta in a plate7 mix constantly on high heat until you reach the desired consistency (I recommend aiming for slightly more liquid than your sweet spot, the sauce will thicken further once served) and all the cheese has dissolved into the sauce salt to taste  Credits:   While this dish&amp;rsquo;s name is the combination of Spaghetti Aglio E Olio and the Italian word for spinach, it is inspired by wanting to do a pasta dish with spinach and having seen this Cacio E Pepe recipe recently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beeny&#39;s Brownies</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/brownies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/brownies/</guid>
      <description>This is a very straightforward chocolate brownies recipe. You can pimp it up with some coffee powder1, a few salt flakes on top, any kind of nuts, chocolate chunks, etc. The world is your chocolate-flavored oyster!
Ingredients (8 slices):    100 grams of flour 37 grams of cocoa powder 125 grams of sugar 2 eggs 1 teaspoon of vanilla extract (optional) 100 grams of salted butter  Preparation:    mix the flour and cocoa in a bowl add the sugar and mix beat the eggs and add add the vanilla extract melt the butter, add it and mix pour in a pan lined with parchment paper  Cooking:    cook 25 to 30 minutes in a 340F (170C) oven let cool in the pan cut into slices before serving (they might be best served the next day for peak flavor and texture)  Credits:   This is my take on Sarah Beeny&amp;rsquo;s chocolate brownies recipe (with which she beat Gordon Ramsay on British television).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eldritch Academia (annotated)</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/fiction/eldritch_academia_anotated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/fiction/eldritch_academia_anotated/</guid>
      <description>This is the annotated edition of Eldritch Academia1. I expect it to be of very limited interest to others (the short story is probably not worth an annotated edition) but, it is a fun way to record some of the thoughts and references I put in the text and an exercise in overloading a page with sidenotes.
My overall feeling about the story is that it lacks conflict, probably because the narrator is not resisting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegan fruity breakfast</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/breakfast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/breakfast/</guid>
      <description>This breakfast manages to both be delicious and give you the feeling that you are eating healthy. And it feels good. I get the needed ingredients about once a month to eat it for a few days (I feel that eating it every day would reduce my enjoyment).
Ingredients (1 bowl):    two tablespoons of granola1 two tablespoons of unsweetened coconut milk yogurt2 two tablespoons of blueberries a few strawberries3  Preparation:    put the granola in a bowl add the yogurt wash and add the blueberries wash, dice and add the stawberries  Credits:   You can find similar recipes on Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nestor&#39;s guide to writing</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/writing/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Writing is easy. Just put a sheet of paper in the typewriter and start bleeding.&amp;rdquo; — Walter Wellesley &amp;ldquo;Red&amp;rdquo; Smith
 I am the intended reader of this guide. If the tone seems harsh or the advice opinionated, it is because I can sometimes be harsh with myself and because I know that those techniques work for me. I have written non-fiction professionally in various fields but never published any fiction so take the following with the appropriate amount of salt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegetarian pasta carbonara</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/weekday_meal/pasta_carbonara/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/weekday_meal/pasta_carbonara/</guid>
      <description>This dish is slightly fancier than my usual weekday dish but it is good enough to have spoiled a lot of restaurant Carbonara pasta for me while being relatively fast and easy to cook. Plus, it is vegetarian!
Ingredients (for two portions):    160 grams of pasta (80 grams per person, you could go up to 100 grams), I like tagliatelle but, most pasta types would be fine1 half of a thick zucchini2 some olive oil some soy sauce two egg yolks3 some milk (about the same volume as the egg yolk) a lot of parmesan (at least the same volume as the egg yolk) a lot of black pepper (get a pepper grinder, you will get a much-improved taste) two big cloves of garlic4  Preparation:   Pasta    fill a pan with water and bring it to a boil you can optionally add a generous amount of salt to your pasta water, the pasta will taste better but, you do not need it here add the pasta when the water starts boiling and keep cooking for about 10 minutes (until your pasta is cooked)  Zucchini    peel your zucchini cut it into thin slices long as about a third of a bacon strip put in a wok with a splash of olive oil add a splash of soy sauce let cook until the pasta is ready  Sauce    put the egg yolks in a bowl add the milk add the parmesan add black pepper (you can, optionally, also add some chili flakes here) add the crushed garlic mix thoroughly and set aside  Assembly    once the pasta is cooked, add a splash of pasta water to the wok, this will help with the sauce consistency (you can be approximate with the quantity, too little and your sauce will miss a bit of thickness, too much and you will have to reduce longer: either way the result will be fine and you can do better next time) you can do it directly from the pasta pan, no need for an intermediate container (that would give you additional opportunities to burn yourself) strain the pasta and add them to the wok (it is okay if there is some pasta water left with the pasta, we have pasta water in the wok anyway) set the heat to low add the sauce and mix constantly (to avoid having the egg yolk curl) until you reach the desired consistency (I recommend aiming for slightly more liquid than your sweet spot, the sauce will thicken further once served) serve on a plate5  Credits:   This is my take on Adam Raguseas&amp;rsquo;s carbonara pasta with zucchini.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Zen story</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/zen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/zen/</guid>
      <description>One day a famous government officer met a highly respected elderly master. Being conceited, he wanted to prove that he was the superior person.
As their conversation drew on, he asked the master, &amp;ldquo;Old monk, do you know what I think of you and the things you said?&amp;rdquo;
The master replied, &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t care what you think of me. You are entitled to have your own opinion.&amp;rdquo;
The officer snorted, &amp;ldquo;Well, I will tell you what I think anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two-ingredient chocolate mousse</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/chocolate_mousse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/chocolate_mousse/</guid>
      <description>This is the perfect recipe to do when you have leftover egg whites. It is delicious and uses barely any ingredients (I always keep the proper chocolate in my pantry to do this recipe when I have egg whites). Its only downside is that, once you have prepared everything, you need to wait.
Ingredients (1 portion):    1 egg whites1 35 grams of chocolate2  Preparation:    beat your egg whites into a nice firm foam melt the chocolate (it is okay to leave some chunks in the melted chocolate, they will add heterogeneity to the result) optionally, if you have egg yolks, add them to the melted chocolate and mix until homogeneous (be careful not to cook them in the hot chocolate) fold (or beat) the melted chocolate into the egg whites pour into one glass, mug, or bowl per portion store in the fridge for at least 5 hours (you can wait a full night if you want to be sure) eat cold (you can shave some chocolate on top if you want to make it look fancy)  Credits:   The proportions are inspired by this Mousse au chocolat facile recipe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Figures of speech</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/figures_of_speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/figures_of_speech/</guid>
      <description>Figures of speech (which you can find here) is a project done illuminations media for the Almeida Theater in which great actors read great speeches and it is absolutely fantastic.
It includes, amongst others, Ian McKellen reading Harvey Milk&amp;rsquo;s Hope Speech, Derek Jacobi reading Socrates&amp;rsquo; I Go To Die, and Noma Dumezweni reading Margaret Sanger&amp;rsquo;s The Morality of Birth Control.
The actors are great, the speeches have stood the test of time and it is a great vessel to get familiar with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First they came ...</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/first_they_came/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/first_they_came/</guid>
      <description>First they came for the Communists
And I did not speak out
Because I was not a Communist
Then they came for the Socialists
And I did not speak out
Because I was not a Socialist
Then they came for the trade unionists
And I did not speak out
Because I was not a trade unionist
Then they came for the Jews
And I did not speak out
Because I was not a Jew</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter from a Birmingham Jail</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/birmingham_jail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/texts/birmingham_jail/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I have almost reached the regrettable conclusion that the Negro&amp;rsquo;s great stumbling block in his stride toward freedom is not the White Citizen&amp;rsquo;s Counciler or the Ku Klux Klanner, but the white moderate, who is more devoted to &amp;ldquo;order&amp;rdquo; than to justice; who prefers a negative peace which is the absence of tension to a positive peace which is the presence of justice.&amp;rdquo; — Martin Luther King Jr., Letter from a Birmingham Jail</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consumers and producers</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/concepts/consumers_producers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/concepts/consumers_producers/</guid>
      <description>Most activities can be categorized as either consumer or producer.
A consumer activity is an activity during which you consume existing content such as watching a video, reading a book, or browsing the Internet. Depending on the content you consumed, it can be nourishing or leave you with a feeling of emptiness.
A producer activity is an activity during which you produce new content for others to consume such as drawing, writing, cooking, or programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rice Zucchini à la Alfredo</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/weekday_meal/rice_zucchini/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/weekday_meal/rice_zucchini/</guid>
      <description>This dish is all about the pleasure of eating rice with Parmesan and butter, with some zucchini tossed in for good measure. It is quick to do and delicious, try it on a weekday.
Ingredients (one person):    Half a zucchini, 60 grams of rice, a lot of salted butter1, as much Parmesan as butter, optionally, some smoked chilly flakes for added flavor complexity.  Preparation:    Peel the Zucchini and dice it, bring water to a boil, add the rice and zucchini to the water and cook for ten minutes2, put the butter on the plate, add the (optional) chilly flakes, once the rice and zucchini are cooked, strain and pour on the butter add the Parmesan and mix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japanese Can Opener</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/objects/can_opener/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/objects/can_opener/</guid>
      <description>The cheapest kind of can opener you can buy in France is a single piece of metal with a sharp edge, it is also the most practical kind of can opener. In the US it is called a Japanese can opener and it is apparently very fancy.
Those things are a marvel of design, they have no moving parts (it is literally a single piece of metal) making them dead easy to use and clean, very durable (they will outlive you, by a long shot), space-efficient (nice if, for whatever reason, you want to travel with your can opener) and dirt cheap (about $9 on Amazon for a fancier model).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Name of the Rose</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/name-of-the-rose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/name-of-the-rose/</guid>
      <description>Note: There will be spoilers.
I just re(re-re)-watched the Name of the Rose and I still absolutely love it.
The main character, William of Baskerville, is basically a Sherlock Holmes clone (he even says &amp;ldquo;Elementary!&amp;rdquo; to his apprentice a couple of times) except that he is a Franciscan monk living during the middle-ages and investigating a murder in an abbey that is busy with a debate on whether the church should be poor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Shopping trolley bag</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/objects/cabas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/objects/cabas/</guid>
      <description>If you do your groceries on foot, a shopping trolley bag (with wheels) is a game-changer.
The main hurdle when going grocery shopping on foot is dealing with the weight of the produces on the way back. However, I observed a large number of old people doing their groceries on foot as if it were nothing (while the way back was clearly strenuous to my weak arms).
Their superpower? The power of the wheel!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pasta bell pepper</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/weekday_meal/pasta_bellpepper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/weekday_meal/pasta_bellpepper/</guid>
      <description>This dish is very fast to cook, brings you the carbs you need, some greens (technically reds), and has a distinct enough flavor to fight monotony in your eating habits.
Ingredients (for two portions):    160 grams of pasta (80 grams per person, you could go up to 100 grams), I like fusilli for this dish but most pasta types would be fine 1 bell pepper (all colors are fine, but I have a slight preference for red as it imparts some color to the pasta) some salted soy sauce (the salt will be useful) some olive oil (we will cook it so no need for high-quality stuff) some herbes de Provence (you could use another dry herbs mix but do use dry herbs, they make the flavor of the dish) some cayenne pepper (optional)  Preparation:   Pasta    fill a pan with water and bring it to a boil (big bubbles, small bubbles do not count as boiling, you will be delighted to discover that I met people for which this is not obvious) add the pasta when the water starts boiling and keep cooking for about 10 minutes (until your pasta is cooked)  Sauce    once the pasta is in the water, put the diced bell pepper in a wok (or similar large pan) on low heat add a generous splash of olive oil add a generous splash of soy sauce (this will bring you the salt in the dish plus a lot of the flavor) add a very generous sprinkle of herbs (you can hardly overdo it here) optionally, add a sprinkle of cayenne pepper (you want enough for people to realize the dish has some hotness but no more, it is not a hot dish) cook on low heat  Assembly    once the pasta is cooked, add a splash of pasta water to the wok, this will help with the sauce consistency (you can be approximate with the quantity, too little and your sauce will miss a bit of thickness, too much and you will have to reduce longer: either way the result will be fine and you can do better next time) you can do it directly from the pasta pan, no need for an intermediate container (that would give you additional opportunities to burn yourself) strain the pasta and add them to the wok (it is okay if there is some pasta water left with the pasta, we have pasta water in the wok anyway) raise to medium heat and keep mixing until you get the sauce consistency you want (the mixing time will depend on the amount of water you put, you should be done in two minutes) serve on a plate, feel free to add butter and shredded Parmesan to pimp the result slightly  Credits:   Using the pasta water comes from French guy cooking&amp;rsquo;s Alex and is a game-changer for pasta sauces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philips Sonicare toothbrush</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/objects/toothbrush/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/objects/toothbrush/</guid>
      <description>The Philips Sonicare toothbrush is the best electronic toothbrush I ever used. By a significant margin. It is not only good at cleaning your teeth but also one of those rare objects that are well designed.
Regarding the quality of the cleaning (arguably the most important criteria), I could feel a sensible reduction in plaque when I went from a traditional toothbrush to an electric toothbrush, but this was one more step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Alchemaster&#39;s Apprentice</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/alchemasters_apprentice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/alchemasters_apprentice/</guid>
      <description>I just finished reading The Alchemaster&amp;rsquo;s Apprentice by Walter Moers.
Superficially, the book is about a young crat1 dying of hunger in the streets until he makes a Faustian bargain with an alchemaster: for a month he will be fed the best food, taught alchemy, and enjoy the best life a crat might want then, at the full moon, he will be killed and rendered for his fat. The book talks about friendship and love from a wide variety of angles, however, none of this is the point of the book, it is barely the seasoning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Birthday of the World and Other Stories</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/birthday_of_the_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/books/birthday_of_the_world/</guid>
      <description>I finished The Birthday of the World and Other Stories by Ursula K. Le Guin a few months ago. I know of Ursula Le Guin by reputation1, but it is the first of her book that I read, and&amp;hellip; it was a slap in the face.
The book is a collection of short stories in her Ekumen universe making them technically science fiction. However, while science-fiction usually deals with things and technologies, these stories are all about people and feelings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crêpes</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/crepes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/others/crepes/</guid>
      <description>Crêpes are the perfect social dish. You can make them together then everyone put the topping of their choice on top, sweet or savory1.
Ingredients (4 people):    250 grams flour 25 grams of sugar 4 eggs 500 ml milk 50 grams of salted butter (or 40 grams of olive oil and a pinch of salt, the taste is slightly different but it works)  Preparation:    put the flour in a mixing bowl add the sugar add the eggs and mix add the milk progressively while mixing add the melted butter (making sure it is not hot enough to cook the eggs prematurely) and mix  Cooking:    slightly oil (or butter) the pan put a ladle worth of crêpe batter and spread it to make it round once the bottom is cooked (the sides should start to get browned), use a spatula and flip it (it should cook for about a minute) repeat as many times as needed  Credits:   This recipe is my version of Crêpes : la meilleure recette rapide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The easy path</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/concepts/easy_path/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/concepts/easy_path/</guid>
      <description>The opposite of wanting something to be perfect is following the easy path: knowing that some things could be done to make your project objectively better but keeping the current version because it is &amp;ldquo;good enough&amp;rdquo;.
This, as long as the modification would be within the scope and allotted time1, is a form of laziness. However, it is insidious. All parts of a project have to be considered &amp;ldquo;good enough&amp;rdquo; before you let go of them to tackle the next step, it is very easy to not realize that your motivation shifted from an objective look at the quality of your work toward avoiding additional work to the detriment of the result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Melting butter</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/technique/melting_butter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/technique/melting_butter/</guid>
      <description>This should be obvious but&amp;hellip;
Ingredients:    the butter you want to melt  Technique:    put the butter in a small bowl microwave until you hear some bubbling sound (30 seconds is usually enough)  Credits:   The technique seems obvious, I am not aware of any particular credits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Melting chocolate</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/technique/melting_chocolate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/technique/melting_chocolate/</guid>
      <description>The classical technique to melt chocolate is to use a double broiler (also called bain Marie). However, I am deeply convinced that using a microwave is significantly easier and faster.
Ingredients:    chocolate to melt a tablespoon of water (you need some water to prevent dry burning but too much will deteriorate the result) if the recipe calls for melted butter, adding cream or milk, you can replace the water with one of those in the quantities required by the recipe  Technique:    put the chocolate in a small bowl add the liquid or milk produce microwave until the chocolate is softened (around one minute depending on the strength of your microwave) mix the result to finish melting the chocolate  Credits:   I am not aware of any particular credit for this technique, I saw it used by a variety of sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>US-style pie crust</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/pies/us_pie_crust/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/pies/us_pie_crust/</guid>
      <description>This pie dough is easy to make and tastes pretty much perfect for a US-style pie (with crust below and above the pie). Plus, the leftover dough can be stored in the fridge for later use.
Ingredients (for one pie):    300 grams of flour 20 grams of sugar (optional) 227 grams of salted butter (get it out of the fridge as soon as you start to raise its temperature and make your job easier) 53 grams of water 8 grams of apple cider vinegar (needs testing to see how impactful it is)  Preparation:    put the flour in a large bowl add the sugar add the butter diced or sliced into thin slices (to simplify the mixing) with one hand mix the dough until you get a crumbly/flaky consistency add half of the water plus the vinegar and mix add the leftover water and mix into a ball cut the ball in two and refrigerate for 30 minutes while you prepare the fillings  Cooking:    You might want to prebake the bottom of our pie (for a European-style pie) or let your pie cook for a long time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A magician is a...</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/magician_is_actor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/essays/magician_is_actor/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;A magician is an actor playing the part of a magician.&amp;rdquo; — Jean Eugène Robert-Houdin.
 The quote   This essay is dedicated to magicians. Others might find it intriguing, but it will probably be irrelevant to them.
If you ask a magician to give you one famous quote about their object of study, the vast majority of them will tell you that Jean Eugène Robert-Houdin once said &amp;ldquo;A magician is an actor playing the part of a magician.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nestor&#39;s guide to creating a blog</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/blogging/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: This guide is mostly about me keeping a trace of the process I followed to create this blog. I really wanted to use GitHub for the hosting and that leads to a lot of additional complexity that you should avoid if you are not used to writing code.
Hosting   I used GitHub pages to host my blog, they are free but only support static websites and, by default, force you to use their domain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nestor&#39;s guide to doing a large project</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/hard_things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/hard_things/</guid>
      <description>Tackling a large project (this applies to anything including a book, a piece of software, or a movie for example) can be daunting. Suddenly it is not a sprint to the end of a task but, rather, an endurance race that requires regularly renewed dedication: something school and early life do not prepare you for.
These are my solutions to tackle large projects (you will find some overlap with my guide to doing the things you love well and my guide to writing).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pasta ratatouille</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/weekday_meal/pasta_ratatouille/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/weekday_meal/pasta_ratatouille/</guid>
      <description>This dish is a worker: it is fast and easy to cook while being delicious and rich in vegetables and flavors.
I have been cooking variations of this dish for as long as I have been cooking for myself, starting when I had my first apartment. It has evolved a lot since its inception but it is still one of my favorite way to eat pasta.
Ingredients (for two portions):    160 grams of pasta (80 grams per person, you could go up to 100 grams), I like fusilli for this dish but most pasta types would be fine half a jar of organic1 ratatouille (this is where I lose my US readers, you simply cannot find this stuff in the US: you might replace it with a jar of tomato sauce that contains a generous amount of eggplants and assorted vegetables) some salted soy sauce (the salt will be useful) some olive oil (we will cook it so no need for high-quality stuff) some salt (optional) some cayenne pepper (optional)  Preparation:   Pasta    fill a pan with water and bring it to a boil (big bubbles, small bubbles do not count as boiling, you will be delighted to discover that I met people for which this is not obvious) you can optionally add a generous amount of salt to your pasta water, the pasta will taste better but, you do not need it here add the pasta when the water starts boiling and keep cooking for about 10 minutes (until your pasta is cooked)  Sauce    once the pasta is in the water, put the ratatouille in a wok (or similar large pan) on low heat add a generous splash of olive oil add a generous splash of soy sauce (this will bring you the salt in the dish plus a lot of the flavor) optionally, add a sprinkle of cayenne pepper (you want enough for people to realize the dish has some hotness but no more, it is not a hot dish) cook on low heat  Assembly    once the pasta is cooked, add a splash of pasta water to the wok, this will help with the sauce consistency (you can be approximate with the quantity, too little and your sauce will miss a bit of thickness, too much and you will have to reduce longer: either way the result will be fine and you can do better next time) you can do it directly from the pasta pan, no need for an intermediate container (that would give you additional opportunities to burn yourself) strain the pasta and add them to the wok (it is okay if there is some pasta water left with the pasta, we have pasta water in the wok anyway) raise to medium heat and keep mixing until you get the sauce consistency you want (the mixing time will depend on the amount of water you put, you should be done in two minutes) serve on a plate, feel free to add butter and shredded Parmesan to pimp the result slightly  Credits:   I used soy sauce and a jar of ratatouille because my father put them in my very first grocery bag as an independent student.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avocado toast</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/sandwich/avocado_toast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/sandwich/avocado_toast/</guid>
      <description>Avocado toast is the most shamefully Californian dish. This version has a nice spicy punch to it.
Ingredients (one toast):    one slice of bread (I recommend multigrain bread, it has more depth of flavor once toasted) some mayonnaise one avocado coarse salt pepper Sriracha sauce (as this is a big part of the final flavor, do not accept substitutes to the original sauce)  Preparation:    toast the bread put a thin layer of mayonnaise on the bread put a layer of avocado on the bread (you can spread it or slice it for a better-looking result) add a zigzag of Sriracha sauce add a generous amount of salt and pepper  Credits:   This recipe is taken straight from You suck at cooking&amp;rsquo;s great Youtube Channel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacon Tomato Melt</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/sandwich/bacon_tomato_melt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/sandwich/bacon_tomato_melt/</guid>
      <description>This is the pinnacle of self-indulging food. It is fast to prepare and very calorie-rich but the bacon, melted cheese, and toasted bread mesh perfectly and hit all the right spots.
Ingredients (one toast):    one or two slices of bacon1 one slice of bread (I recommend multigrain bread, it has more depth of flavor once toasted) some mayonnaise half a tomato coarse salt (optional) shredded cheese  Preparation:    cook the bacon until crisp2 toast the bread spread a thin layer of mayonnaise on the bread (it is there for some flavor notes but also to avoid having the tomato juice make the bread soggy) covers the bread with a one-slice thick layer of tomato sprinkle some salt add a layer of crispy bacon add a pile of shredded cheese at the very least as thick as the rest of the sandwich on top toast until the cheese is melted to your preference serve warm  Credits:   This recipe is taken straight from You suck at cooking&amp;rsquo;s great Youtube Channel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clafoutis</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/clafoutis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/clafoutis/</guid>
      <description>Clafoutis was my favorite kind of cake when I was a kid. My mother used to make plum ones while fruits were in season and I famously ate a full cake that just got out of the oven while she was away from the kitchen. They are also a great way to turn fruits into a cake that looks very pretty while being extremely easy to make.
Ingredients:    about 500grams (you want to cover your pan with a nice layer) of a mix of cherries and apricots (stones fruits such as cherries, plums apricots, and peaches feel like a better match but it works with pretty much anything including bananas and rhubarb, I like a mix of cherries and apricots to vary colors and flavors) 4 eggs 100 grams of flour 60 grams of salted butter (you could use 45 grams of olive oil and some salt, the taste and texture would slightly differ but that still makes for a good cake) 60 grams of sugar (you could go up to 100 grams according to taste) 25cl of milk some vanilla extract (optional)  Preparation:   The pan    put a generous amount of butter on the sides of your cake pan (you want a wider rather than tall pan) cut your fruits (stones fruits can be cut into two or four, don&amp;rsquo;t forget to remove the stone, you can leave the skin on) and spread them in the cake pan  The batter    mix the eggs with the sugar until smooth add the (optional) vanilla extract add the flour while mixing add the milk while mixing melt the butter in a microwave (or oven but 30 seconds in a microwave is perfect) then add (if the butter is warm, mix it fast enough to not cook your egg) pour the batter into your cake pan (the batter will be more golden and liquid than usual cake batter, it is perfectly normal)  Cooking:    cook 30 to 45 minutes at 350F (180C), you can stop once the top is golden and the batter firm serve at room temperature (it is also great cold after a few hours in the fridge) you can (optionally) dust the top with powdered white sugar just before serving if you are serving cold (this is purely esthetic)  Credits:   This clafoutis batter is pretty classic and can be found all over the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tarte au Maroille</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/tarte_maroille/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/special_meal/tarte_maroille/</guid>
      <description>This cheese pie recipe is a family secret. It was passed down from my grandmother to my mother to me (my sister did not care for cooking at the time). I am writing it so that it can be saved for future generations to enjoy (if you want to keep a secret, put it in writing).
Ingredients (two pies):   Dought    1 kg of white flour 5 egg yolks 1 cube of fresh yeast1 a few spoonfuls of sugar (white is fine, brown is better, cassonade/vergeoise is traditional) 125 grams of salted butter (butter is good, salted is better)  Toping    one egg, one egg&amp;rsquo;s worth of milk, some grated nutmeg (optional) one big, full, Maroille2  Preparation:   Dough    Put the sugar and the yeast in a small bowl of warmish water3, mix once and let rest until it gets foamy put most of the flour in a large mixing bowl (set a little aside to shape the dough later) add the egg yolks and the yeast with its water mix until combined, do not over-mix (the resulting dough will be very sticky) cover with a towel and let rise for one hour (warmish places such as a window in the sun are best)  Assembling the pie    spread the dough on top of your pizza pans (you want flat pizza type of pans rather than pie pans), you can use the leftover flour to help shape the dough (do not use a rolling pin, this is a finger-stretching affair) add slices of Maroile on your dough (you want to cover it, the more the merrier) brush with a mix done with one egg and a little bit of milk (you can brush with your fingers) add a little bit of grounded nutmeg  Cooking:    Cook at 180C (350F) for 30 to 45 minutes (the crust should be hardened and the cheese pretty melted).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crumble</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/crumble/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/sweet/cakes/crumble/</guid>
      <description>Crumbles are pretty much impossible to miss and a great way to turn fruits (most fruits are suitable; apples, pears, and peaches are classic) and butter into a good cake. This one is pimped with chocolate chips, cinnamon, vanilla extract, and lemon juice. They are all worth it but, you can cut all of them if you want to keep things simple (or do not have them on hand).
Ingredients (for 4 portions):    100g of flour (you can easily turn the grams into cups and half cups: it is the respective proportions that matter) 100g of salted butter (you can also use unsalted butter and had some salt, the result is identical, but do not omit the salt) 50g of sugar 2 large pears some good cooking chocolate (no need for a sweet one, 70% cacao does a good job, also I like to get a chocolate bar and cut it into smallish chips, you get better quality chocolate and bigger chips) some cinnamon some vanilla extract some lemon juice  Preparation:   bottom layer    peel the pears, dice them, and put them on the bottom of your baking dish (I use a Pyrex square one), you want enough pears to garnish the bottom of the dish with about one centimeter of pears add some lemon juice on top, not much just a spoonful so that the pears are finely coated cut your chocolate into chips and sprinkle them on top of the layer of pears (no need for much, it is not a chocolate cake!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KrautBurger</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/sandwich/krautburger/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/cooking/savoury/sandwich/krautburger/</guid>
      <description>The Krautburger is my favorite homemade burger of the moment. It is vegetarian (but not vegan due to the presence of mayonnaise and, harder to replace, cheese) and light while hitting all the flavors I want due to the melted cheese and toasted bun combined with the surprising freshness of the thick tomato slice hidden inside the burger.
Ingredients (one burger):    a burger bun (bread rather than brioche if possible) some mayonnaise one tomato enough sauerkraut to make a small patty out of it (pick one that is not too flavorful and whose flavor you like, otherwise you might be disappointed by this burger&amp;hellip;) 2 slices of cheese (you want a cheese that does not melt instantly, so no American cheese, I like pepper jack because of the added flavor from the chili flakes, I would probably sprinkle some chilly flakes on my sauerkraut if all I had was Gruyère)  Preparation:    toast the lower bun (this step is optional but will reduce sogginess) spread a layer of mayonnaise on each half-bun (the goal here is not to act on the taste but to stop water from going through and into the bun) put thick tomato slices on the bottom bun until it is fully covered (I like my slices about one centimeter thick) add one slice of cheese put some sauerkraut on top and shape it like a small pattie add the second slice of cheese add the final bun  Cooking:    toast in the oven until the cheese is nicely melted and the top bun lightly toasted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Batman</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/the-batman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/the-batman/</guid>
      <description>I saw the Batman and&amp;hellip; meh.
I love the acting of the Riddler in his unmasked sections (he looks like an accountant and that is great).
Some solid action scenes, but none of the set pieces really strikes me.
The gadgets are really nice (lenses, parachute, etc.) but the scenario leaves me cold. The Riddler and the plot are clearly inspired by Seven while Batman&amp;rsquo;s moral (and notebook) are clearly taken from Watchmen&amp;rsquo;s Rorschach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nightmare alley</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/nightmare-alley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/likes/movies/nightmare-alley/</guid>
      <description>I watched Guillermo Del Toro&amp;rsquo;s Nightmare Alley yesterday and&amp;hellip; It was ok.
I might have been let down a little because I love both Guillermo Del Toro and the source material (by the way, you can find both the original black&amp;amp;white movie and the book for free, legally, on the internet archive) so I had a lot of expectations.
The actors are solid, the movie has a very nice forties ambiance (I love the psychologist&amp;rsquo;s office design) and some scenes are wonderful (the one scene dealing with the consequence of his actions&amp;hellip; and the final scene which was already one of the strong points from the original story) but I felt that the scenario was lacking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nestor&#39;s guide to dating apps</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/dating/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/dating/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: This guide is targeted at heterosexual men (with a focus on people looking for a relationship) and was written at the end of 2021 for a friend, the content might not apply to you. Also, a lot of the following might seem obvious to you but, as what is obvious to some isn’t to others, I am putting a maximum of information here in the hope that you might find things that you do not already know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nestor&#39;s guide to doing the things you love well</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/heuristics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/heuristics/</guid>
      <description>Here are some heuristics I use in life and work:
 Play to your strengths, being balanced sounds nice but end up being really unproductive/unpleasant. Spend time on the things you like, as time and practice pile up you will end up skilled in those domains. Go for the things that are of interest to you, not for the trendy ones. Time spend automating tasks is usually time well spent. Taking a break to gather knowledge on something vaguely connected to the thing you are doing is never time lost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eldritch Academia</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/fiction/eldritch_academia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/fiction/eldritch_academia/</guid>
      <description>Object: Some News   Hey Sonia,
How are you doing?
To answer your question (sorry for the late email, moving did not leave me much time to write), the math department is paying me to study KTu-L spaces.
You might have seen some references to them popping up in the past year, they have gained a lot of visibility as some mathematicians (mostly Providence’s research team which I will be joining this week) claim that they can be used to solve a number of interesting conjectures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nestor&#39;s guide to having ideas</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/guides/ideas/</guid>
      <description>No one is born uncreative   Some people have told me that they are not creative. It usually stems from them thinking that creativity is an innate gift: some people are born with a brain that overflow with ideas at regular intervals while others stay dry for most of their life.
In practice, I found creativity to be a muscle. The more you try to use it and the easier it gets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consulting mentalist</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/mentalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/mentalism/</guid>
      <description>I am a consulting mentalist (amongst other things, I have a book published for that public and I designed several stage shows).
What is mentalism?   Mentalism is an ensemble of techniques (including mnemotechnic, hypnosis, magic tricks, knowledge of statistically likely phenomenons, and a trained intuition) used to produce incredible phenomenons (usually psychic phenomenons or an impressive mastery of the human mind) in an entertainment setting.
One point that is worth stressing is that it is neither all real (magic tricks are great to make things look better / add some punch and anyone telling you they don&amp;rsquo;t use them is either lying or very ignorant) nor all fake (anyone telling you otherwise is, similarly, likely ignorant or a magician who did some telepathy-themed tricks and think that it is all there is to it).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research I did</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/research/</guid>
      <description>I am a researcher with specialties in numerical accuracy, artificial intelligence, data analysis, and high-performance computing.
Papers   You can find most of my publications on Researchgate. Here is a list of them in no particular order:
Ranger21: a synergistic deep learning optimizer (machine learning)   The Ranger21 paper was born from testing a large number of optimizers for deep learning and realizing that, while people were branding them as new optimizers, they often just included one new idea to an existing optimizer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software I wrote</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/about/software/</guid>
      <description>I am an engineer with a specialty in applied mathematics and computer science.
You can find most of the software I developed on Github and Gitlab. Here is a list of some noticeable libraries (focussing on projects where I am the main developer) in no particular order:
Shaman (C++)   Shaman is the crown jewel of my Ph.D., it helps you track and measure the numerical error in computations by replacing the types (double becomes Sdouble) with instrumented version.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
