<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>II. Acting in Society on Nestor Demeure</title>
    <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/</link>
    <description>Recent content in II. Acting in Society on Nestor Demeure</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><atom:link href="https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reading Speculative Books</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/55-reading-speculative/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/55-reading-speculative/</guid>
      <description>When reading an assertion, consider the following: the main message, the number of points made, the specific words used and their order, what can be inferred, and how the assertion is proven.
To internalize the assertion, break down the arguments into a logical structure and anticipate potential responses.
Are the premises sufficiently strong or well-supported? How can the supporting arguments be confirmed and what examples can be provided? With what main idea or argument does it agree or seem to conflict?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visiting Provinces</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/54-visiting-provinces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/54-visiting-provinces/</guid>
      <description>First, when arriving in a new region, avoid keeping records that are easily readable by the locals. Instead, write any noteworthy observations, whether positive or negative, in a foreign language. This prevents locals from taking offense if they happen to come across your notes.&amp;quot;
Second, observe all sacred objects in both public and private spaces, such as the interiors of temples, epitaphs, offerings, tombs of notable figures, and religious symbols and architecture such as organs, columns, and pulpits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being Accused</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/53-being-accused/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/53-being-accused/</guid>
      <description>If you notice that someone has accused you, conceal your knowledge of the accusation and do not immediately change your behavior. This way, the informer cannot boast that their accusation was well-received by the Prince or superior they reported to.
Instead, when the opportunity arises, insinuate to the Prince that your accuser is an enemy and an informer. Suggest that informers, like traitors, are useful when needed but should never be truly trusted or loved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accusing</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/52-accusing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/52-accusing/</guid>
      <description>Avoid being the first to accuse, and refrain from bringing a lawsuit against someone you know the judge favors more than you. Only proceed if you have noticed the judge&amp;rsquo;s opinion shifting in your favor.
If you have brought a lawsuit, or one has been brought against you, even if your cause is most just, act as if it were extremely bad.
Approach and influence the judges with gifts, and your adversary through mediators who may meet with him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arriving at the Truth</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/51-arriving-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/51-arriving-truth/</guid>
      <description>To get an honest opinion about your actions, pretend that someone else is describing them, or read about your own deeds as if they were performed by another person. Then ask for opinions.
Remember that people have different views, and keep in mind that friends may be more forgiving in their evaluation.
If you receive measured praise, you can be more confident in the opinion&amp;rsquo;s sincerity. Giving some praise is considerate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Lending Money</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/50-avoiding-lending/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/50-avoiding-lending/</guid>
      <description>When lending items, instruct the servant who is delivering them to provide a detailed receipt. Have the servant sign the receipt as if they were acting on their own behalf, without your knowledge.
If you cannot avoid lending money, consider the following options: claim that you are also in debt or do not have the full amount requested, and ask to borrow something of equal value in return; or explain that you can provide the money without interest if your friend offers collateral.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Emotions</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/49-managing-emotions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/49-managing-emotions/</guid>
      <description>If you openly display strong emotions or personal feelings for too long, people will eventually oppose your actions. Therefore, it is better to refrain from publicly displaying these emotions or behaviors. Encourage others who genuinely feel the same way to do the same.
In the meantime, it is best to focus on serious matters to distract yourself from the emotions you wish to eliminate.
By doing so, you will conceal your true feelings of anger or happiness from even the most attentive observers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arguing and Correcting</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/48-arguing-correcting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/48-arguing-correcting/</guid>
      <description>Avoid criticizing someone when they expect praise or are expressing gratitude.
Praise even the smallest deeds, as this encourages diligence.
It is best to admonish someone through a mutual friend, in a confidential manner.
If someone is involved in illicit loves and you wish to help them break free, keep them occupied with challenging tasks and responsibilities.
Discreetly arrange for others to criticize the person&amp;rsquo;s words or deeds. Have them report their findings to you, provide false testimony, and disapprove of all the person&amp;rsquo;s actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Vain Pursuits</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/47-avoiding-vain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/47-avoiding-vain/</guid>
      <description>When dealing with a serious matter, let others focus on trivial aspects like applause and glory.
If an enemy wishes to surrender a city, offer them the most honorable conditions. Make them believe they are doing you a favor rather than being conquered. Let him depart with his banners unfurled and provide him with all the symbolic trappings of victory. In exchange, ensure that he yields the lands, hands over the captives, and leaves behind the gold and fortifications before sunset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traveling</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/46-traveling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/46-traveling/</guid>
      <description>Never reveal how much money you have to anyone. If strangers ask about your wealth, always claim to have very little.
Deceive potential thieves as much as you can, and tell no one which direction you are heading. To further conceal your route, ask different people for directions and get varying answers.
Beware of joining quarrelers, as they often start fights to distract and rob those who get involved. If someone taunts you, hide your true feelings and remain calm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deposing the Wicked</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/45-deposing-wicked/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/45-deposing-wicked/</guid>
      <description>If you want to remove someone from their position, start by withholding the funds necessary for them to perform their key responsibilities. This will cause the person to incur debts. These debts can then be used as a pretext to justify their removal from office and subsequent punishment. Ensure that the debts are portrayed as illegitimate, so that the creditors themselves may demand repayment from the person, further pressuring them. Thus you have punished the person financially without trouble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Averting Suspicion</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/44-averting-suspicion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/44-averting-suspicion/</guid>
      <description>Read the section titled Gaining Favor, Avoiding Offense, and Acting Cautiously.
If you are suspected of having slandered or discredited some accusers before the Prince, write letters praising them to the Prince, and ensure these letters reach those who suspect you.
Alternatively, if you wish to vex them, allow genuinely blank letters to be intercepted, making them suspect various secret writing techniques, such as the use of invisible ink that can be revealed by water or heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acquiring Dexterity in Acting</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/43-acquiring-dexterity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/43-acquiring-dexterity/</guid>
      <description>When sympathizing with someone&amp;rsquo;s suffering, console them using common expressions of support, without touching on anything that may offend them.
If someone is disparaged in your presence, be most cautious - neither praise nor condemn them. Both are odious.
Always speak well of your superiors, even if they have offended you. When someone else speaks ill of your superiors, do not agree or pretend to agree with them, even if it pleases you to do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disregarding Criticism</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/42-disregarding-criticism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/42-disregarding-criticism/</guid>
      <description>People are most deceitful when it comes to giving praise or mockery, flattery or taunts.
Collect written satires or mocking texts about you and read them yourself. Also, have others read them and laugh at them, as this will cause the author to despair.
Do not reveal a satirical piece written against you. If it must be revealed, invent a reason for doing so. However, if the satirical piece must be displayed, take the following steps: read it often at home, learn to laugh at it, and assume appropriate emotions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintaining Inner Peace</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/41-maintaining-inner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/41-maintaining-inner/</guid>
      <description>Avoid setting strict deadlines for accomplishing tasks, as unforeseen circumstances may arise, causing you to either neglect other matters or become distressed if you are unable to meet your goal.
Understand that your subordinates are likely to make mistakes; therefore, avoid over-planning.
Disregard the complaints of your subjects about you.
If entrusted with a secret, either decline to accept it or keep it strictly confidential.
Avoid accepting responsibility for others&amp;rsquo; money or belongings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling Self-Praise</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/40-handling-selfpraise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/40-handling-selfpraise/</guid>
      <description>Be cautious not to let praise lead to comparisons or claims of being unique, even if true, as such statements are rarely believed.
If someone openly praises you in the presence of the Prince, doubt whether they have secretly accused you. When you receive excessive praise, be cautious. If all your actions are praised, you are thanked for everything, and you are favored above others, be highly suspicious of these flatteries, as it may be a trap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quelling a Sedition</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/39-quelling-sedition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/39-quelling-sedition/</guid>
      <description>When dealing with a group, never allow more than one person to address you at a time. Instead, let the group choose a single representative from among themselves.
Inquire into the causes of an uprising. If it is due to usury, lend without interest yourself.
Offer great rewards to whoever quells the sedition, suggests a way to resolve it, eliminates the ringleaders, or betrays them.
If the people are rebellious or unruly, they must above all be guided towards virtue by good men.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Punishing and Correcting</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/38-punishing-correcting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/38-punishing-correcting/</guid>
      <description>Do not strike with your own hand, lest you acquire cruelty.
If you need to severely punish someone but lack strong justification, consider this approach: First, punish them for a mild offense that you would typically forgive. The offender will resent it and begin to complain and grumble. When punished again, he will complain again, until as if obstinate, he will give greater cause for a greater punishment, having been found guilty of a serious offense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleeing</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/37-fleeing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/37-fleeing/</guid>
      <description>Carry acid, such as burnt wine, and use it to drench clothes stuffed with straw. Suspend these clothes to create a diversion. The guard will believe you acted out of desperation and, neglecting his watch, will spread word to the others. Seize this opportunity to escape.
Feign illness by eating red ochre to simulate bloody stools, pressing near your elbow to alter your pulse, or inducing pallor. Then request that a doctor be summoned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Controlling Anger</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/36-controlling-anger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/36-controlling-anger/</guid>
      <description>Do not be quick to anger at anyone. Often, you will find that the matter was reported maliciously, or that you misunderstood it. If you act out of anger, the harm will remain with you.
If someone wrongs you, it is best to conceal your true feelings. Quarreling only leads to more conflicts and disrupts peace. Even if you emerge victorious, the consequences will be more severe than if you had been defeated, and you will attract more opposition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preventing Someone from Declining a Duty</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/35-preventing-someone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/35-preventing-someone/</guid>
      <description>If the person objects or makes an excuse, assure them that you will respect their wishes if it becomes evident that assigning them this duty was not in their best interest.
After you have departed, leave behind letters announcing the person&amp;rsquo;s new office. Instruct that these letters be read on a specific date. If the person writes letters back to you, do not respond to them.
If he complains, reassure him by saying that he will hold the office for only a short time and will be relieved of his duties soon if it seems appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Praising Others</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/34-praising-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/34-praising-others/</guid>
      <description>Pretend to be frank, acting as if you speak and act based solely on your own judgment and for the public good, and as if you hate nothing more than flattery.
Excuse someone&amp;rsquo;s gentleness and mercy as a duty of piety, so that their strictness and severity may weaken.
Avoid praising someone in a way that openly criticizes others, except perhaps in a crowd with many confused voices.
Leave people&amp;rsquo;s virtues unpraised and overlook their vices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissolving Friendships</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/33-dissolving-friendships/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/33-dissolving-friendships/</guid>
      <description>When ending a friendship, never abruptly break it off, as if you suddenly hate the person due to a perceived slight or offense. Instead, having reconciled and showing fervent love, gradually withdraw. To allow the friendship to gently dissolve, gradually reduce the frequency of your meetings. If you must meet, keep the conversations brief and invite them to dinner, acting as if you are burdened by business. This way, it won&amp;rsquo;t seem like you were only pretending to be their friend until you decided to cast them out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stirring Hatred Against the Wicked</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/32-stirring-hatred/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/32-stirring-hatred/</guid>
      <description>When in the presence of someone whose favor your target seeks or enjoys, praise your target in a way that may turn into an offense to their benefactor. Mention that what you said is commonly rumored, emphasizing that you are not expressing your own opinion. Imply to the benefactor that he should be concerned about his own reputation and that the reputation of those close to them is also at risk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covering Mistakes</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/31-covering-mistakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/31-covering-mistakes/</guid>
      <description>If you stumble in speech or act thoughtlessly, pretend it was deliberate, to test the judgment of others, or that you misspoke while trying to express something else. Smile as if you achieved your intended goal, or grieve as if you did not.
If you have made a mistake due to ignorance, do not ask others about it in a way that reveals your lack of knowledge or error. Plan ahead on how you would seek the truth or ask for others&amp;rsquo; opinions on what they would do in a similar situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Negotiating Shrewdly</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/30-negotiating-shrewdly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/30-negotiating-shrewdly/</guid>
      <description>When betting on an outcome, place an equal bet with another person on the opposite result. This way, regardless of the actual outcome, you will not incur any net loss.
When drafting onerous contracts, incorporate ambiguous terms that allow for broad or narrow interpretation. For example, upon a city&amp;rsquo;s surrender, promise to preserve everything if no uprising occurs, without specifying publicly or privately whether this applies to your own soldiers or the city&amp;rsquo;s inhabitants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acting in a Novel Way</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/29-acting-novel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/29-acting-novel/</guid>
      <description>Consider four things before acting in a novel way:
 First, consider whether it will be more beneficial or harmful to you? Second, ask yourself if you possess the necessary abilities or talents? Third, consider whether it aligns with your current status? Fourth, consider whether you are respected in your current role? And in the role you aspire to?  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Losses</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/28-avoiding-losses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/28-avoiding-losses/</guid>
      <description>Pay attention to even the smallest issues. Have your agents immediately report to you any potential sources of harm, so that you can take action before it occurs. Furthermore, ask them to suggest preventive measures.
The rates for buying and selling things should be observed, and experts should be consulted about unknown matters.
Each week, have the steward report on what has been accomplished.
After everyone has gone to bed, assign one person to check that the house is locked and note who is absent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feasting</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/27-feasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/27-feasting/</guid>
      <description>When hosting a feast, focus on items that can be preserved, such as candied fruits, decorative wax figurines, ornate fountains, artificial mountains, and self-playing musical instruments.
Include artistic elements that are fitting for the occasion, such as wax candelabra covers bearing the coats of arms of your guests, colorful drinks, scented beverages that seem imported from afar, and artificial wines like those described by Arnaldus de Villa Nova.
Present flowers, colored lettuces, giant eggs made from several smaller eggs and seasoned with spices, candles burning from ice, fragrant fires, vomiting mountains, fountains sprinkling snow, and fake fragrant fruits or apples brought to the table on the very branch - all things which can grow in your garden at little expense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Emotions</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/26-managing-emotions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/26-managing-emotions/</guid>
      <description>Compile examples of emotions and expressions from poetry, such as those found in the Palatium Eloquentiae1, and practice the ones you need until you have mastered them.
Trust no one, not even your closest friend. When interacting with others, you may pretend to trust them, but always maintain control over your facial expressions and words when showing affection. Remember that your face can reveal as much as your words.
Overcome your own timidity, so that even in moments of self-doubt, you can still act as boldly as you have in similar circumstances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responding to Requests</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/25-responding-requests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/25-responding-requests/</guid>
      <description>When presented with a request, do not refuse immediately. Instead, engage in some discussion before refusing. Once you have refused, stand firm in your decision. Only concede for serious reasons.
When you are about to refuse a request, take a moment to consider it, then pretend to be sorrowful. Alternatively, arrange for letters to be brought to you or have someone announce sad news. To achieve this, instruct a trusted servant to give you a predetermined signal, indicating through gestures and words that you are unable to fulfill the requester&amp;rsquo;s desire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaining and Conferring Honors</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/24-gaining-conferring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/24-gaining-conferring/</guid>
      <description>First, persuade others that it is necessary to bestow honor in a manner that you yourself define through the circumstances. Then, excuse yourself from receiving this honor, as if you had already possessed it to the same degree as you do now.
Strive for good and clear counsel and do many things that are pleasing to the public, such as the construction of public buildings, providing aid to the poor, and implementing measures that can be done without suddenly increasing taxes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Wealth</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/23-managing-wealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/23-managing-wealth/</guid>
      <description>Do not despise small gifts and be attentive to losses.
Avoid being wasteful with resources, such as allowing bread, food, or horse feed to go to waste.
Confer with skilled financial advisors and learn their methods.
Consider what can be sold, planted, or produced from your lands. Employ craftsmen to help you achieve these goals.
Know your entire income and always have an eye on your affairs.
Before incurring expenses, consider how you can recover an equal amount, so that you don&amp;rsquo;t lose money overall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Ambushes</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/22-avoiding-ambushes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/22-avoiding-ambushes/</guid>
      <description>Stage a quarrel with a friend to trick your enemy into believing you are genuinely at odds with each other. This may prompt your enemy to reveal their true feelings as they attempt to exploit the situation. Then, suddenly resist and oppose the enemy with your friend&amp;rsquo;s combined strength.
This tactic can also be used against robbers planning an ambush on the road or in similar situations. Intentionally make yourself appear vulnerable and approach the ambush site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joking</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/21-joking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/21-joking/</guid>
      <description>Avoid obscene words or actions, as these are the habits of foolish people. Similarly, refrain from mimicking the sounds of birds or other animals.
Never make jokes about things that would embarrass the other person, such as their physical or personality flaws, as these will leave a negative lasting impression. Furthermore, avoid speaking about the misfortunes of others, whether they are present or not. It is better to listen to such stories than to tell them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversing with Others</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/20-conversing-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/20-conversing-others/</guid>
      <description>Know yourself and from what background you come.
Some people may seem unpleasant to talk to at first, but as you spend more time with them, their wisdom becomes apparent, making the conversation more agreeable. Others may appear prudent and learned at first, but over time, they may prove to be flawed in their judgment or the consequences of their actions. Adapt your interactions based on the type of person you&amp;rsquo;re dealing with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Rid of an Unwelcome Guest</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/19-unwelcome-guest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/19-unwelcome-guest/</guid>
      <description>Arrange a signal with your servant beforehand. When they receive the signal, have them call you away as if for urgent business. They can whisper in your ear, send a messenger with letters, or announce that harm has been done or that there are disturbances among your subjects.
Have a doctor forbid you from speaking or drinking, etc.
Have a saddled horse brought, as if you are about to depart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acting Cautiously</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/18-acting-cautiously/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/18-acting-cautiously/</guid>
      <description>Being cautious involves two aspects: cautious trust and a certain generosity. Cautious trust means being on guard even with friends, as some friendships exist to deceive, and trusting no one without reason to suspect them. Generosity, in this context, means refraining from indiscriminately telling the truth or correcting others&amp;rsquo; errors and habits, while maintaining a pretense of doing so, although this is not entirely harmless.
Entrust a secret to no one, because anyone can become an enemy at any moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acquiring Prudence</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/17-acquiring-prudence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/17-acquiring-prudence/</guid>
      <description>As much as possible, be silent and listen to the advice of others, and carefully weigh it in your mind.
Take care not to be carried away by the passion of love.
Do not value your own words and deeds too highly.
Do not occupy yourself with useless matters that will be of no future use.
Finally, do not entangle yourself in the affairs of others.
Freely give others credit for accomplishments, even if you have greatly contributed to the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encouraging Action</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/16-encouraging-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/16-encouraging-action/</guid>
      <description>To encourage someone to act, take responsibility for any potential losses, such as goods or property, and offer specific rewards in return.
For example, before a battle, a commander should announce compensation for specific injuries, that he will cover their losses in goods and baggage; meanwhile, he should place a strong garrison in the camp, lest concern for it distract the soldiers&amp;rsquo; minds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Offense</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/15-avoiding-offense/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/15-avoiding-offense/</guid>
      <description>If you have been reluctant or less generous in granting someone&amp;rsquo;s request, be careful not to be overly generous to others in a similar situation for some time afterward, even if it seems minor. Otherwise, you will either arouse distrust towards yourself or incite hatred between the parties involved.
Never increase severity toward those you govern unless you also increase rewards or benefits at the same time; otherwise, you will either incur hatred or contempt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discerning Intentions</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/14-discerning-intentions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/14-discerning-intentions/</guid>
      <description>First, examine a person&amp;rsquo;s motives and assess whether they are consistent with their claimed actions, typical behavior, or the actions they are suspected of committing. Additionally, note if the person is acting more passionately or more cautiously than they typically do.
If a person is not acting in their own interest, or if they abruptly change their stance with great zeal, it may indicate that they have been bribed.
If a person does not agree after their stated reasons have been thoroughly disproven, they are not genuinely motivated by those reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering Secrets</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/13-uncovering-secrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/13-uncovering-secrets/</guid>
      <description>Engage even people of low status in conversation. Overcome by kindness, especially if you grease their palms with gold, they will likely tell you everything you want to know. (You can also gather information by talking with children, but this comes with certain risks.)
Set servants against each other, so they will betray each other&amp;rsquo;s secrets.
However, it is crucial to always keep your promises to everyone. Failing to do so will cause them to lose trust in you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Envy</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/12-avoiding-envy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/12-avoiding-envy/</guid>
      <description>Avoid acting as a witness in disputes. Doing so will inevitably offend one side or the other.
Do not speak poorly of anyone, and do not show disdain through your gestures. If you make a scornful remark about someone, continue the conversation as if nothing happened.
In the presence of others, do not show special favor to anyone. If you do, those who are not favored will feel despised and begin to hate you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preserving Health</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/11-preserving-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/11-preserving-health/</guid>
      <description>Avoid eating too little or too much, and ensure that your food is of good quality.
Dress appropriately for the weather, avoiding excessive heat or cold.
Avoid sleeping, working, or living in uncomfortable or stressful environments.
Do not spend too much time in high altitudes.
Overeating and irregular bowel movements are the sources of diseases. Engage in moderate physical activity and rest, and keep your emotions under control.
Do not dwell near swamps or even rivers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Deception</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/10-avoiding-deception/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/10-avoiding-deception/</guid>
      <description>Be cautious when trusting prudent men. They may minimize issues related to their own duties and be too generous when judging the reputations of others. They will not reveal if anyone has spoken badly about you in their presence, nor whom you should be wary of, or what vices they themselves struggle with. The same is true of priests when they praise their penitents, because they can say nothing but good about them, no less than parents about their children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Admonishing</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/9-admonishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/9-admonishing/</guid>
      <description>To reprimand someone without them realizing it, begin by discussing unrelated topics. Then, subtly exaggerate and criticize the actions you want to address. To obscure the fact that you are reprimanding them, add other details to the conversation. Additionally, frequently encourage them to be positive and cheerful, and include some jokes to lighten the mood. If they become sad, inquire about the reason. After discussing their emotional state, add all the other points you want to make at the end, even discussing potential solutions in a general sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asking for Things</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/8-asking-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/8-asking-things/</guid>
      <description>When asking a friend for a favor, make sure your request doesn&amp;rsquo;t require too much money or effort. Simply letting them know you need help should suffice. If your friend does not provide the favor voluntarily, he will not do so even if you ask directly. However, express gratitude for all help provided, as this will subtly convey your desire for further assistance.
If you are about to request something serious, first discuss other matters and subtly explain your desires as if doing something else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving Gifts and Favors</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/7-giving-gifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/7-giving-gifts/</guid>
      <description>Be generous in giving what you know others will not ask for, or what they will never use, such as privileges.
A teacher should not teach his student everything he knows, in order to maintain the student&amp;rsquo;s desire to learn more. Similarly, a parent should not give their child so much that the child no longer needs or hopes for anything more from the parent. The same principle applies to a master&amp;rsquo;s relationship with his servant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading and Writing</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/6-reading-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/6-reading-writing/</guid>
      <description>If you are writing in a public place, pretend to be copying from another document. Hold up a sheet of paper so others can see it, while keeping your actual writing hidden. Cover your work with a book or another sheet of paper, or position the raised paper so that only the line you appear to be copying is visible to anyone who approaches.
If someone approaches while you are reading, quickly turn to a different page to avoid drawing attention to your focus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acquiring Gravity</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/5-acquiring-gravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/5-acquiring-gravity/</guid>
      <description>Undertake occupations suitable to your role: for example, a Prelate should not handle weapons, a Nobleman should not practice chiromancy, a Religious person should not practice medicine, and a Priest should not teach fencing.
Avoid making promises or concessions.
Laugh sparingly, and when you do, keep it brief.
Do not change what has been decided.
Avoid staring at others.
Do not turn up your nose or furrow your brow.
Do not be sullen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding More Time for Business</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/4-time-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/4-time-business/</guid>
      <description>Delegate minor tasks to others.
Establish a strict schedule for yourself and adhere to it without deviation. Allocate the smallest amount of time to the smallest tasks, and spend only the time needed to complete each task effectively.
When fatigued by work, avoid undertaking anything further. Instead, refresh yourself with honest play and physical activity. Afterward, you will accomplish more, with greater ease and in a shorter time. If you must work, take on a task that you can handle without effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaining Esteem and Reputation</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/3-esteem-reputation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/3-esteem-reputation/</guid>
      <description>Never assume that someone will keep a secret if you act or speak too freely or confidently in their presence, even if they are a child or servant. They will judge you by this action and describe you accordingly to others.
Never assume that someone will excuse your questionable behavior; in fact, they will likely interpret it in the worst possible way. To prevent this, avoid engaging in any actions that could be seen as questionable, even if there is only one witness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identifying Who is Someone&#39;s Friend</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/2-identifying-someones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/2-identifying-someones/</guid>
      <description>If you praise someone and a listener remains silent in response, it indicates that the listener is not truly the praised person&amp;rsquo;s friend.
You can also tell that a person is not another&amp;rsquo;s friend if they respond to your praise in certain ways. These include diverting the conversation elsewhere, speaking halfheartedly or reluctantly, diminishing the praise, claiming the story is inconsistent, attributing part of the praise to others, or failing to enhance your praise despite knowing about a praiseworthy deed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaining Favor with a Friend</title>
      <link>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/1-gaining-favor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nestordemeure.github.io/writing/translations/breviarum_politicorum/3-acting-society/1-gaining-favor/</guid>
      <description>Identify your friend&amp;rsquo;s interests and choose gifts that align with them. Suitable items include mathematics books, optical instruments, microscopes, sundials, various mirrors, and other curiosities, as well as treatises on the secrets of nature, such as those written by Mizauld.
Speak with him often, consult him, and ask for his advice, then follow it. But never lay yourself so bare that if he becomes your enemy, he can use it against you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
